<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://wayfare.io/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://wayfare.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://wayfare.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-11-03T19:00:53+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io//</id><title type="html">Wayfare</title><entry><title type="html">Orange County, United</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/01/orange-county-united/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Orange County, United" /><published>2016-11-01T16:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T16:55:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/01/orange-county-united</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/01/orange-county-united/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org&quot;&gt;OC United&lt;/a&gt; is just that… Orange County, United. They are driven to unite north Orange County and provide a place for restorative relationships and life skills training to create empowered lives for OC’s most vulnerable. Founders Jay Williams and Amy Gaw are currently participating in the Launch phase of Wayfare’s &lt;a href=&quot;wayfare.io/startups&quot;&gt;Startup Programs&lt;/a&gt;, and we’ve been inspired by them since day one… in the unique way they are pursuing the common good, their humility and solidarity in standing with the vulnerable, and in the way they invite and unite the communities they live and work in. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re all neighbors. We live in the same space and share the same resources. But some of us don’t have homes. Some of us don’t have families. Some of us are isolated despite being surrounded by others. We were tired of feeling helpless when presented with heartbreaking needs, so we decided to do something about it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org&quot;&gt;OC United&lt;/a&gt; team is made up of a collection of citizens, non-profits and churches that believe they can accomplish more working together than apart. They are based in Christian faith but “welcome anyone with a pulse”. They currently work with the vulnerable in 4 different contexts: those from foster care, those experiencing homelessness, victims of domestic abuse, and families in under-resourced neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of organizations exist to serve vulnerable groups and individuals through various programs and services, but few address the root issue of the problem. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org&quot;&gt;OC United&lt;/a&gt; believes that people become vulnerable because they are experiencing the breakdown of the family unit. The ramifications of this breakdown are all around us in society, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org&quot;&gt;OC United&lt;/a&gt; seeks to rebuild and restore the family units by loving support and transitional empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We believe that lasting change occurs by coming alongside the vulnerable in long-term relationship, not through programs alone. As we continue to make strategic decisions, we want to ask ourselves: How are we helping to heal and restore those affected by broken family units?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org&quot;&gt;OC United&lt;/a&gt; serves the vulnerable in a variety of contexts. Some of their programs include &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org/homeless/&quot;&gt;facilitating family fun nights and kids clubs for motel families&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org/homeless/&quot;&gt;mobile laundry and showers for the homeless&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org/neighbors/&quot;&gt;after school tutoring and ESL classes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org/homeless/&quot;&gt;empowering homeless with life skills and career building&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org/foster-care/&quot;&gt;supporting foster families with errands, childcare, encouragement, &amp;amp; tangible goods&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org/foster-care/&quot;&gt;mentorship&lt;/a&gt;, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are committed to building a strong foundation for the future and sustaining long term impact. Their vision for the future, as a direct result of their mission, is that by June 2017 they will further their impact by working in relationship with 500 individuals/families providing place for connection, support, and empowerment to build into healthy family units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join them in empowering the vulnerable by visiting &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org&quot;&gt;OCUnited.org&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; by attending &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/wayfare-labs-pitch-night/&quot;&gt;Pitch Night&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday, November 10th from 7-9pm at Wayfare’s new location in Fullerton, CA. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/wayfare-labs-pitch-night/&quot;&gt;RSVP here&lt;/a&gt; to hear Jay &amp;amp; Amy share their mission &amp;amp; vision and opportunities for partnership.&lt;/strong&gt; Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="homeless" /><category term="foster-care" /><category term="foster" /><category term="pitch" /><category term="startup" /><category term="vulnerable" /><category term="nonprofit" /><category term="empowerment" /><category term="family" /><category term="neighbors" /><category term="neighborhood" /><category term="solidarity" /><category term="community" /><category term="Orange-County" /><category term="fullerton" /><category term="motel" /><category term="church" /><summary type="html">OC United is just that… Orange County, United. They are driven to unite north Orange County and provide a place for restorative relationships and life skills training to create empowered lives for OC’s most vulnerable. Founders Jay Williams and Amy Gaw are currently participating in the Launch phase of Wayfare’s Startup Programs, and we’ve been inspired by them since day one… in the unique way they are pursuing the common good, their humility and solidarity in standing with the vulnerable, and in the way they invite and unite the communities they live and work in.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/oc-united.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Valuing the Introvert in you</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/21/valuing-the-introvert-in-you/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Valuing the Introvert in you" /><published>2016-10-21T23:37:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-21T23:37:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/21/valuing-the-introvert-in-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/21/valuing-the-introvert-in-you/">&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a quiz! Answer yes or no to the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I prefer one-on-one conversations to group activities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I often prefer to express myself in writing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I dislike small talk, but I enjoy talking in-depth about topics that matter to me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People tell me that I’m a good listener.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoy work that allows me to “dive in” with few interruptions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I like to celebrate birthdays on a small scale, with only one or only a few friends.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People describe me as “soft-spoken” or “mellow.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I prefer not to show or discuss my work with others until it’s finished.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I dislike conflict.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I do my best work on my own.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I tend to think before I speak.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I feel drained after being out and about, even if I’ve enjoyed myself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If I had to choose, I’d prefer a weekend with less to do rather than too much. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were like me and were shaking your head vigorously yes to most of these questions, then congratulations! You are an introvert!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were also like me, then this result would have repulsed you. On almost every one of my report cards, my teachers would write, “Emily needs to come out of her shell.” I recall the first time my mother confronted me about this, gripping the report card in her hand. “Why can’t you be like the other kids? You will not be successful if you are quiet!” These are not words that eight year olds want to hear, or can even comprehend. Even a newly immigrated Chinese woman who barely spoke English knew that there was something “wrong” with being an introvert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on this feedback, I felt the need to correct myself and become a “learned extrovert”. I forced myself to raise my hand and talk in class. I forced myself to be the “leader” in group projects. I forced myself to mingle and hang out in large group settings. To the outside world, it might have seemed I was successful. But was I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I didn’t realize was that “shy” and “introvert” aren’t necessarily the same thing. &lt;strong&gt;Shyness is the fear of negative judgment, and introversion is a preference for minimally stimulating environments.&lt;/strong&gt; On the contrary,extraverts typically tend to enjoy human interactions and thrive off being around other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21st century Western culture revolves around extroversion. Classrooms are structured so that kids face each other in a table and many office spaces are designed in the same manner, to encourage students and coworkers to talk and work together.. We’ve become a culture of personality, where charisma and magnetism are highly favored traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I tried to jam myself into that extrovert mold, it was like trying to hold water on a flat plate: messy and useless. I’d flop onto my bed at the end of the day, feeling so drained that no amount of sleep would take away the empty feeling. It wasn’t until I read Susan Cain’s insights on introversion that I truly understood my personality type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her book, Quiet, was a game changer in my life. The title itself was so eye catching: Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking. I immediately picked up the book and saw this line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Don’t think of introversion as something that needs to be cured.&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d been told my entire life by my parents, teachers, and friends, to “come out of your shell”. Why was this an issue? Why was it a problem that instead of going to someone’s house on a weekend, I preferred to stay at home and read? Why was it a problem that I liked to think and work by myself before group projects? Why did anyone feel like it was necessary that I had to be an “extrovert”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cain argues that introversion is not a problem at all, but can actually be a person’s greatest strength. Everyone has been given different abilities, and it’s just a matter of knowing yourself and putting yourself in the right environments. In fact, there have been a lot of very influential leaders that were introverts: Rosa Parks, Ghandi, and good old honest Abe! Introversion and leadership are not mutually exclusive. Cain brings up the example of Moses; “we don’t ask why God chose as his prophet a stutterer with a public speaking phobia. But we should. The book of Exodus is short on explication, but its stories suggest that introversion plays yin to the yang of extroversion; that the medium is not always the message; and that people followed Moses because his words were thoughtful, not because he spoke them well.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introverts are needed everywhere, even in business! It’s not just an extrovert’s stomping grounds anymore. Because of the overwhelming number of extroverts in the business world, Adrian Schumpeter of The Economist argues that this is why more and more companies need the reflective and long term qualities of an introvert. We need more Mark Zuckerbergs and Bill Gates in a world filled with Steve Jobs and Sheryl Sandbergs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I embrace my introversion, I realize that some of my core strengths come from my introverted personality. My best work comes from my introspection. Creativity flows my from reflection. I strive to be the best version of myself, not a flimsy mold of what society deems is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This by no means is a simple task, and it’s still something I struggle with everyday. But with Cain’s “Quiet Revolution Manifesto”, I’m constantly being reminded that my introversion itself is a strength:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a word for “people who are in their heads too much”— thinkers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solitude is a catalyst for innovation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The next generation of quiet kids can and must be raised to know their own strengths.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sometimes it helps to be a pretend-extrovert. There is always time to be quiet later.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But in the long run, staying true to your temperament is the key to finding work you love and work that matters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One genuine relationship is worth a fistful of business cards.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s okay to cross the street to avoid making small talk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Quiet leadership” is not an oxymoron.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Love is essential; gregariousness is optional.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“In a gentle way, you can shake the world.” —Mahatma Gandhi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So take pride in your personality, introverted or extroverted, because you have the power to change the world as long as you are passionate. It may manifest itself in different ways but the potential is not restricted to how you enjoy your free time. As Susan Cain beautifully states, “we know from myths and fairy tales that there are many different kinds of powers in this world. One child is given a light saber, another a wizard’s education. The trick is not to amass all the different kinds of power, but to use well the kind you’ve been granted.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="introversion" /><category term="introvert" /><category term="personality" /><category term="quiet" /><category term="susan" /><category term="cain" /><category term="shy" /><category term="western" /><category term="culture" /><summary type="html">Let’s take a quiz! Answer yes or no to the following questions:


  I prefer one-on-one conversations to group activities.
  I often prefer to express myself in writing.
  I dislike small talk, but I enjoy talking in-depth about topics that matter to me.
  People tell me that I’m a good listener.
  I enjoy work that allows me to “dive in” with few interruptions.
  I like to celebrate birthdays on a small scale, with only one or only a few friends.
  People describe me as “soft-spoken” or “mellow.”
  I prefer not to show or discuss my work with others until it’s finished.
  I dislike conflict.
  I do my best work on my own.
  I tend to think before I speak.
  I feel drained after being out and about, even if I’ve enjoyed myself.
  If I had to choose, I’d prefer a weekend with less to do rather than too much.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/valuing-the-introvert-in-you.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Buy Jewelry, Change Lives</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/13/buy-jewelry-change-lives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Buy Jewelry, Change Lives" /><published>2016-10-13T21:31:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-13T21:31:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/13/buy-jewelry-change-lives</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/13/buy-jewelry-change-lives/">&lt;p&gt;Modern-day slavery exists in every country in some form or another. Sweatshops, prostitute rings, and domestic work are a few examples of the enslavement of men, women and even children. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;International Labour Organization&lt;/a&gt;, around 21 million individuals are forced into slavery each year around the world, and the impact of slavery is evident in nearly every aspect of our lives. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Slaves harvest cocoa in West Africa, and it ends up in our chocolate. Slaves make charcoal in Brazil, which is used to run smelters that make steel for our cars. Many food products and raw materials are tainted by slavery—such as tomatoes, tuna, shrimp, cotton, diamonds, iron, sugar, and gold.” – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freetheslaves.net&quot;&gt;Free The Slaves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bringing an end to modern-day slavery is a fight that isn’t over, and we stand with the warriors around the world fighting on the frontline for complete redemption and freedom for all people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the many incredible organizations that is committed to ending modern slavery is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purposejewelry.org&quot;&gt;Purpose Jewelry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary’s&lt;/a&gt; social enterprise. They are dedicated to helping every single woman they can, by giving her a second chance at life. 100% of their jewelry proceeds benefit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;International Sanctuary&lt;/a&gt;, their parent non-profit organization, which provides holistic care for young women rescued from sex trafficking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among many other world-changing social enterprises, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purposejewelry.org&quot;&gt;Purpose Jewelry&lt;/a&gt; provides everyday opportunities for consumers like you and I to directly empower women in need worldwide. By buying a piece of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purposejewelry.org&quot;&gt;Purpose Jewelry&lt;/a&gt;, you directly affect the life of a young survivor of sex trafficking across the world in six specific ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medical &amp;amp; Dental Care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary&lt;/a&gt; provides much needed medical and dental care to the women rescued from sex trafficking. This care can be for something as minor as a check-up to life-saving procedures. By buying a necklace, you could very well save someone’s life and help her stay healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary&lt;/a&gt; has started an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org/academy/&quot;&gt;Academy program&lt;/a&gt;, which provides every young woman in the program with opportunities to dream of a sustainable future by setting educational and personal development goals in four core areas, while earning an income. Many girls who escape or are rescued from modern-day slavery are hindered by their lack of education and employable skills. By buying a piece of jewelry and thus giving these girls and women an education, you are opening up doors to a better future and life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scholarships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to providing education to the women they work with, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary&lt;/a&gt; also provides scholarships. With these scholarships, the women are given the opportunity to further their education, either through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org/academy/&quot;&gt;The Academy&lt;/a&gt; or to attend university. These scholarships are funded by your purchases from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purposejewelry.org&quot;&gt;Purpose Jewelry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Counseling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After experiencing the horrors of modern-day slavery and the sex trade, a woman needs a safe space to work through her experiences and feelings. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary&lt;/a&gt; provides support and counseling, helping the women heal. In addition to counseling, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary&lt;/a&gt; provides one-on-one mentoring and life skills training so women can confidently get back on their feet and regain independence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Micro-loans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To regain independence, it is crucial that the survivors of modern-day slavery have basic financial skills and can financially support themselves. When necessary, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary&lt;/a&gt; provides loans to the young women who need them. At the same time, the women are taught financial skills and are helped in opening their own bank account so that they can be financially stable and independent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stability and routine is very important to a woman overcoming the trauma of modern-day slavery, and employment provides this stability. Through working for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purposejewelry.org&quot;&gt;Purpose Jewelry&lt;/a&gt;, these survivors receive job training and paychecks. As a result, they don’t have to worry about job searches or finances, and they can focus on their healing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re invited to join us for a first look at the NEW Purpose Signature Collection tonight at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/purpose-signature-collection/&quot;&gt;Purpose Signature Collection Launch Party&lt;/a&gt; here at Wayfare Costa Mesa. This special collection of five pieces stands for FREEDOM, and we’re encouraging you all to make a fashion statement: wear PURPOSE, wear freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll get a chance to shop the Autumn &amp;amp; Signature collection in person, enjoy delicious food from the Waffle-icious food truck, hear live music by Megan Tibbits, and participate in a raffle with sweet prizes. They’ll also be showing an exclusive first viewing of their PURPOSE brand video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t want to miss this amazing night! The event is free, but please &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/purpose-signature-collection/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt; and invite your friends and family! The first 30 people to show up at the party get FREE swag bags!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="common-good" /><category term="social-enterprise" /><category term="trafficking" /><category term="jewelry" /><category term="enterprise" /><category term="good" /><category term="world" /><category term="slavery" /><category term="empowerment" /><category term="education" /><category term="counseling" /><category term="india" /><category term="women" /><category term="freedom" /><summary type="html">Modern-day slavery exists in every country in some form or another. Sweatshops, prostitute rings, and domestic work are a few examples of the enslavement of men, women and even children. According to the International Labour Organization, around 21 million individuals are forced into slavery each year around the world, and the impact of slavery is evident in nearly every aspect of our lives.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/buy-jewelry-change-lives.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Seeing People Who Feel Invisible</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/04/seeing-people-who-feel-invisible/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seeing People Who Feel Invisible" /><published>2016-10-04T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-04T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/04/seeing-people-who-feel-invisible</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/04/seeing-people-who-feel-invisible/">&lt;p&gt;“His scream was ear-splitting. The stairwell in our apartment building acted as an amplifier, his cry blatantly bouncing of our building’s walls. My wife and I shamelessly named him “the screaming homeless man”.
There was one afternoon when his scream travelled upstairs and found its home in our living room as I was sitting on my couch reading this book about love - Love Does. The book was talking about loving your neighbor, and it hit me: he was my neighbor. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I went down to talk to him for the first time. His name was Matt. In that moment of speaking with him I had this overwhelming sense that I needed to paint his portrait. He had such an interesting face. This big beard. You could see the struggle on Matt’s face, and I saw beauty in it. 
I hadn’t painted in eight years, but I envisioned his story coming alive on the canvas in cool blues and deep yellows. From Matt’s story of ambition, failure, and isolation, &lt;strong&gt;The Faces of Santa Ana&lt;/strong&gt; was born. I call it a family before anything, because that’s what it’s become. I meet them, I build trust, I paint them, and they become family. We have imperfect relationships, there are hard moments. There are easy moments. There are great moments.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian Peterson, founder of the Faces of Santa Ana, studied car design at the Cleveland Institute of Art, and currently works at KIA design center. As I listened to Brian relay Matt’s story, I can tell he’s living out of an unbridled passion to make the invisible seen. In Brian’s case, his medium of choice is oil on canvas, and his process is unlike any other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The painting starts the minute I say hello, before I even buy the canvas. Sometimes, when I meet them I already know what color it’s going to be. I met a lady the other day and I told her, “Red. I have to paint you with Red.” Only after learning their stories can I go home and paint. The painting embodies who they are. Their experiences. I take all of that with me when I go home to paint in my living room. I want what’s coming onto the canvas to be them. Each painting takes between 12 and 16 hours, and then I take it out to them in the streets wherever they may be sleeping, living, or standing. Then they get to sign the painting. That’s important, because I want them to know that they’re part of this story. You can tell some of them forget how to sign their signature. These are people who have been outcast by their families, by society, by everyone that walks by - when I follow through and show them the finished product, trust is built.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a year since his encounter with Matt, and Brian is on his fifteenth FOSA painting, each 30x40inch masterpiece being sold at an average of $2,500. The money from the purchase goes to meet a direct need of the person featured in the painting. How does Brian decide which need to meet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I usually ask them. Along the way I’ve learned a lot, but I want to know their hopes and dreams, I want to know the things that are keeping them in the chains that they’re experiencing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the Faces of Santa Ana, Brian had never sold a painting. His art was always a selfless expression of love towards people he cared about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I gave a piece of art to the financial director at my college, and I gave a bunch of my paintings in college to my friends. I never thought of it as a way to make money, so this is new for me. If you go to my father’s house… his house is all full of my paintings. If I love someone, I give them a painting. I think we all have a unique way to show people love, we all have that capacity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re all born with the capacity to love someone. What’s your medium?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come hear Brian Peterson first hand as he speaks at Q-Commons on, &lt;strong&gt;“Seeing People Who Feel Invisible.”&lt;/strong&gt;  To Register for Q-Commons, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qcommons.com/costamesa&quot;&gt;Q-Commons Costa Mesa website&lt;/a&gt;. Discounted &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qcommons.com/costamesa&quot;&gt;tickets&lt;/a&gt; are available for Wayfare members, students, couples and groups of 8 or more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="art" /><category term="non profit" /><category term="homelessness" /><category term="stories" /><summary type="html">“His scream was ear-splitting. The stairwell in our apartment building acted as an amplifier, his cry blatantly bouncing of our building’s walls. My wife and I shamelessly named him “the screaming homeless man”.
There was one afternoon when his scream travelled upstairs and found its home in our living room as I was sitting on my couch reading this book about love - Love Does. The book was talking about loving your neighbor, and it hit me: he was my neighbor.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/Matt%20Faris.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Novelty isn’t Creativity… at Least not all of it</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/04/novelty-isnt-creativity-dot-dot-dot-at-least-not-all-of-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Novelty isn't Creativity... at Least not all of it" /><published>2016-10-04T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-04T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/04/novelty-isnt-creativity-dot-dot-dot-at-least-not-all-of-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/04/novelty-isnt-creativity-dot-dot-dot-at-least-not-all-of-it/">&lt;p&gt;My wife and I are big fans of Project Runway. Not only do we like design and fashion, but it’s also a fascinating inspection of culture. And we like to predict the winners and losers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each season, there’s a designer who the judges almost kick off but keep around because they have “a very specific point of view.” And because of ratings, I’m sure. Viewers love a good tragedy.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorites was a Japanese guy named Kooan. He specialized in what I vainly attempt to describe as a caricature of California surf culture, Pokemon, and the worst of the 80s. He called it Japanese street wear. The judges didn’t know what to call it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the point. He makes novel clothes. They have a specific point of view, but the judges almost kick him off on the first day of competition. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m concerned he makes crazy clothes for the sake of being crazy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He may just want to be the center of attention.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were concerned that his creativity is limited to the novelty of his clothes—their newness, and they want to know if his creations are also effective. At what? Evoking positive emotion, and making a woman feel beautiful, confident, strong, and noticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reminded me of an important rule: Creativity requires but does not equal novelty. Creativity also requires purpose—purpose that is selfless…other-oriented. Creativity is at least the combination of newness + purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The judges’ common descriptions (paraphrased) for the top designers each week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Any girl would want to wear this dress.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I clearly see a point of view you embody and that others want to be.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you watch the show, you’re probably thinking Patricia and Sandhya of more recent seasons also fall into this category—designing more for themselves and not caring as much about who will actually have to wear their clothes. They were also labeled as crazy by their fellow designers and the judges on more than one occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Observing these designers prompted a key question about the nature of creativity—and about my own inclinations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there times when I care more that my ideas are new than I care if they actually meet the real needs of others? Guilty as charged. I’m adding a new filtering question to my list of “good” ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In coming posts, I’ll continue to explore the nature of creativity. Stay tuned, and jump over to your favorite social channel to share your perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="novelty" /><category term="creativity" /><category term="original" /><category term="ideas" /><category term="design" /><category term="fashion" /><category term="purpose" /><summary type="html">My wife and I are big fans of Project Runway. Not only do we like design and fashion, but it’s also a fascinating inspection of culture. And we like to predict the winners and losers.

Each season, there’s a designer who the judges almost kick off but keep around because they have “a very specific point of view.” And because of ratings, I’m sure. Viewers love a good tragedy.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/novelty-isn't-creativity.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum, by Wayfare | Learning from the Art of Companion Gardening</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/27/introducing-forum-by-wayfare-learning-from-the-art-of-companion-gardening/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum, by Wayfare | Learning from the Art of Companion Gardening" /><published>2016-09-27T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-27T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/27/introducing-forum-by-wayfare-learning-from-the-art-of-companion-gardening</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/27/introducing-forum-by-wayfare-learning-from-the-art-of-companion-gardening/">&lt;p&gt;My dad is a man whose hands were perpetually rough with calluses and deep cracks, whose fingernails were cut dangerously short,left with barely enough room to be lined with dirt. He spent his evenings after work and his weekend mornings in our garden, wrist deep in the familiar warmth of soil that was nourished by our friendly hens and the roots of our thriving plot of vegetables. I inherited my dad’s deep love for the earth and some small part of his green thumb, which instinctively drove me to write my senior thesis on the dynamics of sustainable agriculture in Orange County. From that research arose one of my lifetime heroes: Dan Barber, co-owner of Blue Hill Farm and a leader in the world of food culture and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his riveting ethnography titled ‘The Third Plate: Field Notes on the Future of Food’, Barber comments boldly on the current state of our agricultural system. “In the rush to industrialize farming, we’ve lost the understanding, implicit since the beginning of agriculture, that food is a process, a web of relationships, not an individual ingredient or commodity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the wave of monocultures that struck our nation in the early 1900s, agriculture was characterized by small farms that were home to a community of livestock and a diverse range of crops grown on the same plot. Each plant was dependent on the other to thrive. An ancient Native American technique called companion gardening is the purest example of this symbiotic relationship that exists between plants. Certain plants complement each other especially well, such as beans, squash, and corn. Each were planted in close proximity to one another to support each other in each stage of growth. Beans fix nitrogen in their roots, improving the fertility of the plot. Shallow squash roots act as living mulch, and their spiky leaves ward off pests. Corn acts as a natural pole for the beans to climb, and in turn the beans stabilize the corn stalk. Their relationship is not ambiguous, but rather a symbiotic partnership where there needs to be equal levels of dependence between each plant, intentionality on behalf of the gardener, and creativity in designing the plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the idea of companion gardening, we introduce to you: Forum, by Wayfare. Forum is built on the idea that we are all believers in the beauty of work and the necessity of learning. As we strive to advance the common good, our weakness is self-dependency. Without inspiration, support, and opportunities to challenge our thinking, we wither. We are not to be a wash of industry-specific monocultures, bound by the limitations of self-sufficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forum is a free for Global members! Bring your own lunch and be a part of a culture of people who crave opportunities to challenge each other and build a community around a shared interest in the common good. Join us at Wayfare HQ in Costa Mesa as we launch our first Forum from 12-1pm on Monday, October 3rd. Not local? Participate on your own time via podcast or join us in new locations as we continue to expand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October’s topics + speakers are listed below, so you can save the date. Also - great news! Our first Forum is open to EVERYONE - not just Wayfare members! So bring a friend and learn together over lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October 3 Joel Beukelman, “Do Something: The Power of Personal Branding”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October 10 Jeff Tanner, “Redeeming Work: Exploring the Future of Work as a Tool for Creating the World’s Best Future”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October 17 Jonathan Menkes + Thomas Yee, “10 IP Pitfalls Every Startup Should Avoid”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October 24 Steven + Amber Cowell, “Dropping’ Mics on Open Adoption”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October 31 Emily McLaughlin, “How to Improve Your Company Culture Without Spending a Dime”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="learning" /><category term="forum" /><category term="lunch" /><category term="collaborate" /><category term="speakers" /><category term="inspiring" /><category term="community" /><category term="gardening" /><category term="novelty" /><summary type="html">My dad is a man whose hands were perpetually rough with calluses and deep cracks, whose fingernails were cut dangerously short,left with barely enough room to be lined with dirt. He spent his evenings after work and his weekend mornings in our garden, wrist deep in the familiar warmth of soil that was nourished by our friendly hens and the roots of our thriving plot of vegetables. I inherited my dad’s deep love for the earth and some small part of his green thumb, which instinctively drove me to write my senior thesis on the dynamics of sustainable agriculture in Orange County. From that research arose one of my lifetime heroes: Dan Barber, co-owner of Blue Hill Farm and a leader in the world of food culture and sustainability.

In his riveting ethnography titled ‘The Third Plate: Field Notes on the Future of Food’, Barber comments boldly on the current state of our agricultural system. “In the rush to industrialize farming, we’ve lost the understanding, implicit since the beginning of agriculture, that food is a process, a web of relationships, not an individual ingredient or commodity.”

Before the wave of monocultures that struck our nation in the early 1900s, agriculture was characterized by small farms that were home to a community of livestock and a diverse range of crops grown on the same plot. Each plant was dependent on the other to thrive. An ancient Native American technique called companion gardening is the purest example of this symbiotic relationship that exists between plants. Certain plants complement each other especially well, such as beans, squash, and corn. Each were planted in close proximity to one another to support each other in each stage of growth. Beans fix nitrogen in their roots, improving the fertility of the plot. Shallow squash roots act as living mulch, and their spiky leaves ward off pests. Corn acts as a natural pole for the beans to climb, and in turn the beans stabilize the corn stalk. Their relationship is not ambiguous, but rather a symbiotic partnership where there needs to be equal levels of dependence between each plant, intentionality on behalf of the gardener, and creativity in designing the plot.

From the idea of companion gardening, we introduce to you: Forum, by Wayfare. Forum is built on the idea that we are all believers in the beauty of work and the necessity of learning. As we strive to advance the common good, our weakness is self-dependency. Without inspiration, support, and opportunities to challenge our thinking, we wither. We are not to be a wash of industry-specific monocultures, bound by the limitations of self-sufficiency.

Forum is a free for Global members! Bring your own lunch and be a part of a culture of people who crave opportunities to challenge each other and build a community around a shared interest in the common good. Join us at Wayfare HQ in Costa Mesa as we launch our first Forum from 12-1pm on Monday, October 3rd. Not local? Participate on your own time via podcast or join us in new locations as we continue to expand.

October’s topics + speakers are listed below, so you can save the date. Also - great news! Our first Forum is open to EVERYONE - not just Wayfare members! So bring a friend and learn together over lunch.

October 3 Joel Beukelman, “Do Something: The Power of Personal Branding”

October 10 Jeff Tanner, “Redeeming Work: Exploring the Future of Work as a Tool for Creating the World’s Best Future”

October 17 Jonathan Menkes + Thomas Yee, “10 IP Pitfalls Every Startup Should Avoid”

October 24 Steven + Amber Cowell, “Dropping’ Mics on Open Adoption”

October 31 Emily McLaughlin, “How to Improve Your Company Culture Without Spending a Dime”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/B1.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Brain Food vs. Drain Food: 3 Meals That Will Skyrocket Your Productivity</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/20/brain-food-vs-drain-food-3-meals-that-will-skyrocket-your-productivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brain Food vs. Drain Food: 3 Meals That Will Skyrocket Your Productivity" /><published>2016-09-20T09:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-20T09:45:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/20/brain-food-vs-drain-food-3-meals-that-will-skyrocket-your-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/20/brain-food-vs-drain-food-3-meals-that-will-skyrocket-your-productivity/">&lt;p&gt;It’s obviously no new concept that the way we eat has incredible implications on the way we perform and feel, but fueling our body with foods that increase our overall mental and physical health can often seem expensive or inconvenient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how much more costly and inconvenient is it when we’re not able to perform effectively because of a lack of energy or drive? &lt;!-- more --&gt; When we’re in that 2pm slump, we often turn to quick &amp;amp; easy ways to glean energy, like a pop tart or shot of espresso. Foods that are high in carbs and simple sugars like pop tarts are high in glucose. After eating the pop-tart, glucose is released into our blood in record speed. Unfortunately, the effects are a measly 20 minutes of alertness. After that, we experience a crash where our glucose levels drop dramatically, causing an inability to focus or be motivated. When I think about the ultimate glucose crash, I think about Thanksgiving dinner. Can you imagine working a full eight hour day after indulging in a meal like that? Me either. Our bodies weren’t designed to be productive after fuel like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your quest for the ideal workday meal ends here! I’ve curated a menu specifically designed to help you to eat your way to maximum productivity and provide your body with the right vitamins and minerals to get your wheels turning from the moment you wake up (and whatever you do, don’t skip breakfast).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BREAKFAST: CHIA AND BROWN RICE PUDDING TOPPED WITH BLUEBERRIES, RAW COCOA, AND CHOPPED WALNUTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1/2 cup of brown rice&lt;/strong&gt; cooked in 1 cup boiling water - brown rice is a whole grain filled with vitamins like magnesium that improve your cognitive health. A complex carb, whole grains are designed to give you sustained energy rather than temporary energy like simple carbs do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 tablespoons chia seeds&lt;/strong&gt; - Chia seeds are rich in fiver, omega 3 fats, and protein to boost your energy and metabolism&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handful of raw blueberries&lt;/strong&gt; - blueberries are rich in antioxidants, which improve your memory and motor coordination&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 tablespoon of raw cocoa&lt;/strong&gt; - Here’s permission to eat chocolate for breakfast! dark chocolate contains antioxidants that specifically enhance your focus and concentration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Handful of &lt;strong&gt;raw, chopped walnuts&lt;/strong&gt; - Walnuts are one of the most beneficial nuts you can eat. With vitamin E, melatonin, omega-3 fats, and tons of antioxidants, walnuts support overall brain health, fight stress, and increase your ability to reason logically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LUNCH: SLICED TURKEY SANDWICH ON WHOLE GRAIN BREAD WITH AVOCADO AND A HARD BOILED EGG&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whole Grain bread&lt;/strong&gt;: Like we said, if you’re going to consume carbs, whole grains are the way to go. In addition to improving your cognitive performance, they’re high in fiber which aids in digestion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3-4 slices of &lt;strong&gt;hormone/antibiotic free turkey meat&lt;/strong&gt;: Turkey meat is an ideal source of vitamin B6 and niacin, which are critical to help your body produce natural energy. Why buy hormone/antibiotic free meat? Added hormones in any food interfere with your body’s natural hormone production and can cause anything from mood swings to an increased risk for cancer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sliced avocado&lt;/strong&gt;: Commonly known as one of the most healthy foods you can eat, avocados are packed with fiber, vitamin K, copper, vitamin B6, potassium, and Vitamin E and C. On top of that, they are great for long-term eye health, especially if you’re in front of a computer most of your day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard boiled egg&lt;/strong&gt;: Not only can you get quick protein from a hard boiled egg, but they contain a unique, fatty B-viatmin called choline. Choline boosts your memory and reaction time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DINNER: BAKED SALMON, BAKED SWEET POTATO FRIEDS, STEAMED KALE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 oz &lt;strong&gt;fresh salmon, topped with dill, olive oil, and lemon juice&lt;/strong&gt; and baked at 400 for 20 minutes: Salmon is packed with omega 3s, essential proteins, and tons of B vitamins. Each of these help you gain optimum memory and focus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 Sweet potato&lt;/strong&gt;, sliced, drizzled in olive oil and sea salt, and baked at 400 for 30 minutes: Sweet potatoes have endless health benefits, but since you’re winding down for the night it’s important to note that they are an incredible source of magnesium. Magnesium is the mineral that allows our bodies to relax and de-stress.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steamed kale&lt;/strong&gt;: Dark leafy greens are loaded with vitamins, minerals and phytonutrients like Iron. Iron transports oxygen to your brain and improves your cognitive control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Missed the first Brain Food post? Read our &lt;a href=&quot;http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/14/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity/&quot;&gt;Snack Plan for a Productive Workday&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/14/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity/&quot;&gt;6 Quick Health Tips for improving brain function at work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="productivity" /><category term="health" /><category term="nutrition" /><category term="wellness" /><category term="work" /><category term="brain" /><category term="snacks" /><category term="mealplan" /><category term="meals" /><category term="mealprep" /><category term="food" /><category term="lunch" /><summary type="html">It’s obviously no new concept that the way we eat has incredible implications on the way we perform and feel, but fueling our body with foods that increase our overall mental and physical health can often seem expensive or inconvenient.

But how much more costly and inconvenient is it when we’re not able to perform effectively because of a lack of energy or drive?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/brain-food-vs-drain-food-3-meals-that-will-skyrocket-your-productivity.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Brain Food vs. Drain Food: How to Snack Your Way to Productivity</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/14/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brain Food vs. Drain Food: How to Snack Your Way to Productivity" /><published>2016-09-14T17:33:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-14T17:33:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/14/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/14/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity/">&lt;p&gt;At Wayfare, our vision for the common good doesn’t end with providing coworking space and great coffee. We believe in living out of your full self. This concept of your full self is one that encourages the idea that our work, soul, and physical bodies should ideally be in this symbiotic dance: each one actively working towards the fullness of the other. In a quest to learn more about bridging this relationship, I thought, “What better place to start than in the fridge?”&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our brains work most effectively with about 25 grams of glucose in our blood stream - this is about the amount in a banana, or a 16 ounce glass of cold pressed juice. Even though your brain makes up only 2-3% of your total body mass, it’s responsible for burning 20% of the calories you eat daily, which is why it’s so critical to fuel it appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are quick tips + easy snacks to feed your brain strategically. Be intentional about building these habits, and you’ll see drastic changes in your personal and professional life. Also, stay tuned for Brain Food: Part 2, which includes a full menu specifically curated to fuel your workday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Tips:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drink water from the moment you wake up! While you were asleep, your body got dehydrated, and since your brain tissue is 75% water, you need water to help it operate at maximum capacity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep yourself hydrated with some water &amp;amp; fresh squeezed lemon. Water keeps your brain rolling, while lemon helps your body effectively digest its food and continually burn calories - even while you’re sitting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make your eating decisions before you get hungry! (Plan your meals out daily or weekly). If you wait until your body is craving fuel, you’re craving quick energy which means you’ll choose options with high carbs and lots of sugar, and probably spend a lot more money by eating out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eat smaller, lighter meals about every three hours so that you avoid food induced comas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eat slower - it takes 15 minutes for your brain to let you know your body is full, so try to stretch your meal out to at least 20 minutes. Plus, digesting takes A LOT of your energy. This habit allows your body to phase in its digestion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 pm on a Wednesday and find yourself fading? Keep some trail mix handy for instant brain food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Snacks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sliced banana + Sunflower butter&lt;/strong&gt;: One banana contains that 25 grams of glucose it needs to function at its best capacity + Sun flower seeds have a huge impact on your mental processing ability and overall mood. Packed with B vitamins and thiamine, they also improve your memory!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hummus with raw carrots&lt;/strong&gt;: Raw carrots give you that steady level of blood sugar your brain needs to function. Hummus is made out of garbanzo beans, commonly known as chick peas. Chick peas are also high in antioxidants, and one of the most heart-healthy snacks that you can eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s your favorite snack to fuel your workday?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="productivity" /><category term="work" /><category term="snacks" /><category term="food" /><category term="nutrition" /><category term="health" /><category term="wellness" /><category term="eating" /><summary type="html">At Wayfare, our vision for the common good doesn’t end with providing coworking space and great coffee. We believe in living out of your full self. This concept of your full self is one that encourages the idea that our work, soul, and physical bodies should ideally be in this symbiotic dance: each one actively working towards the fullness of the other. In a quest to learn more about bridging this relationship, I thought, “What better place to start than in the fridge?”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Redefining Productivity</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/06/redefining-productivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Redefining Productivity" /><published>2016-09-06T22:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-06T22:55:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/06/redefining-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/06/redefining-productivity/">&lt;p&gt;At Wayfare, we believe in the world’s best future. We also believe the world’s best future involves books. Real, smell-good books with covers and pages, marked with a heavy amount of highlighter ink. However, we recognize that finding the time to sit down and read often requires more time, energy, and commitment than you can afford.&lt;!-- more --&gt; A study done by Time Magazine found that the average American spends a paltry 19 minutes per day reading. If you’re anything like the next person, you set some lofty reading goals for yourself at the beginning of the year, and now you’ve found yourself somewhere in the middle of seven different titles. You may pick one up at night before bed, determined to make progress, and find yourself cashed out three paragraphs in. It’s ok, we forgive you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if you could glean all the most valuable content from a book in 10-12 minutes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider us your literature butchers: removing the hide, trimming the fat, and handing you the meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month we dove into The Productivity Project. Published in the spring of 2016 and written by a guy named Chris Bailey, the title is rather self explanatory. We live in a culture where everyone is trying to get the most done in the least amount of time. Meanwhile, our relationships and personal sanity often take some brutal hits in the process. If that’s the case, is anything really getting done, or are we just doing damage control? Chris spends an entire year of his life conducting experiments in the pursuit of extreme productivity, and this book covers his surprising results, best practices, and actionable suggestions for effectively and strategically getting stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out some of the experiments Chris put himself through on his quest to maximum productivity:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;90 hour work week, followed by a 20 hour work week, followed by another 90 hour work week&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Living like a complete slob&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Waking up at 5:30 every morning for a few months&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Living in complete isolation for 10 days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gaining 10 pounds of muscle mass, lowering his body fat by 7%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drinking only water for a month&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watching 70 hours of Ted talks one week&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only eating Soylent for a week straight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s our artfully butchered version of his findings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;redefine-productivity&quot;&gt;Redefine productivity.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is important. Picture a Venn diagram of Time, Energy, and Attention. Productivity is at its prime where the three intersect. Stop convincing yourself that productivity means doing more things. Doing more things leads to stress, poor work quality, and low productivity. Instead, Chris poses this idea that pursuing excellence in productivity means buying back your time, energy, and attention by doing the right things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-your-values-straight&quot;&gt;Get your values straight.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you decide to make changes in your life to become more productive, you have to decide WHY you value productivity in the first place. When making any big changes in your life, it’s important to zero in on your values first. Try this: grab a sheet of paper and list out your values. Listing what you value will help you determine what you do with your time. If you put some of these things this book suggests into practice, you could end up with two more hours of free time each day. Use that time wisely! You will experience the most life when you spend time doing things you value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;set-goals&quot;&gt;Set Goals.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set goals at the beginning of your week and at the beginning of your day. Even if they seem petty, tasks like goal setting are a worthy investment of your time, because they lead you to accomplish more. Make sure some of these items include personal goals, things you WANT to do! This includes cleaning up tasks in which you hold little value, but take up a lot of time. If a task takes less than two minutes, don’t even think about to-do listing it, just do it right away rather than adding it to your ‘to-do’ list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-your-biological-prime-time&quot;&gt;Find your biological prime time.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your BPT (biological prime time), and maximize during those hours. Your biological prime time is simply the hours of the day in which you have the most focused energy. How do you find your BPT? Chris suggests conducting a small experiment on yourself: “Cut out caffeine, alcohol, sugar, and as many other stimulants as possible from your diet. Eat small, more frequent meals during the day. Wake up and fall asleep naturally, without the aid of an alarm.” Your BPT is the time that you should use to work on the three most important tasks that you set during your goal making at the beginning of the day. Give yourself permission to be selfish with your BPT, schedule all your meetings either before or after your BPT so that you don’t have to switch gears and keep refocusing your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;combat-procrastination&quot;&gt;Combat procrastination.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do procrastination the right way, it could actually increase your productivity. Let’s get to the root of WHY you’re procrastinating in the first place. There are two parts to our brain: Our limbic system and our prefrontal cortex. The limbic system deals with all of our emotional decisions, while our prefrontal cortex deals with all of our logical decisions. If a task is boring, frustrating, difficult, unstructured, or lacking in meaning or reward, those factors trigger procrastination and our limbic system beats our logical prefrontal cortex. These two are having a conversation all day long, leading us to either make reasonable decisions or emotional decisions. Directly counter each trigger with something! For example, if a task feels unstructured, give yourself 25 minutes to work on it, followed by a five minute break. (This is called the Pomodoro Technique) Still find yourself procrastinating? Just start the task, it will suddenly seem a lot less daunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-time-to-slow-down&quot;&gt;Take time to slow down.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris spends a lot of time talking about mediation. “If you are turned off by the idea of meditation, think about it as ‘mindful breathing’ instead. Mediation simply helps you create space to refocus your brain. He even goes as far to say you can mediate while eating, walking, sitting, or even cleaning. Chris meditates 35 minutes a day, but try starting with 5! Chris found that, “For every minute you meditate, you gain back ten minutes of productivity.” Breathing mindfully and refocusing your attention allows you time to, “identify what’s important and then work deliberately and with intention.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-multi-tasking&quot;&gt;Stop multi-tasking!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re probably questioning this one. Isn’t multi-tasking the key to extreme productivity? Think again. A roman philosopher once said, “To be everywhere is to be nowhere.” Multi-tasking is a lie. “In fact, your brain can’t focus on two things simultaneously - instead, it rapidly switches between them, which creates the illusion that you’re doing more than one thing at a time.” Start re-teaching yourself to be in one place at one time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;disconnect&quot;&gt;Disconnect.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris says it best, “The best way I have found to prevent the internet from wasting my time has been to simply disconnect from it when working on a high-impact or ugly task, and to disconnect as much as possible throughout the day.” Your limbic system FEEDS off the internet. Scrolling, searching, pinning, it’s all mindless and your brain is in limbic heaven. A guy named Tim Pychyl did an experiment on procrastination &amp;amp; found that, “participants spent an average of 47% of their time online procrastinating.” Chris found that “Most people check email about every fifteen minutes, which adds up to thirty-two times over an eight-hour day. That’s thirty-two times that your attention is derailed from what you’re supposed to be working on.”  Try this: Turn off all notifications as much as you possibly can, especially during your BPT! Also, if your job allows, schedule two thirty minute slots during your work day to respond to emails, rather than responding throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-care-of-yourself--your-environment&quot;&gt;Take care of yourself &amp;amp; your environment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave room in your week for house-keeping tasks. Your week will be incredibly more productive if you prioritize a clean environment. What Chris does, is he schedules 3-4 hours on a Sunday to work on things like mowing the lawn, doing laundry, grocery shopping for the week, answering personal emails, cleaning the house, the list goes on. Also, work out regularly! Chris puts it real simply: “The more active you are, the more energy you’ll have to burn.” Make sure to drink water, caffeine, and alcohol strategically. Drink water right when you wake up, drink caffeine right before conquering a big task, and try not to drink alcohol right before bed as it steals your energy from tomorrow by causing you to sleep restlessly. Finally, did you know you can eat your way to productivity? head here and learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brain-dump--dream-big&quot;&gt;Brain dump &amp;amp; dream big.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris brought up a great point, “While you may have the odd Eureka moment while you let your mind wander in the shower, chances are you rarely have a brilliant insight while you’re on your smartphone.” Every day, Chris lets his mind wander for fifteen minutes. He keeps a notebook handy, ready to write down and externalize any brilliant (or not so brilliant) thoughts that come to mind. This includes writing down anything you’re worried or anxious about, as a way to free up mental space and refocus your attention. Try to figure out what kind of actives boost your creativity and allow you to shift into mind-wandering mode. I find the most joy, the most creativity, and the most mental freedom while cooking. Finally, don’t you dare forget to capture, reflect on, and celebrate things you’ve accomplished! Because you’re a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shut-down-early&quot;&gt;Shut down early.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris recommends, “a nightly electronics shutoff ritual, where you shut off your electronics two to three hours before bed.” The blue light from your screen is actually a stimulant that keeps you awake. Don’t think this is hard enough? Quit watching TV, you could gain back13.6 years of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-habits&quot;&gt;Create habits.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create habits that set yourself up for success. Habit cues are the idea of conditioning our brain to recognize certain patterns in our behavior and decision making, so that over time certain neurological pathways are solidified, which allow our brain to act accordingly. Chris describes his workout routine as strategic combination of habit cues: “I had almost every habit cue under the sun: a time (6am) place, (the same gym every morning), emotion (feeling energized after having my pre workout drink or coffee), the presence of people I knew (my workout buddies), and a preceding behavior (waking up early).” Each of the suggestions above are practical, effective habits that you can put in place to reach new levels of productivity and teach yourself to handle your time with deliberate intentionality.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="productivity" /><category term="values" /><category term="nutrition" /><category term="sleep" /><category term="lifehack" /><category term="energy" /><category term="attention" /><category term="multitasking" /><category term="disconnect" /><category term="health" /><summary type="html">At Wayfare, we believe in the world’s best future. We also believe the world’s best future involves books. Real, smell-good books with covers and pages, marked with a heavy amount of highlighter ink. However, we recognize that finding the time to sit down and read often requires more time, energy, and commitment than you can afford.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/redefining-productivity.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">4 Reasons Why We’re Excited to Share Our New Website</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/01/4-reasons-why-were-excited-to-share-our-new-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 Reasons Why We're Excited to Share Our New Website" /><published>2016-09-01T22:14:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-01T22:14:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/01/4-reasons-why-were-excited-to-share-our-new-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/01/4-reasons-why-were-excited-to-share-our-new-website/">&lt;p&gt;After a two month labor of love, we couldn’t be more excited to share the new Wayfare website with you today. Here are four reasons why…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-represents-two-years-of-growth---and-our-community-today&quot;&gt;1. It represents two years of growth - and our community today&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayfare launched two years ago with an idea, a logo, a website with rates, an email address, and 5 wonderful coworking members (that are still with us today… shout out to the original 5! Love you all). What we lacked in space, furniture, members, and coworking expertise, we made up for in tireless drive, countless brainstorm meetings, lean flexibility, a readiness to fail and try again, and a steadfast vision for what Wayfare would be.
 
In the early days, we used to dream of a space filled with people committed to using their unique gifts to advance &lt;a href=&quot;/about/common-good&quot;&gt;the common good&lt;/a&gt;. We envisioned a space that went far beyond desks to park your laptop, but one that awakened people to their true calling and restored the culture of work. We dreamed of a community that would value and support one another, would be eager to work and partner together for the common good… and ultimately, a community that would give birth to new dreams and movements that drive social change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had the joy of seeing these visions for Wayfare not only come to life but become the daily norm in this space. On any weekday at Wayfare, you’ll encounter people collaborating and ideating over coffee, writing, pitching new startups in our &lt;a href=&quot;/startups&quot;&gt;startup programs&lt;/a&gt;, mentoring, working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.wayfare.io/2016/07/11/member-monday-emily-mclaughlin/&quot;&gt;alleviating poverty in Africa&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cappital.co&quot;&gt;building apps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.softboot.org&quot;&gt;creating engineering jobs for emancipated youth&lt;/a&gt;, designing, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.wayfare.io/2016/04/25/member-monday-bailey-van-tassel-of-abel-impact/&quot;&gt;helping companies develop powerful giving strategies&lt;/a&gt;, coaching, and eating ice cream over a game of cornhole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are inspired every day by this &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt;, the work created here, and the common thread of shared values for a better world- but our website didn’t have the same affect. Somewhere in the midst of two years of growth, building products and systems, refining Wayfare’s business model, serving our members, and consuming copious amounts of coffee, &lt;strong&gt;our website and branding took the back seat&lt;/strong&gt;. As our staff and membership has grown, it has become a top priority for us to create a new website that represents the dynamic, dimensional identity of &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;our community&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-shows-how-were-unique&quot;&gt;2. It shows how we’re unique&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get us wrong here. We love coworking, workshops, gatherings, and startups… but it’s the common mission and thread that binds them all together that really drives what we do. We’re not just in this for the ergonomic chairs or the leftover eucalyptus garlands… we’re in this to advance &lt;a href=&quot;/about/common-good&quot;&gt;the common good&lt;/a&gt;, to make the world a better place, to empower others, and to pursue the world’s best future… together. We’re excited to share this mission with you- and invite you to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the design aspect of the  website was important, the  website rebrand was less centered on the aesthetics as it was about communicating Wayfare’s unique mission and &lt;a href=&quot;/about/our-values&quot;&gt;community values&lt;/a&gt;. We put pen to paper, defined and refined who we are, and invited our members, friends, and clients to be a part of it… because they truly are the reason this community is what it is today. We’re excited for you to &lt;a href=&quot;/about/our-model&quot;&gt;read what they had to say&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-visual-and-fun-like-our-community&quot;&gt;3. It’s visual and fun (like our community)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design is such a key element in making a brand’s identity and energy come to life, and we’re excited for a new website and branding that portrays the inviting, adventurous, and communal spirit that embodies &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;the Wayfare community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a rebrand entails much more than slapping on a new logo, we decided it was a great place to start. Our first logo was great for the initial season, and we’re excited to carry forward it’s clean minimalism and the accelerating lines that depict “wayfaring” or journeying. The new logo represents this same adventurous spirit, with added warmth and fluidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the logo, we weaved this same sentiment throughout all the other design aspects of the new  website. We did this in a few ways: incorporating more color and adding a new color palette, becoming more visual in our storytelling, incorporating the adventurous, entrepreneurial spirit of the Wayfare community through adventure themed icons, and adding more white space to let our products speak for themselves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-shows-where-were-going-and-were-going-places&quot;&gt;4. It shows where we’re going… and we’re going places&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main drivers of our website overhaul was the rapid growth of the Wayfare coworking community. In two short years we’ve grown from 6 to 102 coworking members and our private offices are filled with small organizations that have become family (and there’s a waiting list)! We’ve hosted over one hundred gatherings from workshops to fundraiser dinners, birthed eight startups (and are launching four more in December), and have grown from a staff of three  to eleven. Our &lt;a href=&quot;/locations/costa-mesa&quot;&gt;HQ space&lt;/a&gt; is nearly at capacity and we not only needed a more robust website to handle the growth, but &lt;strong&gt;we needed to expand&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve never been the type to shy away from a challenge and are always seeking ways to serve and empower more people, so we started brainstorming expansion. For us, expansion is not (and will never be) about fame or fortune. While we will always strive for global impact, expansion is not about beating competitors, having a distinguished world-class name, or swimming in profit. It’s always been about the common good. It’s about creating the most good for all people, empowering hungry leaders, giving birth to creation restoring movements, providing safe places for community to flourish, helping people walk into their true calling, and about building a world where the most vulnerable thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We thoughtfully decided that the best way to achieve our mission and maximum impact was to launch a &lt;a href=&quot;/membership&quot;&gt;new membership model&lt;/a&gt; and expand to more &lt;a href=&quot;/locations&quot;&gt;locations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a straightforward yet powerful next step for growth, a timely response to current demand, and a solution that is already proven in the marketplace. Our &lt;a href=&quot;/membership&quot;&gt;new membership&lt;/a&gt; now allows us to be more inclusive of our global market, provide practical and relational resources for those who don’t necessarily need workspace, and provide more flexibility (and locations) for those that do. To support this growth, we needed a website and platform that could handle multiple locations and streamline our services, as well as make the critical shift from a local coworking space to a global community that enables us to welcome more world changers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoy the new site &amp;amp; that it inspires and drives you towards a life of greater impact. &lt;a href=&quot;/membership&quot;&gt;Looking for community&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;/locations&quot;&gt;Need a workspace&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;/startups&quot;&gt;Have an idea you’d like to turn into reality&lt;/a&gt;? We’d love to learn more about you, and we openly welcome any website &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.typeform.com/to/vn3h2H&quot;&gt;feedback and suggestions&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="website" /><category term="growth" /><category term="rebrand" /><category term="brand" /><category term="logo" /><summary type="html">After a two month labor of love, we couldn't be more excited to share the new Wayfare website with you today. Somewhere in the midst of two years of growth, building products and systems, refining Wayfare's business model, serving our members, and consuming copious amounts of coffee, our website and branding took the back seat. As our staff and membership has grown, it has become a top priority for us to create a new website that represents the dynamic, dimensional identity of our community today.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/4-reasons-why-were-excited-to-share-our-new-website-0700d8.jpg" /></entry></feed>
