<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://wayfare.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://wayfare.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-09-20T21:06:39+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/</id><title type="html">Wayfare</title><entry><title type="html">Brain Food vs. Drain Food: 3 Meals That Will Skyrocket Your Productivity</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/20/brain-food-vs-drain-food-3-meals-that-will-skyrocket-your-productivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brain Food vs. Drain Food: 3 Meals That Will Skyrocket Your Productivity" /><published>2016-09-20T09:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-20T09:45:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/20/brain-food-vs-drain-food-3-meals-that-will-skyrocket-your-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/20/brain-food-vs-drain-food-3-meals-that-will-skyrocket-your-productivity/">&lt;p&gt;It’s obviously no new concept that the way we eat has incredible implications on the way we perform and feel, but fueling our body with foods that increase our overall mental and physical health can often seem expensive or inconvenient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how much more costly and inconvenient is it when we’re not able to perform effectively because of a lack of energy or drive? &lt;!-- more --&gt; When we’re in that 2pm slump, we often turn to quick &amp;amp; easy ways to glean energy, like a pop tart or shot of espresso. Foods that are high in carbs and simple sugars like pop tarts are high in glucose. After eating the pop-tart, glucose is released into our blood in record speed. Unfortunately, the effects are a measly 20 minutes of alertness. After that, we experience a crash where our glucose levels drop dramatically, causing an inability to focus or be motivated. When I think about the ultimate glucose crash, I think about Thanksgiving dinner. Can you imagine working a full eight hour day after indulging in a meal like that? Me either. Our bodies weren’t designed to be productive after fuel like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your quest for the ideal workday meal ends here! I’ve curated a menu specifically designed to help you to eat your way to maximum productivity and provide your body with the right vitamins and minerals to get your wheels turning from the moment you wake up (and whatever you do, don’t skip breakfast).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BREAKFAST: CHIA AND BROWN RICE PUDDING TOPPED WITH BLUEBERRIES, RAW COCOA, AND CHOPPED WALNUTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1/2 cup of brown rice&lt;/strong&gt; cooked in 1 cup boiling water - brown rice is a whole grain filled with vitamins like magnesium that improve your cognitive health. A complex carb, whole grains are designed to give you sustained energy rather than temporary energy like simple carbs do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 tablespoons chia seeds&lt;/strong&gt; - Chia seeds are rich in fiver, omega 3 fats, and protein to boost your energy and metabolism&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handful of raw blueberries&lt;/strong&gt; - blueberries are rich in antioxidants, which improve your memory and motor coordination&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 tablespoon of raw cocoa&lt;/strong&gt; - Here’s permission to eat chocolate for breakfast! dark chocolate contains antioxidants that specifically enhance your focus and concentration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Handful of &lt;strong&gt;raw, chopped walnuts&lt;/strong&gt; - Walnuts are one of the most beneficial nuts you can eat. With vitamin E, melatonin, omega-3 fats, and tons of antioxidants, walnuts support overall brain health, fight stress, and increase your ability to reason logically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LUNCH: SLICED TURKEY SANDWICH ON WHOLE GRAIN BREAD WITH AVOCADO AND A HARD BOILED EGG&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whole Grain bread&lt;/strong&gt;: Like we said, if you’re going to consume carbs, whole grains are the way to go. In addition to improving your cognitive performance, they’re high in fiber which aids in digestion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3-4 slices of &lt;strong&gt;hormone/antibiotic free turkey meat&lt;/strong&gt;: Turkey meat is an ideal source of vitamin B6 and niacin, which are critical to help your body produce natural energy. Why buy hormone/antibiotic free meat? Added hormones in any food interfere with your body’s natural hormone production and can cause anything from mood swings to an increased risk for cancer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sliced avocado&lt;/strong&gt;: Commonly known as one of the most healthy foods you can eat, avocados are packed with fiber, vitamin K, copper, vitamin B6, potassium, and Vitamin E and C. On top of that, they are great for long-term eye health, especially if you’re in front of a computer most of your day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard boiled egg&lt;/strong&gt;: Not only can you get quick protein from a hard boiled egg, but they contain a unique, fatty B-viatmin called choline. Choline boosts your memory and reaction time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DINNER: BAKED SALMON, BAKED SWEET POTATO FRIEDS, STEAMED KALE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 oz &lt;strong&gt;fresh salmon, topped with dill, olive oil, and lemon juice&lt;/strong&gt; and baked at 400 for 20 minutes: Salmon is packed with omega 3s, essential proteins, and tons of B vitamins. Each of these help you gain optimum memory and focus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 Sweet potato&lt;/strong&gt;, sliced, drizzled in olive oil and sea salt, and baked at 400 for 30 minutes: Sweet potatoes have endless health benefits, but since you’re winding down for the night it’s important to note that they are an incredible source of magnesium. Magnesium is the mineral that allows our bodies to relax and de-stress.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steamed kale&lt;/strong&gt;: Dark leafy greens are loaded with vitamins, minerals and phytonutrients like Iron. Iron transports oxygen to your brain and improves your cognitive control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Missed the first Brain Food post? Read our &lt;a href=&quot;http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/14/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity/&quot;&gt;Snack Plan for a Productive Workday&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/14/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity/&quot;&gt;6 Quick Health Tips for improving brain function at work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="productivity" /><category term="health" /><category term="nutrition" /><category term="wellness" /><category term="work" /><category term="brain" /><category term="snacks" /><category term="mealplan" /><category term="meals" /><category term="mealprep" /><category term="food" /><category term="lunch" /><summary type="html">It’s obviously no new concept that the way we eat has incredible implications on the way we perform and feel, but fueling our body with foods that increase our overall mental and physical health can often seem expensive or inconvenient.

But how much more costly and inconvenient is it when we’re not able to perform effectively because of a lack of energy or drive?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/brain-food-vs-drain-food-3-meals-that-will-skyrocket-your-productivity.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Brain Food vs. Drain Food: How to Snack Your Way to Productivity</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/14/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brain Food vs. Drain Food: How to Snack Your Way to Productivity" /><published>2016-09-14T17:33:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-14T17:33:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/14/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/14/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity/">&lt;p&gt;At Wayfare, our vision for the common good doesn’t end with providing coworking space and great coffee. We believe in living out of your full self. This concept of your full self is one that encourages the idea that our work, soul, and physical bodies should ideally be in this symbiotic dance: each one actively working towards the fullness of the other. In a quest to learn more about bridging this relationship, I thought, “What better place to start than in the fridge?”&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our brains work most effectively with about 25 grams of glucose in our blood stream - this is about the amount in a banana, or a 16 ounce glass of cold pressed juice. Even though your brain makes up only 2-3% of your total body mass, it’s responsible for burning 20% of the calories you eat daily, which is why it’s so critical to fuel it appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are quick tips + easy snacks to feed your brain strategically. Be intentional about building these habits, and you’ll see drastic changes in your personal and professional life. Also, stay tuned for Brain Food: Part 2, which includes a full menu specifically curated to fuel your workday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Tips:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drink water from the moment you wake up! While you were asleep, your body got dehydrated, and since your brain tissue is 75% water, you need water to help it operate at maximum capacity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep yourself hydrated with some water &amp;amp; fresh squeezed lemon. Water keeps your brain rolling, while lemon helps your body effectively digest its food and continually burn calories - even while you’re sitting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make your eating decisions before you get hungry! (Plan your meals out daily or weekly). If you wait until your body is craving fuel, you’re craving quick energy which means you’ll choose options with high carbs and lots of sugar, and probably spend a lot more money by eating out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eat smaller, lighter meals about every three hours so that you avoid food induced comas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eat slower - it takes 15 minutes for your brain to let you know your body is full, so try to stretch your meal out to at least 20 minutes. Plus, digesting takes A LOT of your energy. This habit allows your body to phase in its digestion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 pm on a Wednesday and find yourself fading? Keep some trail mix handy for instant brain food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Snacks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sliced banana + Sunflower butter&lt;/strong&gt;: One banana contains that 25 grams of glucose it needs to function at its best capacity + Sun flower seeds have a huge impact on your mental processing ability and overall mood. Packed with B vitamins and thiamine, they also improve your memory!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hummus with raw carrots&lt;/strong&gt;: Raw carrots give you that steady level of blood sugar your brain needs to function. Hummus is made out of garbanzo beans, commonly known as chick peas. Chick peas are also high in antioxidants, and one of the most heart-healthy snacks that you can eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s your favorite snack to fuel your workday?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="productivity" /><category term="work" /><category term="snacks" /><category term="food" /><category term="nutrition" /><category term="health" /><category term="wellness" /><category term="eating" /><summary type="html">At Wayfare, our vision for the common good doesn’t end with providing coworking space and great coffee. We believe in living out of your full self. This concept of your full self is one that encourages the idea that our work, soul, and physical bodies should ideally be in this symbiotic dance: each one actively working towards the fullness of the other. In a quest to learn more about bridging this relationship, I thought, “What better place to start than in the fridge?”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Redefining Productivity</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/06/redefining-productivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Redefining Productivity" /><published>2016-09-06T22:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-06T22:55:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/06/redefining-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/06/redefining-productivity/">&lt;p&gt;At Wayfare, we believe in the world’s best future. We also believe the world’s best future involves books. Real, smell-good books with covers and pages, marked with a heavy amount of highlighter ink. However, we recognize that finding the time to sit down and read often requires more time, energy, and commitment than you can afford.&lt;!-- more --&gt; A study done by Time Magazine found that the average American spends a paltry 19 minutes per day reading. If you’re anything like the next person, you set some lofty reading goals for yourself at the beginning of the year, and now you’ve found yourself somewhere in the middle of seven different titles. You may pick one up at night before bed, determined to make progress, and find yourself cashed out three paragraphs in. It’s ok, we forgive you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if you could glean all the most valuable content from a book in 10-12 minutes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider us your literature butchers: removing the hide, trimming the fat, and handing you the meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month we dove into The Productivity Project. Published in the spring of 2016 and written by a guy named Chris Bailey, the title is rather self explanatory. We live in a culture where everyone is trying to get the most done in the least amount of time. Meanwhile, our relationships and personal sanity often take some brutal hits in the process. If that’s the case, is anything really getting done, or are we just doing damage control? Chris spends an entire year of his life conducting experiments in the pursuit of extreme productivity, and this book covers his surprising results, best practices, and actionable suggestions for effectively and strategically getting stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out some of the experiments Chris put himself through on his quest to maximum productivity:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;90 hour work week, followed by a 20 hour work week, followed by another 90 hour work week&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Living like a complete slob&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Waking up at 5:30 every morning for a few months&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Living in complete isolation for 10 days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gaining 10 pounds of muscle mass, lowering his body fat by 7%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drinking only water for a month&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watching 70 hours of Ted talks one week&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only eating Soylent for a week straight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s our artfully butchered version of his findings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;redefine-productivity&quot;&gt;Redefine productivity.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is important. Picture a Venn diagram of Time, Energy, and Attention. Productivity is at its prime where the three intersect. Stop convincing yourself that productivity means doing more things. Doing more things leads to stress, poor work quality, and low productivity. Instead, Chris poses this idea that pursuing excellence in productivity means buying back your time, energy, and attention by doing the right things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-your-values-straight&quot;&gt;Get your values straight.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you decide to make changes in your life to become more productive, you have to decide WHY you value productivity in the first place. When making any big changes in your life, it’s important to zero in on your values first. Try this: grab a sheet of paper and list out your values. Listing what you value will help you determine what you do with your time. If you put some of these things this book suggests into practice, you could end up with two more hours of free time each day. Use that time wisely! You will experience the most life when you spend time doing things you value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;set-goals&quot;&gt;Set Goals.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set goals at the beginning of your week and at the beginning of your day. Even if they seem petty, tasks like goal setting are a worthy investment of your time, because they lead you to accomplish more. Make sure some of these items include personal goals, things you WANT to do! This includes cleaning up tasks in which you hold little value, but take up a lot of time. If a task takes less than two minutes, don’t even think about to-do listing it, just do it right away rather than adding it to your ‘to-do’ list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-your-biological-prime-time&quot;&gt;Find your biological prime time.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find your BPT (biological prime time), and maximize during those hours. Your biological prime time is simply the hours of the day in which you have the most focused energy. How do you find your BPT? Chris suggests conducting a small experiment on yourself: “Cut out caffeine, alcohol, sugar, and as many other stimulants as possible from your diet. Eat small, more frequent meals during the day. Wake up and fall asleep naturally, without the aid of an alarm.” Your BPT is the time that you should use to work on the three most important tasks that you set during your goal making at the beginning of the day. Give yourself permission to be selfish with your BPT, schedule all your meetings either before or after your BPT so that you don’t have to switch gears and keep refocusing your attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;combat-procrastination&quot;&gt;Combat procrastination.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do procrastination the right way, it could actually increase your productivity. Let’s get to the root of WHY you’re procrastinating in the first place. There are two parts to our brain: Our limbic system and our prefrontal cortex. The limbic system deals with all of our emotional decisions, while our prefrontal cortex deals with all of our logical decisions. If a task is boring, frustrating, difficult, unstructured, or lacking in meaning or reward, those factors trigger procrastination and our limbic system beats our logical prefrontal cortex. These two are having a conversation all day long, leading us to either make reasonable decisions or emotional decisions. Directly counter each trigger with something! For example, if a task feels unstructured, give yourself 25 minutes to work on it, followed by a five minute break. (This is called the Pomodoro Technique) Still find yourself procrastinating? Just start the task, it will suddenly seem a lot less daunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-time-to-slow-down&quot;&gt;Take time to slow down.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris spends a lot of time talking about mediation. “If you are turned off by the idea of meditation, think about it as ‘mindful breathing’ instead. Mediation simply helps you create space to refocus your brain. He even goes as far to say you can mediate while eating, walking, sitting, or even cleaning. Chris meditates 35 minutes a day, but try starting with 5! Chris found that, “For every minute you meditate, you gain back ten minutes of productivity.” Breathing mindfully and refocusing your attention allows you time to, “identify what’s important and then work deliberately and with intention.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-multi-tasking&quot;&gt;Stop multi-tasking!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’re probably questioning this one. Isn’t multi-tasking the key to extreme productivity? Think again. A roman philosopher once said, “To be everywhere is to be nowhere.” Multi-tasking is a lie. “In fact, your brain can’t focus on two things simultaneously - instead, it rapidly switches between them, which creates the illusion that you’re doing more than one thing at a time.” Start re-teaching yourself to be in one place at one time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;disconnect&quot;&gt;Disconnect.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris says it best, “The best way I have found to prevent the internet from wasting my time has been to simply disconnect from it when working on a high-impact or ugly task, and to disconnect as much as possible throughout the day.” Your limbic system FEEDS off the internet. Scrolling, searching, pinning, it’s all mindless and your brain is in limbic heaven. A guy named Tim Pychyl did an experiment on procrastination &amp;amp; found that, “participants spent an average of 47% of their time online procrastinating.” Chris found that “Most people check email about every fifteen minutes, which adds up to thirty-two times over an eight-hour day. That’s thirty-two times that your attention is derailed from what you’re supposed to be working on.”  Try this: Turn off all notifications as much as you possibly can, especially during your BPT! Also, if your job allows, schedule two thirty minute slots during your work day to respond to emails, rather than responding throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-care-of-yourself--your-environment&quot;&gt;Take care of yourself &amp;amp; your environment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave room in your week for house-keeping tasks. Your week will be incredibly more productive if you prioritize a clean environment. What Chris does, is he schedules 3-4 hours on a Sunday to work on things like mowing the lawn, doing laundry, grocery shopping for the week, answering personal emails, cleaning the house, the list goes on. Also, work out regularly! Chris puts it real simply: “The more active you are, the more energy you’ll have to burn.” Make sure to drink water, caffeine, and alcohol strategically. Drink water right when you wake up, drink caffeine right before conquering a big task, and try not to drink alcohol right before bed as it steals your energy from tomorrow by causing you to sleep restlessly. Finally, did you know you can eat your way to productivity? head here and learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brain-dump--dream-big&quot;&gt;Brain dump &amp;amp; dream big.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris brought up a great point, “While you may have the odd Eureka moment while you let your mind wander in the shower, chances are you rarely have a brilliant insight while you’re on your smartphone.” Every day, Chris lets his mind wander for fifteen minutes. He keeps a notebook handy, ready to write down and externalize any brilliant (or not so brilliant) thoughts that come to mind. This includes writing down anything you’re worried or anxious about, as a way to free up mental space and refocus your attention. Try to figure out what kind of actives boost your creativity and allow you to shift into mind-wandering mode. I find the most joy, the most creativity, and the most mental freedom while cooking. Finally, don’t you dare forget to capture, reflect on, and celebrate things you’ve accomplished! Because you’re a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shut-down-early&quot;&gt;Shut down early.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris recommends, “a nightly electronics shutoff ritual, where you shut off your electronics two to three hours before bed.” The blue light from your screen is actually a stimulant that keeps you awake. Don’t think this is hard enough? Quit watching TV, you could gain back13.6 years of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-habits&quot;&gt;Create habits.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create habits that set yourself up for success. Habit cues are the idea of conditioning our brain to recognize certain patterns in our behavior and decision making, so that over time certain neurological pathways are solidified, which allow our brain to act accordingly. Chris describes his workout routine as strategic combination of habit cues: “I had almost every habit cue under the sun: a time (6am) place, (the same gym every morning), emotion (feeling energized after having my pre workout drink or coffee), the presence of people I knew (my workout buddies), and a preceding behavior (waking up early).” Each of the suggestions above are practical, effective habits that you can put in place to reach new levels of productivity and teach yourself to handle your time with deliberate intentionality.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="productivity" /><category term="values" /><category term="nutrition" /><category term="sleep" /><category term="lifehack" /><category term="energy" /><category term="attention" /><category term="multitasking" /><category term="disconnect" /><category term="health" /><summary type="html">At Wayfare, we believe in the world’s best future. We also believe the world’s best future involves books. Real, smell-good books with covers and pages, marked with a heavy amount of highlighter ink. However, we recognize that finding the time to sit down and read often requires more time, energy, and commitment than you can afford.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/redefining-productivity.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">4 Reasons Why We’re Excited to Share Our New Website</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/01/4-reasons-why-were-excited-to-share-our-new-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 Reasons Why We're Excited to Share Our New Website" /><published>2016-09-01T22:14:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-01T22:14:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/01/4-reasons-why-were-excited-to-share-our-new-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/01/4-reasons-why-were-excited-to-share-our-new-website/">&lt;p&gt;After a two month labor of love, we couldn’t be more excited to share the new Wayfare website with you today. Here are four reasons why…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-represents-two-years-of-growth---and-our-community-today&quot;&gt;1. It represents two years of growth - and our community today&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayfare launched two years ago with an idea, a logo, a website with rates, an email address, and 5 wonderful coworking members (that are still with us today… shout out to the original 5! Love you all). What we lacked in space, furniture, members, and coworking expertise, we made up for in tireless drive, countless brainstorm meetings, lean flexibility, a readiness to fail and try again, and a steadfast vision for what Wayfare would be.
 
In the early days, we used to dream of a space filled with people committed to using their unique gifts to advance &lt;a href=&quot;/about/common-good&quot;&gt;the common good&lt;/a&gt;. We envisioned a space that went far beyond desks to park your laptop, but one that awakened people to their true calling and restored the culture of work. We dreamed of a community that would value and support one another, would be eager to work and partner together for the common good… and ultimately, a community that would give birth to new dreams and movements that drive social change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had the joy of seeing these visions for Wayfare not only come to life but become the daily norm in this space. On any weekday at Wayfare, you’ll encounter people collaborating and ideating over coffee, writing, pitching new startups in our &lt;a href=&quot;/startups&quot;&gt;startup programs&lt;/a&gt;, mentoring, working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.wayfare.io/2016/07/11/member-monday-emily-mclaughlin/&quot;&gt;alleviating poverty in Africa&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cappital.co&quot;&gt;building apps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.softboot.org&quot;&gt;creating engineering jobs for emancipated youth&lt;/a&gt;, designing, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.wayfare.io/2016/04/25/member-monday-bailey-van-tassel-of-abel-impact/&quot;&gt;helping companies develop powerful giving strategies&lt;/a&gt;, coaching, and eating ice cream over a game of cornhole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are inspired every day by this &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt;, the work created here, and the common thread of shared values for a better world- but our website didn’t have the same affect. Somewhere in the midst of two years of growth, building products and systems, refining Wayfare’s business model, serving our members, and consuming copious amounts of coffee, &lt;strong&gt;our website and branding took the back seat&lt;/strong&gt;. As our staff and membership has grown, it has become a top priority for us to create a new website that represents the dynamic, dimensional identity of &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;our community&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-shows-how-were-unique&quot;&gt;2. It shows how we’re unique&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get us wrong here. We love coworking, workshops, gatherings, and startups… but it’s the common mission and thread that binds them all together that really drives what we do. We’re not just in this for the ergonomic chairs or the leftover eucalyptus garlands… we’re in this to advance &lt;a href=&quot;/about/common-good&quot;&gt;the common good&lt;/a&gt;, to make the world a better place, to empower others, and to pursue the world’s best future… together. We’re excited to share this mission with you- and invite you to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the design aspect of the  website was important, the  website rebrand was less centered on the aesthetics as it was about communicating Wayfare’s unique mission and &lt;a href=&quot;/about/our-values&quot;&gt;community values&lt;/a&gt;. We put pen to paper, defined and refined who we are, and invited our members, friends, and clients to be a part of it… because they truly are the reason this community is what it is today. We’re excited for you to &lt;a href=&quot;/about/our-model&quot;&gt;read what they had to say&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-visual-and-fun-like-our-community&quot;&gt;3. It’s visual and fun (like our community)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design is such a key element in making a brand’s identity and energy come to life, and we’re excited for a new website and branding that portrays the inviting, adventurous, and communal spirit that embodies &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;the Wayfare community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a rebrand entails much more than slapping on a new logo, we decided it was a great place to start. Our first logo was great for the initial season, and we’re excited to carry forward it’s clean minimalism and the accelerating lines that depict “wayfaring” or journeying. The new logo represents this same adventurous spirit, with added warmth and fluidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the logo, we weaved this same sentiment throughout all the other design aspects of the new  website. We did this in a few ways: incorporating more color and adding a new color palette, becoming more visual in our storytelling, incorporating the adventurous, entrepreneurial spirit of the Wayfare community through adventure themed icons, and adding more white space to let our products speak for themselves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-shows-where-were-going-and-were-going-places&quot;&gt;4. It shows where we’re going… and we’re going places&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main drivers of our website overhaul was the rapid growth of the Wayfare coworking community. In two short years we’ve grown from 6 to 102 coworking members and our private offices are filled with small organizations that have become family (and there’s a waiting list)! We’ve hosted over one hundred gatherings from workshops to fundraiser dinners, birthed eight startups (and are launching four more in December), and have grown from a staff of three  to eleven. Our &lt;a href=&quot;/locations/costa-mesa&quot;&gt;HQ space&lt;/a&gt; is nearly at capacity and we not only needed a more robust website to handle the growth, but &lt;strong&gt;we needed to expand&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve never been the type to shy away from a challenge and are always seeking ways to serve and empower more people, so we started brainstorming expansion. For us, expansion is not (and will never be) about fame or fortune. While we will always strive for global impact, expansion is not about beating competitors, having a distinguished world-class name, or swimming in profit. It’s always been about the common good. It’s about creating the most good for all people, empowering hungry leaders, giving birth to creation restoring movements, providing safe places for community to flourish, helping people walk into their true calling, and about building a world where the most vulnerable thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We thoughtfully decided that the best way to achieve our mission and maximum impact was to launch a &lt;a href=&quot;/membership&quot;&gt;new membership model&lt;/a&gt; and expand to more &lt;a href=&quot;/locations&quot;&gt;locations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a straightforward yet powerful next step for growth, a timely response to current demand, and a solution that is already proven in the marketplace. Our &lt;a href=&quot;/membership&quot;&gt;new membership&lt;/a&gt; now allows us to be more inclusive of our global market, provide practical and relational resources for those who don’t necessarily need workspace, and provide more flexibility (and locations) for those that do. To support this growth, we needed a website and platform that could handle multiple locations and streamline our services, as well as make the critical shift from a local coworking space to a global community that enables us to welcome more world changers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoy the new site &amp;amp; that it inspires and drives you towards a life of greater impact. &lt;a href=&quot;/membership&quot;&gt;Looking for community&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;/locations&quot;&gt;Need a workspace&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;/startups&quot;&gt;Have an idea you’d like to turn into reality&lt;/a&gt;? We’d love to learn more about you, and we openly welcome any website &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.typeform.com/to/vn3h2H&quot;&gt;feedback and suggestions&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="website" /><category term="growth" /><category term="rebrand" /><category term="brand" /><category term="logo" /><summary type="html">After a two month labor of love, we couldn't be more excited to share the new Wayfare website with you today. Somewhere in the midst of two years of growth, building products and systems, refining Wayfare's business model, serving our members, and consuming copious amounts of coffee, our website and branding took the back seat. As our staff and membership has grown, it has become a top priority for us to create a new website that represents the dynamic, dimensional identity of our community today.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/4-reasons-why-were-excited-to-share-our-new-website.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Our Kids, Our Future</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/29/our-kids-our-future/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our Kids, Our Future" /><published>2016-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/29/our-kids-our-future</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/29/our-kids-our-future/">&lt;p&gt;The 2016-2017 school year is upon us and while Back to School is top of mind, we’re featuring various action steps that can be taken to support the kids, teachers, parents, and schools in our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many ways that any person can use what they have to contribute to the flourishing of our kids.  Today we are focusing on several ways to support kids in our area where &lt;strong&gt;we each can play a role in raising up the next generation of leaders, creators, innovators, and world-changers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-hope-alliancehttpwwwprojecthopeallianceorg-costa-mesa&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.projecthopealliance.org&quot;&gt;Project Hope Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, Costa Mesa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to their website, “Childhood homelessness is Orange County’s best-kept secret. Under its veil of affluence are the faces of more than 26,000 children experiencing homelessness and 126,000 children living in poverty. They say goodnight from motels, shelters, and couches.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Housing and education are inextricably linked to each other, but there is hope. By stabilizing families in their own homes and providing their children with an exceptional education, we can and will break the cycle of homelessness.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Step One // Volunteer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.projecthopealliance.org/secondsaturday/&quot;&gt;Second Saturdays&lt;/a&gt;: Second Saturdays are quarterly opportunities to help their offices with a range of projects, such as organizing the food pantry, stuffing backpacks, working on administrative tasks, or creating crafts or art projects for kids they serve. This help, although simple, is significantly far-reaching. These volunteer days are a time for individuals of all ages (even small kids), families, and groups to connect with Project Hope Alliance’s staff and mission while supporting the families they serve. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.projecthopealliance.org/secondsaturday/&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for more info or email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:connie@projecthopealliance.org&quot;&gt;Connie&lt;/a&gt; with any questions or to sign you or your group up to volunteer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Step Two // In-Kind Gifts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While financial donations are always appreciated, gifts of items, also known as in-kind gifts are also appreciated.  Their needs are frequently changing, so for an up to date list of current needs please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.projecthopealliance.org/in-kind-gifts/&quot;&gt;Project Hope webpage about in-kind gifts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-literacy-project-foundationhttpliteracyprojectfoundationorg-newport-beach-ca&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://literacyprojectfoundation.org&quot;&gt;The Literacy Project Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, Newport Beach, CA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact: Kimberly Vig&lt;br /&gt;
Email: kim@literacyprojectfoundation.org&lt;br /&gt;
Office Phone: 949.721.1319&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://literacyprojectfoundation.org&quot;&gt;The Literacy Project Website&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Currently 45 million Americans are functionally illiterate and cannot read above a 5th grade level.              50% of adults cannot read a book written at an 8th grade level.
57% of students failed the California Standards Test in English. 1/3 of fourth-graders reach the proficient reading level. 25% of six million kids in California school systems are able to perform basic reading skills. 85% of juvenile offenders have problems reading. 3 out of 5 people in American prisons can’t read. 3 out of 4 people on welfare can’t read
(Sources: National Institute for Literacy, National Center for Adult Literacy, The Literacy Company, U.S. Census Bureau).”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://literacyprojectfoundation.org&quot;&gt;The Literacy Project&lt;/a&gt; is leading the charge against growing illiteracy amongst school-age children. They are bridging the literacy gap by serving the literacy needs of struggling 2nd grade readers…the early makings of an at-risk student who may end up illiterate and lose all hope of living a productive adult life.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://literacyprojectfoundation.org&quot;&gt;The Literacy Project&lt;/a&gt; offers a comprehensive instructional program that improves both academic and attitudinal levels of students performing far below English proficiency standards. The program is aligned with Common Core and collaborative learning methods, and is administered by Master Teachers who are product-trained experts and highly credentialed as reading and language arts specialists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program is provided at no cost to both the school and qualified students in the 2nd grade. This program teaches the fundamental principles of phonics in all three learning modalities - auditory, visual and tactile - critical to children with varying learning styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their significant measurable results prove increased reading skill levels of up to 75% and positive increases in building self-esteem and better attitudes towards reading of up to 85%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Step // Donate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsor a struggling reader, donate toward expanding this unique program in all local elementary schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wilson-street-learning-center-costa-mesa&quot;&gt;Wilson Street Learning Center, Costa Mesa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilson St. Learning Center (WSLC) was formed in 2009 to provide a safe and comprehensive place for kids to go after school. The WSLC mission includes not just academic guidance but also meets the spiritual, physical, and emotional needs of the students that live nearby. Parents are an essential part of the WSLC and volunteer in the community through parenting classes, ESL, or joining nearby Wilson Elementary School’s PTA. Nearly 100 families participate and enroll their families in the opportunities at WSLC. After-school tutoring is every day from 3-5pm. Parenting classes are offered every Thursday evening 7-9pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Step&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get involved by becoming one of the following: after-school grade level academic volunteer, coach sports, give prayer support, donate classroom supplies and sports equipment, help paint classrooms, and assist with parent ESL classes at night. Financial contributions to continue all these programs, fund scholarships for graduating students, and add academic coordinators would be graciously received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact: Olga Parra&lt;br /&gt;
Email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:olgawslc@yahoo.com&quot;&gt;olgawslc@yahoo.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Phone: 949.630.6071&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;back-to-school-improv-night-fundraiserhttpswayfareticketleapcomwriters-room-improv-fundraiser-writers-room-productions&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/writers-room-improv-fundraiser/&quot;&gt;Back to School Improv Night Fundraiser&lt;/a&gt;, Writer’s Room Productions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, we’d love for you to join &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.writersroomproductions.org&quot;&gt;Writer’s Room Productions&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://wayfare.io/events&quot;&gt;Wayfare&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;Friday, September 16th&lt;/strong&gt; to help support this non-profit in their mission to ignite confidence and creatitvity in the next generation through creative writing and performances. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/writers-room-improv-fundraiser/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.writersroomproductions&quot;&gt;visit their website&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about this amazing non-profit organization and the ways you can support their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="costa-mesa" /><category term="education" /><category term="common-good" /><summary type="html">The 2016-2017 school year is upon us and while Back to School is top of mind, we’re featuring various action steps that can be taken to support the kids, teachers, parents, and schools in our community.

There are so many ways that any person can use what they have to contribute to the flourishing of our kids.  Today we are focusing on several ways to support kids in our area where we each can play a role in raising up the next generation of leaders, creators, innovators, and world-changers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/our-kids-our-future.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Member Monday: Sarah Heath</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/22/member-monday-sarah-heath/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Member Monday: Sarah Heath" /><published>2016-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/22/member-monday-sarah-heath</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/22/member-monday-sarah-heath/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah Heath&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best movie of all time is clearly….&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newsies and anything Guy Ritchie has made except for that one with Madonna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your favorite local restaurant?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been going to Durty Nelly’s for years. I love that little pub!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How would you spend your ideal day off?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Ideal day off would probably include one or all of the following: going on a run or to the gym, going on a road trip, taking my dog to the beach, dinner with friends with great food and conversation. Is it the weekend yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you could go anywhere in the world you haven’t been, where would you go and why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably cheating but Ireland. I am going there in October. My family is from England and as many times as I have been across the pond I have never gone to Ireland. There is something so captivating about photos of Ireland I can’t wait to see the beautiful landscape and visit all the local restaurants and pubs I am traveling with folks who have family there so it is going to be a fun adventure I think! Look out Australia you are next!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you do for work? Tell us a little bit about how you got to where you are today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a United Methodist Pastor. In July I was asked to help revitalize and relaunch the community at First UMC in Costa Mesa. I am the lucky person who gets to work at the 100 year old gorgeous church building on 19th!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I got there is a long story but here is the short version: I came to California after graduating from Grad school in North Carolina where I got my Mdiv at Duke University. It was in grad school that my passion for creating and curating community began. After grad school I was brought out to Irvine to do youth and college ministry. While at that church I was part of a team that created a new worship service and became the lead speaker for that service. I was then asked to go to Rancho Santa Margarita to serve as the preaching pastor of a church who had just merged with another community and I spent 5 years there. It was a wonderful community filled with diversity and creativity and I think really prepared me for the work here in Costa Mesa. It has been amazing to see the community already grow at this little historic church. It is diverse and welcoming and we are just a month into it! I just get to help move it forward and work with developing the site itself to be a place of safety and sanctuary in Costa Mesa. As we say it is “A heart for the city in the heart of the city”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you stay inspired? Productive?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am inspired by all the amazing friends I have who are bringing goodness to the world. I am also inspired by the people I work with and for. Seeing people go through transformation keeps this job inspiring. Watching lives move closer to who they were intended to be is awe inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that I always have a looming deadline whether it be a writing deadline, a speaking engagement, or just the fact that Sunday is ALWAYS coming I stay aware that deadlines are a constant! I love the apps Evernote and Asana both of those keep me productive and on task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your favorite part of your work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love getting to be with people in their biggest moments and I love creating things like art, talks, sermons, and studies that connect people to the divine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/member-monday-sarah-heath-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sarah Heath&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some of the biggest challenges of your work and what advice would you give to someone experiencing similar challenges?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time management is the hardest part of my job currently. From being a project manager for a big re-build project, to managing volunteers and creating weekly talks my time is filled with good things but I could work 24 hours everyday. I think the best thing I can do is create a team that help me take some of these things off of my desk. I think building a team is always one of the most important things about being a change maker!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you decide to work out of Wayfare?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the construction of our facility they took down the office space, not only that but someone kept stealing the cooper wire and so we didn’t even have electricity for a month. Just when I thought slow wifi was a stressor having no power caused us to have to get creative! I could have worked from home but being surrounded by change makers was always a goal for us. Working at Wayfare was an intentional choice for me to be in contact with those who were doing some really important and creative things in Costa Mesa that the church community can partner with and enact some crazy goodness in the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some ways (if any) we can support you and get involved with your work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have such a small amazing community I think anytime we can partner with people who are doing things to help change the world we are amplifying the difference we can make in the world. So I think partnerships are one of the greatest ways we can mutually support each other. I also don’t have tons of creative resources so I am always loving to support anyone doing the arts by providing a space for them to do that. And of course you are always welcome to our new/ancient community on Sundays at 10am!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connect with Sarah on social media &lt;strong&gt;@revsarahheath&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://fumccostamesa.org/&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; (site is under  construction!)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="costa-mesa" /><category term="member-monday" /><summary type="html">I could have worked from home but being surrounded by change makers was always a goal for us. I think anytime we can partner with people who are doing things to help change the world we are amplifying the difference we can make in the world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/member-monday-sarah-heath.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Member Monday: Jonathan Trigg</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/15/member-monday-jonathan-trigg/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Member Monday: Jonathan Trigg" /><published>2016-08-15T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-15T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/15/member-monday-jonathan-trigg</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/15/member-monday-jonathan-trigg/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Trigg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the name of your company/organization?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.theintegrated.life&quot;&gt;The Integrated Life&lt;/a&gt;, Inc., a startup seeking to address the needs of emerging adults as they transition into life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best movie of all time is clearly….&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dumb &amp;amp; Dumber&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your favorite local restaurant?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How would you spend your ideal day off?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fly Fishing. But my day to day reality is more like day dreaming of fly fishing… or ballin it up with Shaq and Kobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/member-monday-jonathan-trigg-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jonathan Trigg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you could go anywhere in the world you haven’t been, where would you go and why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ireland, to have a glass of irish whiskey with an Irish man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you do for work? Tell us a little bit about how you got to where you are today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently developing the business model for The Integrated which essentially supports emerging adults, age 18-26, transition into adulthood. I am writing the curriculum and developing the website as well as doing everything, except social media (because I have an awesome intern team and intern director!). The Integrated started about 2 years ago when I decided I wanted to mentor a few college students because it is such a vital and crucial developmental time for them. Gandolf, aka Jeff Tanner (co-founder of Wayfare), planted the seed that my ideas could turn into a non-profit… so here I am today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the Integrated is a startup and I needed some form of income, I also work at Sidecar Doughnuts &amp;amp; Coffee as a Manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you stay inspired and productive?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading, podcasts, and good conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your favorite part of your work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The free doughnuts and coffee. Duh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But seriously, I love sharing the mission and vision and seeing others get excited about it and want to be involved some how. It’s super fun. The other aspect is how much I continue to grow and be stretched as I try to figure this thing out. I have grown so much in so many areas of life. If you’d like to learn more about those areas of growth, check out my &lt;a href=&quot;www.theintegrated.life&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some of the biggest challenges of your work and what advice would you give to someone experiencing similar challenges?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unknown and the fear of making mistakes. Something I keep running into is that I miss 100% of the shots I don’t take. Yep, that’s from Wayne Gretzky, but it so true. Keep taking risks and every failure means knowledge and growth for pushing your business forward or just growing personally in all aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you decide to work out of Wayfare?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gandalf (Jeff Tanner) told me to. Whatever Gandolf says, you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started because I was and still am so new the the business and startup world and Wayfare is such a great support for me spiritually, practically, and emotionally as I press on into the wilderness of starting a business. There is also such a rad network of other entrepreneurs doing amazing things to advance the common good in different ways that makes working here so much fun to connect with, partner with, and collaborate with other like-minded folk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some ways (if any) we can support you and get involved with your work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult to say at the moment as the Wayfare community has and still supports me in every way I can imagine right now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing we are doing right now with the Integrated is collecting stories for our blog from adults that have experience &amp;amp; wisdom to share with young 20-somethings emerging into adulthood. We’d love to have you share the things you wish you would have heard when you were younger and the wisdom you’ve gleaned along the way. If you would like to share your story with us, please email me at &lt;strong&gt;jonathan@theintegrated.life&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visit the Integrated &lt;a href=&quot;http://theintegrated.life&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href=&quot;www.instagram.com/theintegrated&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/the_integrated&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="costa-mesa" /><category term="member-monday" /><summary type="html">I am currently developing the business model for The Integrated which essentially supports emerging adults, age 18-26, transition into adulthood. I am writing the curriculum and developing the website as well as doing everything, except social media (because I have an awesome intern team and intern director!). The Integrated started about 2 years ago when I decided I wanted to mentor a few college students because it is such a vital and crucial developmental time for them. Gandolf, aka Jeff Tanner (co-founder of Wayfare), planted the seed that my ideas could turn into a non-profit... so here I am today.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/member-monday-jonathan-trigg.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Writer’s Room Productions: Keeping the Arts in Education</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/15/writers-room-productions-keeping-the-arts-in-education/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Writer's Room Productions: Keeping the Arts in Education" /><published>2016-08-15T05:29:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-15T05:29:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/15/writers-room-productions-keeping-the-arts-in-education</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/15/writers-room-productions-keeping-the-arts-in-education/">&lt;p&gt;I’d like to introduce you to &lt;a href=&quot;http://wayfarelabs.org&quot;&gt;Wayfare Labs&lt;/a&gt; Alum, &lt;a href=&quot;http://writersroomproductions.org&quot;&gt;Writer’s Room Productions&lt;/a&gt; founded by Amber and Gabriel Robin. Here is cofounder Amber Robins’ story in her own words:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-story&quot;&gt;My Story&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in 2nd grade I was tested and diagnosed with dyslexia. For many months I felt like I couldn’t keep up with the rest of my class, and finally my parents had some answers. Because of this, I qualified for the RSP program at my school and three times a week I had to leave my regular class to do my school work in another room with a Special Ed aid. As a seven year old, I didn’t fully understand why I was being asked to work differently, but it definitely made me feel isolated. I learned very early on how to joke with my friends at school and be self deprecating about my situation. Part of the program was reading and writing. A lot of reading and writing. Late into 4th grade, my RSP teacher, Mrs. Jones told me that she was going to publish one of my stories in our library. I remember working on my story and the artwork for weeks. Figuring out where I wanted the words to be on the page and how big to draw my pictures. In May we turned in our stories and in June I got to see the final product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-dancing-book&quot;&gt;The Dancing Book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There it was. “The Dancing Book” By Amber Queen, 4th grade. I held in my hand the hard backed, 8.5 by 11 book with my name on the cover and &lt;strong&gt;I felt so proud of myself.&lt;/strong&gt; We took our books in and the librarian had even created my card for the card catalog and I was now a member of the Dewey Decimal System. As years went on I can remember going to the library just to visit my book. It lived on an end cap near the entrance with several other books written by students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t fully realize how much power this moment had in my life until much later, but knowing that someone,an adult, found value in my story was powerful. So powerful that here I am today loving my job because I get to tell kids all over Southern California that their stories have value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Knowing that someone, an adult, found value in my story was powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prof. George Land did a study regarding imagination/creativity by measuring abstract thought in children. Over the years these same children were tested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Test results amongst 5 year olds: 98%&lt;br /&gt;
Test results amongst 10 year olds: 30%&lt;br /&gt;
Test results amongst 15 year olds: 12%&lt;br /&gt;
Same test given to 280,000 adults: 2%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first drop off of 68% in abstract thought as it correlates with imagination and creativity is happening when children are still in elementary school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the Recession in 2008, &lt;strong&gt;schools have had to cut back on their extra arts programs&lt;/strong&gt; even more. Most of these programs now have to be funded by outside parent organizations. &lt;strong&gt;But there are over 4000 low income (also called Title 1) schools in California alone. These schools don’t have the access to funds for extra programs.&lt;/strong&gt; They are no longer exposed to live music, theater, or dance without the help of outside funding. These expressions not only bring joy and creativity to a child’s school experience, but are becoming a necessity for college and job placement. The space to be creative in the classroom is not what it should be today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keeping-creativity-in-the-classroom&quot;&gt;Keeping Creativity in the Classroom&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://writersroomproductions.org&quot;&gt;Writer’s Room Productions&lt;/a&gt; is a nonprofit dedicated to creating high quality arts education through the power of creative writing through a variety of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.writersroomproductions.org/programs&quot;&gt;programs&lt;/a&gt;. For fifteen years I have seen first hand the benefit of imagination in schools. Confidence comes out of being validated and encouraged. We ignite confidence AND creativity through creative writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors-showcase&quot;&gt;Authors Showcase&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you remember the story you wrote about your summer vacation in third grade? Or the one about your Imaginary Friend going on an adventure to Disneyland? Do you have children? Imagine the story they wrote for class this year…  Now imagine that story coming to life on stage, in a room full of schoolmates and family cheering them on. Our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.writersroomproductions.org/programs#AUTHORSSHOWCASE&quot;&gt;Authors Showcase&lt;/a&gt; team of professional actors and musicians are inspired by the creative writing students are already doing in their classrooms. &lt;strong&gt;My story came to life in a book, and we’re now bringing stories to life through live theater!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As August of 2016 we have produced 98 student stories at 12 different schools and camps in and around Southern California. By June of 2017 we want to have produced 300 stories! In April we launched our Podcast series &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.writersroomproductions.org/podcast&quot;&gt;Story Rocket&lt;/a&gt;, featuring some of these stories that we have turned into podcast theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end of the 2017 school year will mark two full seasons for our organization. Not only will these 300 stories have been showcased, but their family, friends, teachers and schoolmates will all be asking themselves the same question, “What Story Will I Tell?” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now I ask you the question, “What story will you help tell?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-you-can-help&quot;&gt;How You Can Help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check out ways you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.writersroomproductions.org/get-involved&quot;&gt;support and donate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Subscribe to and share the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.writersroomproductions.org/podcast&quot;&gt;Story Rocket Podcast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connections: Do you know a school, camp or children’s hospital that could benefit from our programs? Or will you help us make even more connections in the entertainment industry? &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:programs@writersroomproductions.org&quot;&gt;Contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read more about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.writersroomproductions.org/programs#AUTHORSPLANET&quot;&gt;Authors Planet&lt;/a&gt;, our &lt;a href=&quot;https://gospaces.com/s/StM_&quot;&gt;Creative Writing Curriculum&lt;/a&gt;, and our partnership with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.classy.org/checkout/donation?eid=67944&quot;&gt;Royal Family Kids Camp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="startups" /><category term="education" /><category term="arts" /><summary type="html">When I was in 2nd grade I was tested and diagnosed with dyslexia. For many months I felt like I couldn’t keep up with the rest of my class, and finally my parents had some answers. Because of this, I qualified for the RSP program at my school and three times a week I had to leave my regular class to do my school work in another room with a Special Ed aid. As a seven year old, I didn’t fully understand why I was being asked to work differently, but it definitely made me feel isolated. I learned very early on how to joke with my friends at school and be self deprecating about my situation.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/writers-room-productions-keeping-the-arts-in-education.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Reasons an Internship is Worth Your Time</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/12/5-reasons-an-internship-is-worth-your-time/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Reasons an Internship is Worth Your Time" /><published>2016-08-12T23:26:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-12T23:26:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/12/5-reasons-an-internship-is-worth-your-time</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/12/5-reasons-an-internship-is-worth-your-time/">&lt;p&gt;If you’re on the fence about interning this semester, we say: go for it!&lt;!-- more --&gt; Here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life-long relationships&lt;/strong&gt; This is the sexy version of “networking” (we hate the word networking). Knowing people  significantly boosts your credibility and chances of being hired somewhere. Being intentional about investing in the people around you throughout your internship builds relational equity—something that is invaluable as you begin to pursue a long-term career.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A higher starting salary.&lt;/strong&gt; College graduates who have an internship under heir belt are actually able to compete for higher starting wages. Having gone through an internship program shows your employers that you’re one step ahead of the next guy, with relevant experience and solid references to back it up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academia meets practical experience.&lt;/strong&gt; An internship offers you a unique opportunity to bridge college and your career. A good internship program will give you real projects &amp;amp; responsibilities so you can take 12+ years of head-knowledge and begin to apply it in a real-world setting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Résumé-building.&lt;/strong&gt; Let’s be honest, most of our college résumés were less than impressive. Part time here, babysitting there… internships add some meat to the bones of your resume. They tell your future employers that you went out of your way to seek experience and assure them that you would add concrete value to their company.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take your career on a test-run.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s like like playing house—you get to try something out without the burden of a long term commitment. You discover your strengths, your weaknesses, what you love about work, and what you can’t stand. You learn what type of people you work well with and what type of people you clash with. You find out what gives you life and what drains you. Internships are key to personal and professional development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to intern at Wayfare? Head to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/internships&quot;&gt;wayfare.io/internships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to apply + find out more, we can’t wait to meet you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="internship" /><category term="career" /><summary type="html">If you’re on the fence about interning this semester, we say: go for it!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/5-reasons-an-internship-is-worth-your-time.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Member Monday: Ally Garvin of Neat Coffee</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/08/member-monday-ally-garvin-of-neat-coffee/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Member Monday: Ally Garvin of Neat Coffee" /><published>2016-08-08T09:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-08T09:30:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/08/member-monday-ally-garvin-of-neat-coffee</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/08/08/member-monday-ally-garvin-of-neat-coffee/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ally Garvin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the name of your company?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://neat.coffee&quot;&gt;Neat Coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best movie of all time is clearly….&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E.T.!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your favorite local restaurant?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boathouse Collective&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How would you spend your ideal day off?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would spend my whole day off outside, from sunrise to sunset. Throw in a few good meals, a hike, the ocean, something new and some friends and it’s perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you could go anywhere in the world you haven’t been, where would you go and why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would go to Japan to check out the local coffee culture, eat amazing food and explore the smaller towns and countryside with David.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you do for work? Tell us a little bit about how you got to where you are today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day to day, you can mostly find me slinging lattes, running errands, creating new syrup flavors and catching up with my regulars but I am slowly making more time for myself to work on my business instead of at my business. If I had known how much hard work being a business owner would take, I probably would have never taken the leap but I can’t imagine doing anything else. After falling in love with coffee on a farm in Uganda and working at 3 local coffee shops here in Costa Mesa, I decided to go for it on my own. I am currently the owner, manager, accountant, social media coordinator, and one of two baristas for Neat Coffee but I am working hard toward eventually having a full team, a better work/life balance and a larger shop that serves excellent coffee and provides a healthy space for the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/175587975&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;267&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/175587975&quot;&gt;Neat Coffee | Our Story&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/user54578162&quot;&gt;Neat.Coffee&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you stay inspired? Productive?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stay inspired by hearing other people’s stories and visiting other coffee shops. On my admin days, I enjoy placing orders and working out my profit margins from the comfort of Wayfare’s lounge chairs and couches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your favorite part of your work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people I get to see everyday, working with other local businesses and dreaming about the future of Neat Coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/member-monday-ally-garvin-of-neat-coffee-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ally Garvin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some of the biggest challenges of your work and what advice would you give to someone experiencing similar challenges?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the nitty gritty of working out profit margins, and knowing who and when to hire, it’s hard to stay focused and to know what to say yes or no to as a new business owner. Create a vision/philosophy for your business based on your morals, values and goals and then let that guide your decisions. I would also suggest meeting on a regular basis with another business owner or someone smarter than you. Ask for help. Write down all of your ideas. Make tangible to-do lists and then create check points for yourself. It’s important to look back at even a month ago to see what you’ve accomplished and then decide what you want/need to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you decide to work out of Wayfare?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Keri Fox gave me the idea! I wanted a space where I could start out small, keep a low overhead and gain momentum while looking for a larger location. Wayfare has been the absolute ideal spot to start up shop and I don’t think I’ll ever leave. Neat and Wayfare are both based around a model of community and it turns out that we’re pretty complimentary to each other :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some ways (if any) we can support you and get involved with your work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wayfare community has already done so much for Neat. Thanks for being so encouraging and supportive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit Neat &lt;a href=&quot;http://neat.coffee&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/neat.coffee&quot;&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;, and stop by to enjoy a tasty honey cinnamon or lavender latte during Neat’s open hours:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mondays-Fridays: 7am-4pm&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;amp; Saturdays: 8am-noon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located inside Wayfare at the corner of Baker &amp;amp; Redhill at &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/maps/PH8TPTV6rKN2&quot;&gt;270 Baker St E, Ste 200, Costa Mesa, CA 92626&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="costa-mesa" /><category term="member-monday" /><category term="coffee" /><summary type="html">Day to day, you can mostly find me slinging lattes, running errands, creating new syrup flavors and catching up with my regulars but I am slowly making more time for myself to work on my business instead of at my business. If I had known how much hard work being a business owner would take, I probably would have never taken the leap but I can't imagine doing anything else. After falling in love with coffee on a farm in Uganda and working at 3 local coffee shops here in Costa Mesa, I decided to go for it on my own. I am currently the owner, manager, accountant, social media coordinator, and one of two baristas for Neat Coffee but I am working hard toward eventually having a full team, a better work/life balance and a larger shop that serves excellent coffee and provides a healthy space for the community.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/member-monday-ally-garvin-of-neat-coffee-3.jpg" /></entry></feed>
