<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://wayfare.io/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://wayfare.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://wayfare.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-12-02T22:29:12+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io//</id><title type="html">Wayfare</title><entry><title type="html">Building Creation Economies: The Confounding Merger of Work and Leisure</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/02/the-confounding-merger-of-work-and-leisure/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building Creation Economies: The Confounding Merger of Work and Leisure" /><published>2016-12-02T18:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-02T18:20:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/02/the-confounding-merger-of-work-and-leisure</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/02/the-confounding-merger-of-work-and-leisure/">&lt;p&gt;On a Sunday morning in February of 2013, I began a journey that has been transforming the way I understand my life and work. In a profound spiritual encounter, I was called out of an 8 year career in banking that had brought comfort and control to me and my family, and God gave me two objectives: 1. Have my identity rooted in him, and 2. Live a life of adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I began the transition out of my job and into an unknown adventure where I would begin challenging my previously held understanding of work, a cultural transition was happening in the entertainment industry, which was also challenging my understanding of leisure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For context, I was born in the 70s, so my most formative early memories of television were in the 1980s. I would wait in eager anticipation of Sunday nights when the A-team would pull of their next miraculous feat and their fearless leader, Hannibal Smith, would deliver my favorite line: “I love it when a plan comes together.” In fact, I was so captivated by their work that I learned to play their theme song on the piano. It’s actually ringing in my ears right now and giving me energy as I write. But I digress. In the 90s, my curiosity and desire for adventure was catalyzed on Wednesday nights through agents Mulder and Scully of the X-files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while we would occasionally and haphazardly tape shows on our VCR, for the most part, we were still eager for the event–not the escape from, but the entrance into a new story, a new adventure, a new possibility. And in the words of modern day prophets, Arcade Fire, “We used to wait for it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as VCRs, DVRs, and Netflix ushered the term “binge watching” into our national rhetoric, there was a point when my leisure time began to feel like work. I’m not sure exactly when it happened, but many shows began to feel necessary but burdensome. The began to feel like toil. Obligation. “I just have to make it through this.” “It’s on my list.” Or, I have to watch this so I can compete for social relevancy with my friends. Or my favorite (and most embarrassing): “My wife is watching this show in the next room, and I need to keep up with her.” As I began to become aware of this strange experience, I was initially reluctant to share this with others for fear that I was the only one so dysfunctional, but as I began to carefully broach the topic, I realized–unfortunately–I’m not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this phenomenon has been further engrained in our lives through the storyfication of social media. This week, I’ve found myself habitually defaulting to my Instagram story feed at least once, but let’s be honest, more like 10 times a day, for fear of missing out on the lives of close friends who I could be talking to instead….and strangers who I’ve never met but with whom I have a parasocial relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these two converging shifts, I found myself adopting a holy curiosity about work and leisure that have prompted a deep introspection for me about how I want to live my life, and I know I’m not alone. As we’ve convened creators, doers, and adventurers for the common good in this community we call Wayfare, I’ve engaged in enough conversations and been asked enough compelling questions to prompt a deeper dive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we begin this conversation as a community, I’d love to know what questions you have or what challenges you face in this realm. Tweet your thoughts + questions to @wayfarehq or email me at jeff@wayfare.io.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="creation" /><category term="economy" /><category term="life" /><category term="community" /><category term="common good" /><category term="leisure" /><summary type="html">On a Sunday morning in February of 2013, I began a journey that has been transforming the way I understand my life and work. In a profound spiritual encounter, I was called out of an 8 year career in banking that had brought comfort and control to me and my family, and God gave me two objectives: 1. Have my identity rooted in him, and 2. Live a life of adventure.

As I began the transition out of my job and into an unknown adventure where I would begin challenging my previously held understanding of work, a cultural transition was happening in the entertainment industry, which was also challenging my understanding of leisure.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/s3d29ihiuqa-ryan-jacobs.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Allkiind: In it for Good</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/29/allkiind-in-it-for-good/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Allkiind: In it for Good" /><published>2016-11-29T23:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-29T23:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/29/allkiind-in-it-for-good</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/29/allkiind-in-it-for-good/">&lt;p&gt;In the middle of the hot summer of 2016 in a garage in Fullerton, CA, a few friends got together and dreamed. It may be cliché, but they wanted to create the best business they could imagine: an excellent brand with a pure heart. They wanted to do something truly good and make the world brighter. 
They talked and bonded and rallied around certain indispensable values. We brainstormed 50 possible names and wrote them on a whiteboard. We lived on iced coffee from Starbucks and Del Taco burritos (and they still have hundreds of hot sauce packets).&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“[We] talked about our sincere desire to make the world better. We started with our values and built a business that would embody them”, said Luke Laubhan, Co-Founder &amp;amp; Co-CEO, “We knew we valued inclusiveness, and agreed that unity, positivity (the opposite of cynicism) and honesty are building blocks for a better reality. We aspired to be global. We liked the idea of ‘mankind,’ something that represents all of our infinite potential. [And] finally, Allkiind clicked.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the midst of brainstorming and burritos on another 90 degree day, it all took shape. The dream materialized, and Allkiind was born. &lt;strong&gt;Allkiind is a social enterprise that makes lifestyle products, speaks boldly into people and everyday culture, and financially supports a variety of causes and non-profits… all for the common good.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allkiind’s chief cause is to truly do good, across every aspect of the company, broadly and openly. Specifically, they’ve focused on three main areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They’ve focused on building an ethical and responsible supply chain.&lt;/strong&gt; Allkiind wants to do it right at every level and for them, it means making as much as they can personally and locally where they can see things up close, and holding out for WRAP certification abroad. It also means being intentional about their environmental impact, from using recycled packaging to our own giant, blue recycle bin at HQ.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;**They’re committed to speaking boldly. **Allkiind’s messaging aims to challenge and celebrate. They aspire to positively challenge themselves, others, the status quo, and injustice; and eagerly celebrate the good stuff in life: beauty, people, causes, and victories - there’s so much!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They give back tangibly to good deeds, charitable causes, and non-profits.&lt;/strong&gt; Allkiind is committed to making a tangible impact in the world, rolling up their sleeves and diving in it (for good). So, off the top, Allkiind donates 10% of its revenue to charitable causes and non-profits. There’s no fuzzy math: If a customer buys a $10 item, Allkiind donates $1. When someone spends $100, they donate $10. It really adds up! They select causes and non-profits based on their team’s research and suggestions from the Allkiind community. To be transparent, they post their give-back stories on their blog (it’s a part of the whole celebration thing).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allkiind is just a little over three months old (they launched in August ‘16), and they’ve already inspired and changed lives through their process and products. They’ve been able to provide everything from socks for the local homeless community to Halloween costumes for kids in need. Allkiind has donated school supplies, delivered headbands to those fighting cancer, and financially helped a variety of charitable organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt; “With a small staff and a brand new operation, almost every step requires everyone’s time and attention. That said, it’s a uniquely collaborative environment, and it’s fun to be all pulling in the same direction, working on different aspects of the same stuff. It really is a team effort. There’s three of us working in a garage every day, building out a business from scratch. With all the work to do and a great big world in need, it’s not hard to stay focused. To be honest, we still don’t know everything Allkiind will be. That’s part of the adventure. But we do know our values, [and] we feel like we’re just getting started. Operating a business is a journey, and there’s a lot to learn, but our mission fuels us: Allkiind will challenge ourselves and others, and it will celebrate the good.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re inspired by the team at AllKiind team and the beautiful way they are pursuing work &amp;amp; the common good. They are a living example of “a small group of thoughtful, committed citizens [that] can change the world”, and they have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to have them a part of &lt;a href=&quot;wayfare.ticketleap.com/spread-joy&quot;&gt;Spread Joy&lt;/a&gt; Market this Saturday at Wayfare Costa Mesa! Stop by THIS Saturday from 11 AM - 4PM to shop Allkiind products, meet the team, and enjoy a Neat Coffee or one of many incredible local food vendors! Click to learn more about Spread Joy or enter our door prize giveaway!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="business" /><category term="creativity" /><category term="common" /><category term="common-good" /><category term="lifestyle" /><category term="brand" /><category term="give" /><category term="back" /><category term="giving" /><category term="charity" /><category term="nonprofit" /><category term="values" /><category term="allkiind" /><category term="ethical" /><category term="responsible" /><category term="celebrate" /><category term="spread-joy" /><summary type="html">In the middle of the hot summer of 2016 in a garage in Fullerton, CA, a few friends got together and dreamed. It may be cliché, but they wanted to create the best business they could imagine: an excellent brand with a pure heart. They wanted to do something truly good and make the world brighter. 
They talked and bonded and rallied around certain indispensable values. We brainstormed 50 possible names and wrote them on a whiteboard. We lived on iced coffee from Starbucks and Del Taco burritos (and they still have hundreds of hot sauce packets).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/all-kiind.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning and Cultivating your Strengths: Insights from a Wayfare Intern</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/29/learning-and-cultivating-your-strengths-insights-from-a-wayfare-intern/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning and Cultivating your Strengths: Insights from a Wayfare Intern" /><published>2016-11-29T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-29T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/29/learning-and-cultivating-your-strengths-insights-from-a-wayfare-intern</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/29/learning-and-cultivating-your-strengths-insights-from-a-wayfare-intern/">&lt;p&gt;The light streaming into the beautiful shared space was the first thing I noticed. The natural light from the atrium created this warm glow, but the most impressive light came from the passionate people who worked at Wayfare and I only noticed it more and more as the internship continued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What even is an internship? A part time job before an actual job? An internship is not about showing off your strengths, it’s about learning and cultivating them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the very first things the interns did together was take a Strengths Finder test and discuss our results as a group. Totally clueless going into the test, I was so surprised by the results. Not only did I learn the nuances of my strengths, I learned how diverse the other interns and staff were. The beauty of this exercise was that no two people were the same and together we could complement each other to accomplish amazing goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of us could not be any more different. Alandra was a recent college grad with a photography degree, nervous about how far her new art degree could take her. Desiree worked a full time job, Allie had just moved to Orange County from Chicago, and I was still in college, intimidated about being the youngest one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of this internship we got to see so many amazing things fulfilled. Interns usually get shafted and degraded into solely getting coffee or filing paperwork. But at Wayfare, we were treated like part of the Wayfare family. Work seriously becomes play when you’re surrounded by rad people and a cute little coffee shop that keeps you highly caffeinated. It’s so refreshing and inspiring to see a community like this dive full force into what they believe while keeping their core values and the common good at the center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only were we encouraged to build on our existing strengths, we were all motivated to discover strengths we never knew we had. Alandra learned that she was capable of so much more in just three mere months and that her passion for photography could be implemented into multiple avenues of work. She explored creative direction, social media marketing strategy, visual branding, and story telling with a team that was generous, encouraging, and kind. Deziree was able to utilize her creative side to help with graphics and visuals for various projects and give input in upcoming campaigns. As the front end web development intern, Allie was able grow in her web development skills by taking ownership of website revisions and asset creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I was the youngest intern, my voice was still heard. It was heard most clearly in the captions, content planning, and blog posts that I took ownership of. Every day was an adventure, tailoring stories at Wayfare, exploring the lives of others, and trying to capture that light that I was so enthralled by on the first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The light comes streaming in from everyones’ smiles, the passion that drives their dreams, the way they interact with one another and I know we’ve all been so blessed to have this experience and soak in this light for this short internship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayfare is about community and you are all a part of that. When you embrace it and run with it, we all become stronger, wiser and more effective. We have learned so much here about leadership and quality work from these humble souls. We are leaving better people and that has been the biggest take away. You can’t buy that or fake it, you have to actually experience the light that flows from here and live it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="internship" /><category term="work" /><category term="strengths" /><summary type="html">The light streaming into the beautiful shared space was the first thing I noticed. The natural light from the atrium created this warm glow, but the most impressive light came from the passionate people who worked at Wayfare and I only noticed it more and more as the internship continued.

What even is an internship? A part time job before an actual job? An internship is not about showing off your strengths, it’s about learning and cultivating them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/nfta8pdaq9a-bench-accounting.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Blankets that Feed: Chris &amp;amp; Jesenia’s Entrepreneurial Journey</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/23/blankets-that-feed-chris-and-jesenias-entrepreneurial-journey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blankets that Feed: Chris &amp; Jesenia's Entrepreneurial Journey" /><published>2016-11-23T11:05:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-23T11:05:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/23/blankets-that-feed-chris-and-jesenias-entrepreneurial-journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/23/blankets-that-feed-chris-and-jesenias-entrepreneurial-journey/">&lt;p&gt;Focused on a mission to feed Christmas dinners to families in need, Chris &amp;amp; Jesenia Pena created &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siestasforfiestas.com&quot;&gt;Siestas for Fiestas&lt;/a&gt;: blankets that provide hope and meals to families in Cancun, Mexico. For every blanket that is sold, a Christmas meal is provided to a family living in poverty in Cancun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siestasforfiestas.com&quot;&gt;Siestas For Fiestas&lt;/a&gt; was born out of a desire to support our church in Cancun as they provide Christmas meals for families living in poverty. The church we attended while living in Cancun had a yearly project of providing families with Christmas meals. We were moving back to LA and wanted to find a way to support them. At the same time we had fallen in love with the material our blankets are made out of and thought, why don’t we make beach blankets out of them and sell them to support the church? It started small with just 16 blankets, but has grown significantly in the last year. This is a blessing because the more blankets we sell, the more meals we can provide to families in need.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dinners &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siestasforfiestas.com&quot;&gt;Siestas for Fiestas&lt;/a&gt; provides are packaged in a way that families can easily pick up at the local church and take back home to enjoy as a family on Christmas Eve. The meal includes a rotisserie chicken, 2 pounds of soup, 2 pounds of salad, a 2 liter soda, 4 dinner rolls, and paper goods (utensils, plates, and napkins). All is packed inside a reusable container with a sticker that, when translated says, “Jesus goes with me”. By providing families with meals, they are able to share love and hope with families who are really struggling financially. Most of the families they serve live in homes that don’t have electricity or access to water, making it hard for them to have a hot, homemade meal. Christmas is usually spent like any other day, but the meals provided by Siestas for Fiestas give them something special to enjoy with their families. Through this they know they are loved and not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The most life-giving part of our work is knowing that we are being used to provide for God’s people. We have no idea what we’re doing most of the time. We didn’t study fashion and don’t know how to sew, and running a business is hard work. This is why it’s so important to make it a point to focus on our mission &amp;amp; remember why we started when things get hard. We constantly tell ourselves ‘You are feeding a family, this is worth it!’ Knowing we are providing meals to families so they can have a Christmas fiesta keeps us determined through the hard times.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through their mission, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siestasforfiestas.com&quot;&gt;Siestas for Fiestas&lt;/a&gt; is bridging the gap for everyday consumers to be a part of something bigger. Each blanket provides a meal for an entire family, and their customers have the opportunity to buy a blanket and directly bless a family across the world on Christmas day. In the next year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siestasforfiestas.com&quot;&gt;Siestas for Fiestas&lt;/a&gt; will be working closely with their church in Cancun on new projects that create opportunities for those living in poverty so they may provide for themselves and their families to end poverty in the areas surrounding Cancun, Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join them in their mission by buying a blanket at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/spread-joy/&quot;&gt;Spread Joy Market&lt;/a&gt; here at Wayfare Costa Mesa on Saturday, December 3rd from 11AM-4PM.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="entrepreneur" /><category term="founder" /><category term="social-enterprise" /><category term="impact" /><category term="blankets" /><category term="give-back" /><category term="cancun" /><category term="mexico" /><category term="Christmas" /><category term="siestas" /><category term="fiestas" /><category term="poverty" /><category term="empowerment" /><category term="blanket" /><summary type="html">Focused on a mission to feed Christmas dinners to families in need, Chris &amp;amp; Jesenia Pena created Siestas for Fiestas: blankets that provide hope and meals to families in Cancun, Mexico. For every blanket that is sold, a Christmas meal is provided to a family living in poverty in Cancun.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/siestas-for-fiestas.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Role of Gratitude in a Broken Yet Beautiful World</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/21/the-role-of-gratitude-in-a-broken-yet-beautiful-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Role of Gratitude in a Broken Yet Beautiful World" /><published>2016-11-21T17:29:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-21T17:29:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/21/the-role-of-gratitude-in-a-broken-yet-beautiful-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/21/the-role-of-gratitude-in-a-broken-yet-beautiful-world/">&lt;p&gt;This week our thoughts turn toward pumpkin pie, mashed potatoes, family, friends, and gratitude. Many of us will gather around tables and perhaps a grown up (gasp … I think I might be that grown up now) may encourage us to say something we are grateful for. Admittedly at times in my past (especially as a teenager) this was an awkward exchange and felt a tad cheesy.  But I think the practice of gratitude deserves some further exploration and it could serve us well to incorporate it into our daily lives, not just around a table once a year. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studies have been done on the role that gratitude plays in a person’s life.  The book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.intelligentchange.com/products/the-five-minute-journal&quot;&gt;The Five Minute Journal&lt;/a&gt;, talks about studies that show that the practice of intentional gratitude improves the overall physical and emotional well-being of people.   This begs the question: How do we do that? It is easy to do when things are going well, but often harder to practice when we are experiencing difficult times, loss, grief, or even when we are just having an off day. The practice of gratitude does not not entail ignoring the realities of life, but rather celebrating in the midst of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-steps-to-incorporating-gratitude-into-daily-life&quot;&gt;5 Steps to Incorporating Gratitude into Daily Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following are 5 things that I have practiced (sometimes more consistently than others) that have made a real difference for me in living a life of intentional gratitude.  Perhaps they can be a jumping off point for you as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;start-a-gratitude-journal&quot;&gt;Start a Gratitude Journal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a notebook and start listing what you are thankful for. That’s all. Choose a time in your day whether it be upon waking, while you sip your coffee, around the dinner table, or as you go to bed to intentionally list out 3 things you are thankful for each day. Grab a pen and start writing. Try not to repeat yourself. It is truly amazing that number of things that can be celebrated! It is also a great way to keep a record to look back on during difficult times that can serve as an uplifting tool.  So do it as something you can do to benefit your current self and your future self as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;focus-on-who-not-just-what&quot;&gt;Focus On Who, Not Just What&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If thanksgiving literally means the giving of thanks, then there is naturally someone to whom thanks can be given. This makes the focus not only on what you are thankful for, but takes it a step further and allows you to recognize to whom you can give thanks. As a person who believes in God, I tend to give thanks to God as kind of a catch all for everything I am thankful for. As I’ve been writing this post I have begun to consider the people to whom I can direct my thanks.  So if you aren’t someone who believes in God, or even if you are, try considering which people to whom you could express thanks. For example, being thankful for food can lead us to be thankful for the farmer who grew it,  the worker who harvested it, and the person who stocked the shelves. As I consider who these people are, even though I’ve never met them, it draws an awareness in me that I am just one part of a greater community of people. This allows me to think about a life experience outside of my own, which is a great way to consider the important role each of us plays in our communities, relationships, and the world. So, next to your list of the things you are thankful for, write down who can be thanked as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tell-people&quot;&gt;Tell People&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you consider the people who you can thank, if it is possible, tell them. This act of expressing gratitude draws us into relationship with other people and there is transformative power in living life alongside others, investing in them and being invested in. Expressing gratitude to others can be as simple as a text to your friend telling them that you appreciate the role they play in your life, writing a note and sending it via snail mail, delivering cookies to the local fire or police department, or handing a bottle of water to the person who collects your garbage. At a minimum, practice saying thank you. Sometimes the frantic pace of a day leads me to interact with people and I don’t pause long enough to say thank you for the simple things people do for me every day. The person who makes my coffee, the delivery person who brings the packages, the person who cleans the table at the restaurant or fills my water are all things that I am indeed grateful for, but sometimes I forget to express it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ask-people&quot;&gt;Ask People&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a friend who also happens to be a member of the Wayfare community and she asks the best questions. Instead of simply asking the expected “How are you?”, she asks things like, “What are you most looking forward to today?”,  “What is your favorite thing about fall?”, “What are you working on that is really life giving?”. When she asks these questions it always gets me to pause, think, and intentionally reflect upon the good that is a part of every day.  Another way to ask questions that point toward gratitude is the game Highs and Lows. We often play it around the dinner table as a family and it entails each person sharing the best and worst parts of their day. It fully acknowledges that there are hard parts of life and yet there is always room for gratitude even right alongside the not so great stuff. Sometimes when it is a particularly bad day, my default “high” is, “I drank coffee.”  And, let me tell you, I am legitimately thankful that there is always coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-good-thing&quot;&gt;One Good Thing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be real. Sometimes it’s really hard to practice gratitude. This life is full of incredibly wonderful things and horribly heavy things. Sometimes there are seasons where it seems like nothing can possibly be called good. What if in the midst of the thick of it, something good can be found? My thoughts during these times in my own life can go one of two ways. I can spiral into every possible negative outcome of my current circumstances and end up feeling continuously worse and worse or I can acknowledge and experience the sadness for what it is, and then identify one good thing. Just one. It requires some creativity, and it is surprising to me that it is usually the direct result of the current suffering. For example, several of my best friends are people who I met as a direct result of going through some of the darkest seasons of my life. Most of my greatest personal growth has occurred during times of difficulty. Sometimes, when I can’t possibly see anything good in the suffering, I choose to change my focus (even if for a minute) and be thankful for sunshine, chocolate, coffee, and warm blankets. So if you find yourself in a place of struggle and all of this focus on positivity is a bit too much, I want to encourage you to allow yourself to be sad &amp;amp; share that grief with others, but also take a tiny step in the direction of gratitude. If nothing else, in acknowledging and experiencing grief, we can allow these times and seasons to develop relationships with others who have experienced similar challenges, and that is something we can celebrate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is in this posture of thanksgiving — the giving of thanks—  for things and to others, acknowledging the brokenness of the human existence and the simultaneous beauty of the many things we can celebrate — it is here where there exists the power of gratitude to transform individuals, communities, and in turn, the world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="thanksgiving" /><category term="gratitude" /><category term="family" /><category term="grateful" /><category term="thankful" /><category term="journal" /><category term="broken" /><category term="beautiful" /><category term="hardship" /><category term="grief" /><category term="intentional" /><summary type="html">This week our thoughts turn toward pumpkin pie, mashed potatoes, family, friends, and gratitude. Many of us will gather around tables and perhaps a grown up (gasp … I think I might be that grown up now) may encourage us to say something we are grateful for. Admittedly at times in my past (especially as a teenager) this was an awkward exchange and felt a tad cheesy.  But I think the practice of gratitude deserves some further exploration and it could serve us well to incorporate it into our daily lives, not just around a table once a year.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/the-role-of-gratitude.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">World-Class Products Meet Worldwide Change</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/18/world-class-products-meet-worldwide-change/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="World-Class Products Meet Worldwide Change" /><published>2016-11-18T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-18T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/18/world-class-products-meet-worldwide-change</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/18/world-class-products-meet-worldwide-change/">&lt;p&gt;Meet &lt;a href=&quot;parkerclay.com&quot;&gt;Parker Clay&lt;/a&gt;! Through the sale of high-quality leather goods, they are creating jobs for people coming out of human trafficking in Ethiopia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founder Ian Bentley tells the story behind Parker Clay, and the experience that moved him and his wife Brittany to act on the problem they were experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Back in 2008 we were moved by the number of orphans living in the world. Some statistics place the numbers at 163 million orphans worldwide. While those statistics are alarming, and we looked at these numbers and said, “What if that was Parker or Clayton?”, our two biological children. From that moment, the journey to Ethiopia started and in 2011 when we brought home our Ethiopian daughter, Selah, who was 5 months old at the time. While in Ethiopia we spent time with a number of organizations looking for ways to address some of the root causes to poverty and the disruption of family. It was soon after this that we packed up our lives and moved to Ethiopia to help with development work centered around job creation and capacity development with vulnerable women.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once they were on the ground in Ethiopia, they quickly learned that Addis Ababa’s central market is the site of numerous brothels, where girls as young as 8 are exploited into prostitution. &lt;br /&gt;
Ian + Brittany began partnering with Women at Risk, an organization that helps with rehabilitation and job placement opportunities across Ethiopia, so that they could work firsthand with vulnerable women caught up in the commercial sex industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They met Zewditu, who became one of the first women to join the Parker Clay team. Zewditu is in her early 20’s and comes from a farming family just outside of Ethiopia’s capital city, Addis Ababa. When Zewditu was a young girl, her mother passed away and a lot of pressure was placed on her older sister to provide for the family. Her older sister was forced to go to an Arab country to look for work so she could send money back to her family. Afraid that she might have to make a similar choice, Zewditu came to Parker Clay where she was trained to sew and offered a job. She now dreams of getting married and having kids of her own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zewditu’s story is one of empowerment and change, where her value and dignity was restored through Parker Clay’s unique mission. While they love sharing the story of individuals behind their products, Parker Clay believes that the story of community is just as significant. Parker Clay has cultivated a unique community of farmers, tanneries, and artisans who are involved at every step of the process until the product ends up in the consumer’s hands. Through the purchase of their unique products, the consumer becomes part of a global community and a larger impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Parker Clay is about showing these women that they see them, they care about them, and they support them. Their advise for aspiring social enterprises?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Be willing to go deep into relationship and be prepared for a messy process that comes with developing relationship. Let your vision guide you and be aware of mission drift. You might start with great intentions, but then find yourself compromising the very purpose and impact you are trying to make. Hold ruthlessly to your vision, even perhaps at cost for short term gain.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be a part of the larger story that Parker Clay is crafting, and shop their leather goods this season at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/spread-joy/&quot;&gt;Spread Joy Market!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><summary type="html">Meet Parker Clay! Through the sale of high-quality leather goods, they are creating jobs for people coming out of human trafficking in Ethiopia.

Founder Ian Bentley tells the story behind Parker Clay, and the experience that moved him and his wife Brittany to act on the problem they were experiencing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/low_res.jpg.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Give Love, Give Life: Greeting Cards that Feed Children in Need</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/15/give-light-give-love/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Give Love, Give Life: Greeting Cards that Feed Children in Need" /><published>2016-11-15T18:09:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-15T18:09:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/15/give-light-give-love</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/15/give-light-give-love/">&lt;p&gt;Meet LoveLight Paper! Focused on a mission to give love and give life, they make cards and products that empower others to love their friends and family well and make an impact on children around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founder + designer Chelcea Cummings tells the story of Love Light Paper, and the bigger purpose behind their cards. 
&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ve always loved giving gifts and spending way, WAY too much time in greeting card sections, trying to pick out the ‘exact perfect card’ for whomever I was buying for. More often than not, I would find myself thinking, “if only I could find a card that had ‘this’ on it,” or “if it only said ‘that’ instead.” LoveLight Paper was born out of of this… my desire to make gift-giving personal and meaningful, rather than just ritual… to Give Love. I started designing cards with specific people in mind, so it could be the perfect card for that specific person. But I wanted these cards to go even beyond that… to Give Life… to sustain life beyond a simple material gift given. I sought out local non-profits that would help fulfill this desire, and found Kids Around The World’s One Meal mission. Through their program, a portion of the proceeds from every item purchase goes to providing a meal to a child in need. It’s a one-for-one style program, but some products give even more than one meal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through their stationary, LoveLight Paper is bridging the gap for every day consumers to be a part of something bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chelcea explains that, “Within cards and gifts, people communicate some of their deepest and most meaningful messages to one another… things that otherwise go unsaid on a daily basis. Most of our cards are left blank inside intentionally - so that you as the gift-giver or note-writer can be the one to make it meaningful… to deepen your relationships by loving one another. And as you give that card to someone, how special is it to know that you also just provided a meal for a someone else, somewhere else around the world! It’s a gift that keeps on giving.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With running a social enterprise comes an immense amount of reward, but also its fair share of challenges and defeats. Chelcea + her husband, co-founders on a mission together, are fueled knowing that their simple products are able to literally give life and nourishment to children around the world. As consumers are giving these cards to friends and family for celebrations, milestones, and encouragement, an even more basic level of need is being met. Each product bought represents another life being sustained and nourished. It’s a gift that keeps on giving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one of our featured brands this season at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/spread-joy/&quot;&gt;Spread Joy Market&lt;/a&gt;, we invite you to take part in the bigger impact that this company is having! LoveLight Paper wants to provide you with ways to shine light and spread love to others who share our deepest needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of spreading joy and gift-giving this holiday season, LoveLight Paper Co. is giving away packets of Christmas gift tags at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/spread-joy/&quot;&gt;Spread Joy Market&lt;/a&gt; for anyone that follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/lovelightpaper/&quot;&gt;@lovelightpaper&lt;/a&gt;. Join us at WayfareHQ from 11-4 on December 3rd to shop goods that give back and spread joy, and head &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/spread-joy/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to enter our doorprize giveaway!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="stationary" /><category term="social enterprise" /><summary type="html">Meet LoveLight Paper! Focused on a mission to give love and give life, they make cards and products that empower others to love their friends and family well and make an impact on children around the world.

Founder + designer Chelcea Cummings tells the story of Love Light Paper, and the bigger purpose behind their cards.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/c8e1079fb76d-LoveLight_WEB1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">On Becoming Mom: Sally Kim’s Journey Toward Adoption</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/11/on-becoming-mom-sally-kims-journey-toward-adoption/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Becoming Mom: Sally Kim's Journey Toward Adoption" /><published>2016-11-11T09:38:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-11T09:38:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/11/on-becoming-mom-sally-kims-journey-toward-adoption</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/11/on-becoming-mom-sally-kims-journey-toward-adoption/">&lt;p&gt;When I was engaged, I once had a woman tell me that I would never understand what being a mom meant until I birthed my own child. That I would never understand the true depths of the heart of a mother, the very heartbeat of motherhood, until my body carried, delivered, and nursed a baby of my very flesh-made in love and intention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know how to respond. I had just lost two precious children as a foster mom. They were my biological half brothers and my foster sons at the same time, and they were reunified with our birth mom, a devastating decision by the Orange County Juvenile Courts, for me and for them. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were mine to love for two years. I bottle weaned, potty trained, and endured the storm of tantrums for one. I laid on the ground soiled with the tears of meltdowns and helped with math and reading, and sat in parent teacher conferences with another. My body was exhausted all the time. The bags under my eyes felt beyond just an expression of tiredness-I felt them physically weighing me down. My body did not deliver these boys, but my body felt motherhood deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After losing them, my body turned more exhausted, more tired; my mind turned over the events daily, and my bed became a place where I imagined what their new life looked like without our stability and love. I’m not anti-second chances, but I am for the child, not the birth parent, first. Unfortunately, this circumstance favored only the mom who still drank, still hit, still screamed, still left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the midst of our loss, my husband and I found out we were expecting our first. I carried our daughter for nine months and ate all my greens and had the experience of birthing her and nursing her and experiencing the helpless neediness of a newborn babe. She’s forever my girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, the birthing, the nursing, and the physical act of carrying her in my womb didn’t replace the loss of the two I carried in my heart. No; if anything, it made the loss all the deeper for those nine months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward some time-we have an eleven month old, are expecting baby number two, and receive an unexpected, but oh-so-hoped-for phone call from Child Protective Services-the situation worsened and it’s time to bring our boys home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two years of not seeing and not hearing from them; not knowing who was tucking them in, or if they even had a bed to be tucked into. Two years of not knowing who was reading them stories or crying with them when life felt too heavy for such a little heart…not being able to comfort or scare away the monsters (both real and imaginary)-they were coming home, maybe this time for good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And something interesting has haunted (for lack of a better word) my mind these last six months of having our boys home. We now have a house of seven, three adopted, two birthed, one still nursing, one enjoying her new found favorite word, “no…” and there has never been a moment where I look at one child as more “mine” than the other. My sons are not less ours because we didn’t birth them. They have a background we must fight to understand, yes-But our hearts do not lack a deep love for them because they were not brought home from the hospital with us. Our daughters are not more ours because we experienced the 30 hours in the hospital of laboring and waiting and yearning for them. Yes, that’s an experience to treasure and remember-but so is the anticipation we experienced on our drive to Orangewood to pickup our sons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are different chapters of the same book; different layers of the same love. One does not make me more of a mother than the other. Each child has initiated me into this role of mommy-hood-releasing in me the fire to fight for whatever is needed for one the power to love at any cost for all, and the soft whisper of nurturing that is birthed with becoming Mom-no matter how the title was given.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sally Kim</name></author><category term="adoption" /><category term="motherhood" /><category term="family" /><category term="children" /><category term="birth" /><category term="foster-care" /><summary type="html">When I was engaged, I once had a woman tell me that I would never understand what being a mom meant until I birthed my own child. That I would never understand the true depths of the heart of a mother, the very heartbeat of motherhood, until my body carried, delivered, and nursed a baby of my very flesh-made in love and intention.

I didn’t know how to respond. I had just lost two precious children as a foster mom. They were my biological half brothers and my foster sons at the same time, and they were reunified with our birth mom, a devastating decision by the Orange County Juvenile Courts, for me and for them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/on-becoming-mom.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Journey Toward Impact</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/08/a-journey-toward-impact/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Journey Toward Impact" /><published>2016-11-08T22:53:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-08T22:53:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/08/a-journey-toward-impact</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/08/a-journey-toward-impact/">&lt;p&gt;“My story has been one marked by journey. Journey through a sea of unknowns, intricate passions, and deep questions. I’ve always been fascinated by people, and I’ve always loved business. Since I was little, I’ve always sought to get understanding at the root, and to be apart of people’s journeys.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within minutes of my conversation with Kalee, I recognize an immense amount of experience, depth, and passion. After graduating from Southern Methodist University as a communications and PR major, Kalee dove right into a career in marketing at a sports entertainment firm. With clients like Puma, ATNT, and other big name companies, Kalee was balancing a lot of responsibility, traveling constantly, and often working 60-80 hour weeks. 
“When you’re working that much and you’re traveling that much, it can also be really lonely and isolating. So I came to this place… if I’m going to be working this much, I should at least be doing something I really care about.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeking more meaning and purpose in her work meant living through a nine month journey of asking hard questions to find out what her best contribution to the world could be.&lt;br /&gt;
“What are my skills? What are my gifts? What do I like? I didn’t even know, to be honest, and it was really disorienting.” 
Through asking hard questions, allowing people to speak into her life, and a pivotal conversation with her mom, Kalee came to realize she wanted to be a therapist. She didn’t even know what a marriage and family therapist was at the time, but Kalee knew she had experienced a lot of healing in her life, so she wanted to be able to offer that to people.What Kalee was stepping into didn’t make sense at first, and she didn’t have a complete picture of what she was walking into, but isn’t that where the adventure is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After completing her program and powering through the grind of getting her hours, Kalee launched her own private practice in January of this year. “What I say I will never do, tends to be what I do. This whole journey has been one of open hands, and I’ve really grown. In getting to be in private practice, in in-patient psych, in trauma work, and in getting to see how people’s stories play out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After launching her practice, Kalee knew there was still more - something different, something bigger she needed to step into. Kalee asked, “What are the parts of me that I want to play in? I have this kingdom to play in, where do I say ‘yes’ and where do I say ‘no way?’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this whole season, Kalee had always been involved at Wayfare on different levels. “I realized I love business strategy, it excites me. But I also love leaders. I understand the nuances and complexities of being a leader. Whether you’re the CEO for a for-profit, whether you’re the executive director of a non-profit, or you’re leading a church… whatever it is, there are a lot of things that go with that. It can be a very isolating place, and it’s really  hard to live into the fullness of who you are because of the expectation, because of the pressure, because of the burdens. You can’t be fully known, because of the expectations at play.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And out of Kalee’s heart, her background, and her first hand experience in leadership, Wayfare’s Impact Program was born. She began asking the question, “What does it look like to create a space for leaders to be fully human and flourish for themselves, but then also for their relationships and their organizations to flourish?”  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Kalee came to Jeff Tanner, co-founder of Wayfare, with this vision, and it catalyzed. She entered Launch, one of Wayfare’s startup programs, and began a 15 week journey to grow the Impact Program from an idea to an organization, to help leaders sustain impact. Kalee’s heart bleeds with the passion to change the culture of work by providing leaders with a space to live in the fullness of who they are and lead their organizations out of that place - instead of a place of isolation, burnout, exhaustion, and failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One thing we believe is that a lonely leader won’t sustain impact. If you’re living detached from who you are, then you’re not going to be able to continue leading and impacting well. Your impact may actually become destructive, and you will start to implode. That may be a slow deterioration, or it may be an accelerated deterioration. With that, you also start to see the breakdown in family, the breakdown in an organization, as well as personal breakdown.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By providing practical and integrated support, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wayfare.io/startups/&quot;&gt;Impact&lt;/a&gt; provides a space for leaders to lead sustainably. Leaders who are apart of the Impact program are placed in locationally based cohorts to meet once a month. Groups are led by a business guide and an integration guide, and participants will engage in discussion on organizational victories, unique challenges, and questions so that they begin to have a bigger picture of what they’re operating out of. The experience is very collaborative, organic, and it’s a very in-process format. Through facilitated conversation, shared meals, and guided self-reflection, the Impact Program is a tool for leaders to be able to invest intentionally in their lives and in their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kalee’s mission is that as leaders begin to live into the fullness of who there are, they begin to work in meaning and interact with one another in a way that starts to define the new vocabulary that they’re bringing into their own organization. As they model this in their leadership, their employees will be empowered and start to ask questions and realize that who they are is so incredibly intertwined with the way they work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Kalee prepares to launch the Impact Program this Thursday at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/wayfare-labs-pitch-night/&quot;&gt;Wayfare’s Pitch Night&lt;/a&gt;, she invites people into her vision - to take a step toward sustainable impact for themselves, or encouraging a leader they know to step into it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="life" /><category term="startups" /><category term="impact" /><summary type="html">“My story has been one marked by journey. Journey through a sea of unknowns, intricate passions, and deep questions. I’ve always been fascinated by people, and I’ve always loved business. Since I was little, I’ve always sought to get understanding at the root, and to be apart of people’s journeys.”

Within minutes of my conversation with Kalee, I recognize an immense amount of experience, depth, and passion. After graduating from Southern Methodist University as a communications and PR major, Kalee dove right into a career in marketing at a sports entertainment firm. With clients like Puma, ATNT, and other big name companies, Kalee was balancing a lot of responsibility, traveling constantly, and often working 60-80 hour weeks. 
“When you’re working that much and you’re traveling that much, it can also be really lonely and isolating. So I came to this place… if I’m going to be working this much, I should at least be doing something I really care about.”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/a-journey-toward-impact.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">That Marriages Would Thrive: From Crashing to Connecting</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/04/that-marriages-would-thrive-from-crashing-to-connecting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="That Marriages Would Thrive: From Crashing to Connecting" /><published>2016-11-04T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-04T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/04/that-marriages-would-thrive-from-crashing-to-connecting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/04/that-marriages-would-thrive-from-crashing-to-connecting/">&lt;p&gt;What do you think of when the word marriage comes up? Long flowing white dress? Small house in the suburbs? Two individuals who are devoted to spending the rest of their lives together? &lt;!-- more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Casey and Meygan met each other in college, it was love at first sight. Young and in love, they decided to get married just two years later. The young couple went into their new stage of life full of wonder and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While marriage is a beautiful union, it is not at all what the movies depict it to be. Between both sets of parents, there were 12 marriages. They knew firsthand the troubles, the pain, and the brokenness of marriage. Refusing to let those failed marriages affect their future, Casey and Meygan dove into their marriage headfirst to prove to themselves that marriage can work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That idealized view came crashing down soon enough as their lives became plagued with arguments after arguments. Wasn’t marriage the answer to happiness? Why was it suddenly so difficult to maintain happiness after they said “I do”? They vowed that divorce was not an option, but things seemed so bleak and the first three years of the marriage progressively became worse and worse. They were missing connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is not where their story ends. Casey and Meygan knew it was time for a change. But what would help rekindle their marriage? They surrounded themselves with mentors that guided them through this difficult season. They sought to improve and work on themselves before finding fault in the other. They read any book they could get their hands on and attended a marriage boot camp! In many ways, they started dating each other again, discovering what made the other person tick, learning how to communicate better, taking up hobbies together, to back when they were two wide eyed college lovers. They were committed to connecting again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through commitment and connecting, they learned that great marriages don’t just happen by accident. It takes a lot of work, intentionality 365 days a year; thus Marriage365 was born! Casey and Meygan are continually striving to help keep marriages thriving to help out similarly struggling couples, whether that’s through their monthly podcast, online courses, or even being coaches and mentors. They want to see marriages last a lifetime and be a part of the solution. Too often marriage counseling hovers on two extremes; focusing on only family and not the underlying problems or too individualistic, often resulting in divorce. &lt;a href=&quot;http://marriage365.org&quot;&gt;Marriage365&lt;/a&gt; uniquely places itself in the middle, getting down to the raw issues while focusing and family and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their advice for struggling couples? “Many married couples do not want to spend time or money on their marriage until it’s too late. They don’t see the value of regular maintenance with their relationship. The biggest advice we would give is that money, careers, your home, your car all can come and go but your relationships with others is where you’ll find true happiness and contentment. It’s truly how you should measure your success in life.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mission is not an easy one; each couple is unique and success looks different for each one.  No one should have to deal with life’s hardships alone and this organization has so many resources that can aid your journey with your spouse. Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://marriage365.org&quot;&gt;marriage365.org&lt;/a&gt; for marriage resources, to refer your friends, and donate. Commit to connecting again with helpful resources, including online courses, private coaching, monthly webcasts, and e-books like one of their most popular: “Naked Dinners”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="common good" /><category term="work" /><summary type="html">What do you think of when the word marriage comes up? Long flowing white dress? Small house in the suburbs? Two individuals who are devoted to spending the rest of their lives together? 

When Casey and Meygan met each other in college, it was love at first sight. Young and in love, they decided to get married just two years later. The young couple went into their new stage of life full of wonder and love.

While marriage is a beautiful union, it is not at all what the movies depict it to be. Between both sets of parents, there were 12 marriages. They knew firsthand the troubles, the pain, and the brokenness of marriage. Refusing to let those failed marriages affect their future, Casey and Meygan dove into their marriage headfirst to prove to themselves that marriage can work.

That idealized view came crashing down soon enough as their lives became plagued with arguments after arguments. Wasn’t marriage the answer to happiness? Why was it suddenly so difficult to maintain happiness after they said “I do”? They vowed that divorce was not an option, but things seemed so bleak and the first three years of the marriage progressively became worse and worse. They were missing connection.

But this is not where their story ends. Casey and Meygan knew it was time for a change. But what would help rekindle their marriage? They surrounded themselves with mentors that guided them through this difficult season. They sought to improve and work on themselves before finding fault in the other. They read any book they could get their hands on and attended a marriage boot camp! In many ways, they started dating each other again, discovering what made the other person tick, learning how to communicate better, taking up hobbies together, to back when they were two wide eyed college lovers. They were committed to connecting again.

Through commitment and connecting, they learned that great marriages don’t just happen by accident. It takes a lot of work, intentionality 365 days a year; thus Marriage365 was born! Casey and Meygan are continually striving to help keep marriages thriving to help out similarly struggling couples, whether that’s through their monthly podcast, online courses, or even being coaches and mentors. They want to see marriages last a lifetime and be a part of the solution. Too often marriage counseling hovers on two extremes; focusing on only family and not the underlying problems or too individualistic, often resulting in divorce. Marriage365 uniquely places itself in the middle, getting down to the raw issues while focusing and family and love.

Their advice for struggling couples? “Many married couples do not want to spend time or money on their marriage until it’s too late. They don’t see the value of regular maintenance with their relationship. The biggest advice we would give is that money, careers, your home, your car all can come and go but your relationships with others is where you’ll find true happiness and contentment. It’s truly how you should measure your success in life.”

This mission is not an easy one; each couple is unique and success looks different for each one.  No one should have to deal with life’s hardships alone and this organization has so many resources that can aid your journey with your spouse. Visit marriage365.org for marriage resources, to refer your friends, and donate. Commit to connecting again with helpful resources, including online courses, private coaching, monthly webcasts, and e-books like one of their most popular: “Naked Dinners”.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/IMG_8700.JPG" /></entry></feed>
