<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://wayfare.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://wayfare.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-11T02:16:29+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/</id><title type="html">Wayfare</title><entry><title type="html">Cultivating a Rhythm of Rest and Work</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/03/29/cultivating-a-rhythm-of-rest-and-work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cultivating a Rhythm of Rest and Work" /><published>2017-03-29T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-29T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/03/29/cultivating-a-rhythm-of-rest-and-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/03/29/cultivating-a-rhythm-of-rest-and-work/">&lt;p&gt;Simplicity, Sabbath, Kon Mari, Minimalism, Balance…being in the creative industry, primarily in the blogging world, I hear these words &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt;. Oh, you too? I’m not surprised. From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Life-Changing-Magic-Tidying-Decluttering-Organizing/dp/1607747308/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1489519329&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=life+changing+magic+of+tidying+up&quot;&gt;Life Changing Magic of Tidying Up&lt;/a&gt; to [Capsule Wardrobes], to &lt;a href=&quot;https://minimalismfilm.com&quot;&gt;Documentaries&lt;/a&gt;…there seems to be an incessant hunt for slowness. Here’s the thing, simplicity and rest are not trends; they are absolute necessities for our survival. 
&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many, many opinions and how-to’s on creating space to rest. You can go through all your clothes and throw away whatever doesn’t spark joy (the Kon Mari Method) and download the latest productivity apps (I’m totally into &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/minimalist-task-reminder-to-do-list/id993066159?mt=8&quot;&gt;MinimaLIST&lt;/a&gt; right now), but unless we get to the root of our busyness and constant waves of rush, we will never fully enter into rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband is a worship pastor, we have two children under two, and three in school. I work &lt;a href=&quot;https://lettersfromamister.com/what-i-do-i-write/&quot;&gt;freelance as a writer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://heritage-mercantile-co.myshopify.com/collections/events&quot;&gt;teaching workshops&lt;/a&gt; and coaching for blogs and non-profits. His job can take him anywhere from one to ten nights a month, and leaves me alone on the weekends, and mine takes consistent creative juice-flow while wiping high chairs and scrubbing cherrios off the floor (ok, you can’t actually scrub cherrios, but you get the concept, right?)…and, in between all of this, we are called to rest. Yes. Called to rest. Let’s eliminate the buzzword balance and replace it with dance. It is absolutely necessary for us to find the dance, the harmony, between work, and rest, because, if we do not learn to rest well, we cannot impact the world with our work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of telling you a list of things you must do, eliminate, or check to create a rhythm of rest in your life, here are some tools I’ve learned as I journey through our chaotic, creative, and beautiful life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop putting pressure on yourself to rest.&lt;/strong&gt; This totally debunks the purpose of it. We get so tangled in knots about making sure we’re resting that we are stressed about getting rest (huh?). Instead, lay out what your ideal routine looks like, then lay out what your survival routine looks like. You will experience both in your life, and it can be a consistent, and, dare I say, beautiful ebb and flow between the two as you navigate through life. Everyday will not be ideal. In fact, most days will not be ideal. Most days, especially those with little people in their care, will be sheer chaos. It’s how we journey through those days that count.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light a Candle.&lt;/strong&gt; I am, however, a huge fan of the Sabbath, and believe it’s something we’re called to do. I believe Sabbath and day offs are two different beasts to tackle; that one is for oil changes and raking leaves, and the other is for pausing and letting life happen around you, while you completely let go of your daily agenda, responsibilities, and worries to worship. How we do this is, come Sunday afternoon, after the busiest time of week for us (remember, pastor family), we light a candle to initiate the end of busy and the beginning of Sabbath. I make the same meal in the crockpot every single Sunday, I clean the house deeply so that come Sunday night and Monday morning I can breathe and be present with my family without noticing the crumbs on the floor, I delete social media from my phone and have our kids turn off their devices and put them in a drawer. We shut down, gathering around the table with a candle resting in the middle, and play the question game, then gather in the living room for board games or reading, or just being quiet, but present, together.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create quiet hours.&lt;/strong&gt; One thing we love to do, and don’t do nearly enough, are quiet hours. I have carried this false belief for years that I must be able to do anything, everything, always. No matter how crazy the kids are, or how insane my husband’s ministry is, or how close my work deadlines are, I thought I needed to roll with it to show how strong I am. The reality is, rest reveals strength. I had to come to terms with the fact that I need set, sacred spaces of total silence, or I will lose my (insert appropriate emoji here). We decided to implement quiet hours with our kids after realizing (one) we hate screens and (two) kids hate life without screens. We believe in the power of boredom, and that creativity can spring from giving ourselves, and our loved ones, spaces without forced stimulation. So, in our ideal schedule, we have an hour a day of no screens and of total quiet. Sometimes we’ll have some easy music on, and this usually takes place during the toddler’s naptime. Each person is responsible for finding their own silent activity, whether it’s making paper airplanes, reading a book, scrolling through a blog (for me! It’s a rule bend because it’s an important way I experience rest), making a slow, pour over coffee. This is not family play time, this is not time to engage, but rather to step back so we can come together and be fully, fully present with each other when we do choose to reconnect. Our kids have come to love it so much that if we don’t have it for a few days, they actually start to ask for it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is absolutely necessary for us to find the dance, the harmony, between work, and rest, because, if we do not learn to rest well, we cannot impact the world with our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, there is no simple formula or perfect way to create rhythms of rest in our lives. There are tools and opinions that can be helpful, but don’t bombard yourself with research in a hunt for the perfect experience. The secret, my secret, is to accept the season of life you are in at the present, and embrace what the dance between work and rest looks like for you today. Recognize your ideal rhythm, and implement a variation of that into your current season. By implementing sacred space to rest, your work will be more impactful and life-giving for not only yourself, but the world you are serving.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sally Kim</name></author><category term="rest" /><category term="minimalism" /><summary type="html">Simplicity, Sabbath, Kon Mari, Minimalism, Balance…being in the creative industry, primarily in the blogging world, I hear these words a lot. Oh, you too? I’m not surprised. From the Life Changing Magic of Tidying Up to [Capsule Wardrobes], to Documentaries…there seems to be an incessant hunt for slowness. Here’s the thing, simplicity and rest are not trends; they are absolute necessities for our survival.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/ValerieDenisePhotos(38of64).jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wearing Many Hats: The Reality of Work and Business</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/03/23/wearing-many-hats-the-reality-of-work-and-business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wearing Many Hats: The Reality of Work and Business" /><published>2017-03-23T22:05:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-23T22:05:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/03/23/wearing-many-hats-the-reality-of-work-and-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/03/23/wearing-many-hats-the-reality-of-work-and-business/">&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.strengthsfinder.com/home.aspx&quot;&gt;Strengths Finder 2.0&lt;/a&gt; (of which I am a huge fan), my top strength is &lt;strong&gt;Achiever&lt;/strong&gt;. So when a day goes by where I haven’t achieved all of the things that I set out to do in a day, I have a hard time feeling like I have accomplished anything at all. This tends to be a problem for me because as the cofounder of a small, but growing organization, I know what it is like to have an entire day go by and to be left wondering where all of my time went! At the end of the day, even if I’ve been productive and I’ve clearly made progress in several small areas, if I spent very little time executing on my primary objectives it can feel defeating.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the things I’ve had to do as I’ve started and run various companies are: run payroll, file DBAs, register domain names, pay bills, build websites, create financial projections, open bank accounts, pull together tax information, communicate with lawyers, act as tech support, communicate with investors, mop up spills, schedule meetings, book travel plans, manage inventory, develop content, ideate on revenue streams, speak at events, pitch investors, order soap dispensers, plunge toilets, install thermostats, run sound, and build furniture. The list could go on, but you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Obviously the specific tasks you have to juggle vary depending on the nature of your business or organization and your role. But the reality is, you wear many hats. &lt;strong&gt;It it the nature of running a business. It is the nature of freelance work. It is the nature of starting something new. And it can be overwhelming.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this to say, I’m sure many of you can resonate with attempting to juggle the many things that go into running the various aspects of your business. Some you love, some you don’t. But you do them all, because they’re necessary for you to do… at least at first. We tell founders in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/startups/&quot;&gt;Launch program&lt;/a&gt; that whether you plan to stay small or grow, &lt;strong&gt;having your hand in everything at the beginning is an essential part of the process for the long run&lt;/strong&gt;. After having done many of the things, as time has gone on I’ve been able to better navigate exactly what to do myself, what to hire out, and who to hire to do some of these things. But having done many of them at first, helped me know who to hire for specific roles. It’s also helped me understand which methods and tools I use to help me manage what I need to get done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love learning about new methods and user-friendly web-based tools that can can help me manage all of the different categories of tasks that I find myself completing. However, researching the best methods and tools &lt;strong&gt;just takes more time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I’m thrilled to share this free downloadable guide called &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.activehosted.com/f/18&quot;&gt;16 Apps &amp;amp; Strategies for Streamlining Your Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that was written by one of our coworking members, &lt;a href=&quot;http://setterstudios.com&quot;&gt;Brandon Setter&lt;/a&gt;, filmmaker and unofficial king of efficiency. These are his current tried-and-true favorites. The descriptions and research have been done for you so you can just focus on doing your best work. But first &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.activehosted.com/f/18&quot;&gt;sign up to get the guide emailed to you&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Arbini</name></author><category term="business" /><category term="freelance" /><category term="small business" /><category term="owner" /><category term="founder" /><category term="achiever" /><category term="tasks" /><category term="roles" /><category term="hiring" /><category term="apps" /><category term="efficiency" /><category term="automation" /><category term="tools" /><summary type="html">According to the Strengths Finder 2.0 (of which I am a huge fan), my top strength is Achiever. So when a day goes by where I haven’t achieved all of the things that I set out to do in a day, I have a hard time feeling like I have accomplished anything at all. This tends to be a problem for me because as the cofounder of a small, but growing organization, I know what it is like to have an entire day go by and to be left wondering where all of my time went! At the end of the day, even if I’ve been productive and I’ve clearly made progress in several small areas, if I spent very little time executing on my primary objectives it can feel defeating.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/16-apps-and-strategies-for-streamlining-your-work.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Voice of Comparison (and How to Stop it)</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/21/the-voice-of-comparison-and-how-to-stop-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Voice of Comparison (and How to Stop it)" /><published>2017-02-21T05:43:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-21T05:43:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/21/the-voice-of-comparison-and-how-to-stop-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/21/the-voice-of-comparison-and-how-to-stop-it/">&lt;p&gt;There’s a not so subtle voice that wells up inside of me more often than I’d like to admit. It’s the ugly voice of comparison. This voice leads to one of two problematic feelings for me: inferiority or superiority. Because the truth about comparison is that it goes both ways. It’s the voice that says what I do doesn’t matter, because someone else is doing something better. It is the voice that minimizes what others do because I don’t see the value in it or understand it. It’s the voice that tells me I don’t have anything to offer because I don’t have everything together. It’s the voice that also says I don’t need to feel too bad about my shortcomings, because at least I’m not quite as much of a mess as so-and-so. But today I’d like to boldly declare, regardless of what it says, &lt;strong&gt;the voice of comparison is a liar.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason we compare ourselves to others, for better or for worse, is ultimately because we want our lives to matter. I know that I am not alone in this and so today I’d like to invite you to join me in listening to a different voice. One that doesn’t guide us to a place of self-deprecation &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; to a place of arrogance, but to a place of considering the unique role that we each have. This voice asks the question, &lt;strong&gt;“What is your best contribution to the world?”&lt;/strong&gt; The answer to this question is always the same answer. For everyone. No matter what. The answer to the question, “What is your best contribution to the world?”, is quite simply, ‘You.” &lt;strong&gt;Your best contribution to the world is you.&lt;/strong&gt; Your abilities, your resources and talents, and your relationships and experiences are uniquely yours. And that matters. You can contribute to the world by doing what you can, with what you have, where you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s no need to compare yourself to somebody else in order to determine how much you matter, because the world needs you to be &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now that we have that cleared up. We face another question.  What happens if I don’t quite know what my abilities, resources or talents are?  What if I can’t make sense of the place I currently am or the relationships I currently have? Here’s the fun part. You go on an adventure of self discovery and try things out. Here are a few ways to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-what-you-like-to-do&quot;&gt;Find What You Like to Do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identify some activities or hobbies that you like. Find others that share those interests and build relationships with them. Here are a few ideas to start: Join a book club, attend a workout class, gather friends for a monthly supper club, sign up for a class or workshop, play basketball with some friends, play the guitar, learn a new craft that you’ve always wanted to try, take your dog to a dog park, take a walk around your neighborhood and talk to your neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find ways you can use what you like to better the life of someone else. Love to cook? Bring someone a meal. Love a certain sport? Gather some friends for an intramural league or volunteer to coach a youth team or help at a sports camp. Enjoy gardening? What neighbor or coworker wouldn’t love a homegrown bouquet or a few fresh tomatoes or oranges? Find something that you like and consider how to bless others or invite others in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;identify-your-strengths&quot;&gt;Identify Your Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/StrengthsFinder-2-0-Tom-Rath/dp/159562015X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1487737297&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=strengths+finder+2.0&quot;&gt;The Strengths Finder 2.0&lt;/a&gt; is a great book and comes with a code that gives you access to a highly comprehensive online assessment tool to help you identify your strengths. The basic premise of this book is that we often can identify our short-comings easily and spend a lot of effort to overcome them.  However, there are parts of us where we naturally excel and most of our effort should go toward developing our strengths. At Wayfare, we use this book in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/startups/&quot;&gt;startup incubator&lt;/a&gt; and have found that it’s worth every penny. (And we don’t get paid a penny to promote this book. We just really love it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;contribute-in-everyday-life&quot;&gt;Contribute in Everyday Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may or may not be living where you want to, working where you want to, or are at the place you thought you’d be at this point in your life. Either way, no matter where you are, you can contribute to the world.  Your neighbors, your friends, your coworkers, your family and the people in your city can benefit from the fact that you are in their lives. My friend recently left a couple of balloons and a nice card with a treat attached for each of her neighbors in their driveways as they got home from work. Another person I know lives in a third-world country, doesn’t have running water, and helps provide medical care to people in her community.  Some other friends of mine love babies and step in to &lt;a href=&quot;http://safe-families.org&quot;&gt;help families in crisis&lt;/a&gt; by temporarily caring for their children. Another friend of mine makes school lunches for her boys. She’s started offering to make lunches for their classmates as well. Moms take her up on it and when asked why she does it she says, “Because I can. And if I’m doing it anyway I might as well make someone else’s life easier by helping them out.” &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facesofsantaana.com&quot;&gt;Someone else I know&lt;/a&gt; befriends people experiencing homelessness, uses his skills as an artist to paint their portraits, sells the paintings, and uses the funds to help his friends in a tangible way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me? Today, I made meals for my family, washed their clothes, and helped my son with math. Obviously I wrote a blog post too. It’s my hope that in my family they know they are loved and in turn, they love others. It’s my hope that in my writing, I can encourage others. I also went to the chiropractor. Because I have to take care of myself too. It isn’t much, but it isn’t &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; much, you know? It’s just me. Because it’s what &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; have to offer.  To my family, to my community, to myself in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We each have our roles. And they each matter. Let’s say ‘no’ to the voice of comparison, and ‘yes’ to contributing to the world in our own unique ways.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="creativity" /><category term="purpose" /><category term="ideas" /><category term="world" /><category term="homeless" /><category term="strengths" /><category term="relationships" /><summary type="html">There’s a not so subtle voice that wells up inside of me more often than I’d like to admit. It’s the ugly voice of comparison. This voice leads to one of two problematic feelings for me: inferiority or superiority. Because the truth about comparison is that it goes both ways. It’s the voice that says what I do doesn’t matter, because someone else is doing something better. It is the voice that minimizes what others do because I don’t see the value in it or understand it. It’s the voice that tells me I don’t have anything to offer because I don’t have everything together. It’s the voice that also says I don’t need to feel too bad about my shortcomings, because at least I’m not quite as much of a mess as so-and-so. But today I’d like to boldly declare, regardless of what it says, the voice of comparison is a liar.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/comparison-blog-resized.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">“But What Do I Doooo?”: The Case for a Strong Mission Statement</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/19/but-what-do-i-doooo-the-case-for-a-strong-mission-statement/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="&quot;But What Do I Doooo?&quot;: The Case for a Strong Mission Statement" /><published>2017-02-19T17:27:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-19T17:27:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/19/but-what-do-i-doooo-the-case-for-a-strong-mission-statement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/19/but-what-do-i-doooo-the-case-for-a-strong-mission-statement/">&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite movies is Disney’s “The Kid”. In the scene where big Russ is trying to explain his job as an image consultant and little Rusty is trying to understand what that means, he looks up and in a childish, drawn out tone says, “But what do I doooo?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This very phrase and in Rusty’s tone went through my head about 1,000 times as we started exploring re-articulating our mission statement. I was newly hired as the Executive Director of Mika Community Development Corporation but had been a part of the organization for 11 of our 12 years. Our work wasn’t changing but we needed to clarify and focus the most core part of our work, our mission.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, Mika’s mission statement read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mika exists to identify and equip leaders from low-income neighborhoods to build communities with VISION (Vision, Interdependent Relationships with God and with each other, Servant Leadership, Impact, Organization, and Networks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was not a bad mission statement. It served us well and directed our work for over a decade. However, besides myself and the previous Executive Director, no one could remember the thing. You’d ask 10 people what Mika did and you’d get 10 different answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to tell you this process of asking, “But what do we dooooo?” was simple and fast. But as with most things that are good, it took time. A lot of time. Just over a year to be exact. This was not a process to be rushed and clarifying the core problem we were addressing was the ONLY way we were going to know if our solutions were actually solving anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be scary, because what if the answer is no? &lt;strong&gt;What if you get really clear on the problem only to find what you’ve been doing isn’t really solving the core problem?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my 12 years of working with and for multiple non-profits, I’ve seen that we’re often afraid of asking the hard questions. It could affect our funding. It could mean stopping or changing long term programs. It could mean saying no to funds that don’t align with our mission. It could mean people choosing not to partner with you anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many of you starting something new, this could also mean that your idea looks different than what you have been thinking about for years. But the freedom of clarity and focus far outweighs the anxieties and frustrations that come from lack of clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mika’s work draws heavily from Bryant Myers’ book “Walking With the Poor” where he presents the idea of relational poverty and its effect on economic poverty. He suggests that “poverty is a result of relationships that do not work, that are not just, that are not for life, that are not harmonious or enjoyable. Poverty is the absence of Shalom in all its meanings.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was made more accessible by the popular “When Helping Hurts” and explores the effects of the breakdown in relationship of our four primary relationships – our relationships with God, with self, with others, and with the rest of creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had been using this language to explain the core problem we were addressing and justify how we work, but hadn’t connected that the way we articulated our mission spoke more to strategy than mission fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leadership Development and Community Building (our core strategies) are wonderful things but they are tools to fulfilling a larger mission. We identified early on in the process that our core mission had to be articulated in relationship terms. If you’ve ever wordsmithed something for so long it makes your brain hurt, you’ll understand how we were feeling after months of not landing on something concrete. I could walk you through all the versions and would be happy to if you contact me directly, but where we finally landed was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mika exists to build whole relationships in Costa Mesa.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be fooled by the simplicity of this statement. There was a lot of time (and tears) that went into the final iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clarity this statement brought to me and to our team was incredible. It created a clear lens to evaluate every single thing we do. We asked: does this program build wholeness in relationship with God, self, or others? For 80% of what we did the answer was a resounding YES! If the answer was no, another set of questions followed. Not fitting into our core mission didn’t automatically mean we needed to stop doing something, but clarified what questions we should be asking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of the hardest decisions I’ve made as Executive Director were closing a community center and changing a 10 year Christmas tradition that had become an institution in our city. I realized that even the most beautiful community development work can become a part of sustaining a need that has changed or may not even exist anymore. Once we became really clear on the problem we were addressing (broken relationships) we had to make sure our solutions (strategies and programs) were completely in line. To sum this up in one short post is oversimplifying a very difficult and timely process, but as one that’s still in it (and will hopefully always be asking the hard questions) I’m here to tell you it’s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I participated in Wayfare’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/startups/idea-weekend/&quot;&gt;Idea Weekend&lt;/a&gt; from a different perspective than most of the people in the room. I wasn’t starting something brand new but had a new idea for our already existing organization. We had done a lot of the above mentioned work and started asking some specific questions regarding funding and sustainability. It was inspiring to be with 14 other people who were vulnerable enough to ask the hard questions and do the hard work of clarifying their problem in order to know what the best solutions were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As was the case with many people in the room, what I started thinking was the problem was only scratching the surface and attending the Idea Weekend helped me to clarify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What seems like a very scary and hard process of questioning is totally worth it in the end when you’re willing to do the work. Well done for diving in.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Keturah Kennedy</name></author><category term="startups" /><category term="startup" /><category term="insight" /><category term="mission" /><category term="statement" /><category term="why" /><category term="mika" /><category term="costa mesa" /><category term="the kid" /><category term="non-profit" /><category term="social enterprise" /><category term="when helping hurts" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="clarity" /><category term="focus" /><category term="sustainability" /><category term="funding" /><summary type="html">One of my favorite movies is Disney’s “The Kid”. In the scene where big Russ is trying to explain his job as an image consultant and little Rusty is trying to understand what that means, he looks up and in a childish, drawn out tone says, “But what do I doooo?” This very phrase and in Rusty’s tone went through my head about 1,000 times as we started exploring re-articulating our mission statement. I was newly hired as the Executive Director of Mika Community Development Corporation but had been a part of the organization for 11 of our 12 years. Our work wasn’t changing but we needed to clarify and focus the most core part of our work, our mission.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/but-what-do-i-do.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Coworking as Team? 3 Reasons Why it’s Good for You, Your Team &amp;amp; Your Organization</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/08/an-office-inside-an-office/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coworking as  Team?  3 Reasons Why it's Good for You, Your Team &amp; Your Organization" /><published>2017-02-08T05:06:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-08T05:06:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/08/an-office-inside-an-office</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/08/an-office-inside-an-office/">&lt;p&gt;You started something! That’s a big deal. Whether you’ve been at it for awhile or you are just starting out, you might find yourself exploring the idea of moving to your own office space. Next step…secure a lease, right? Maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve asked a few of the members that work out Wayfare full time why they have chosen to have their offices and build their team inside of the a shared workspace environment rather than in their own private office space. A few main themes came up: &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/membership/&quot;&gt;The Community&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/membership/faq/&quot;&gt;The Flexibility&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/startups/&quot;&gt;Business Opportunities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-community-for-you-and-your-team&quot;&gt;The Community (for you and your team)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We love having our own personal space, but I also love seeing how my team is part of the greater community of people within Wayfare. The community here is like-minded, which is a huge deal. They care about people and I think it helps my team have a better work experience than we’d have if our team was isolated in our own space without interaction and encouragement from others…It’s more than a workspace, it’s a family.”-Jon F., &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cappital.co&quot;&gt;Cappital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I came from working alone in a windowless office to a place where there is life happening to the fullest. I no longer leave my day exhausted and drained, but with new ideas, new questions, and a new sense of energy to take me into the next day.-Erica N., &lt;a href=&quot;http://redemptionchurch.org&quot;&gt;Redemption Church&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wayfare fosters a unique culture and brings together a big family. This aligns with the philosophy that’s deeply rooted in [our] business.-Han L., &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moraleagency.com&quot;&gt;Morale Agency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wholeheartedly agree! Running your own business or organization is hard and can be draining. It is great to be able to share some of the things that are going on in your work and receive encouragement from others who have walked or are walking the same path. Sometimes all you need is the encouragement to keep going or some insight that you’d likely never come up with on your own. That is where being surrounded by other people outside of your own organization is a huge help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;flexibility-in-team-growth&quot;&gt;Flexibility in Team Growth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When you are starting something new and growing your team it is impossible to know how quickly or how slowly you’ll grow. The month-to-month flexibility and the ability to add employees as we grow is the perfect solution for us. We don’t need to keep moving offices as we add more people. We keep our dedicated office and just add employees who can work out of the main coworking space and the office.-Jon. F., &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cappital.co&quot;&gt;Cappital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have a dedicated office space at Wayfare you are welcome to work in the main workspace as well. This is a great option if you are looking for a change of scenery or to accommodate a growing team.  As you make new hires, you can easily add them on without needing to move offices. At Wayfare you aren’t committed to an office lease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;opportunities-for-collaboration-and-business-growth&quot;&gt;Opportunities for Collaboration and Business Growth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“To put it simply, Neat Coffee would not currently exist without Wayfare. Not only have you provided me with a space in which to test out my dreams, but you have been so supportive and helpful from the second the idea was born. From creating projections for my business, to giving great advice on a weekly basis…you have played an integral role in making Neat Coffee successful.-Ally G., &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neat.coffee&quot;&gt;Neat Coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Having the ability to make connections and interact with people within the greater coworking community provides natural ways to connect and grow our business, gain customers and connections, and explore new ideas. Being a part of this community allows us to get to know other people who can speak into what we are doing and see things from a new perspective because they have an outside point of view that we don’t have.-Jon F., &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cappital.co&quot;&gt;Cappital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have  so many have stories of people within the workspace and the greater advisor network helping each other out with projects, gaining business through connections with fellow members, and receiving insight on how to run their organization more effectively by rubbing shoulders with others. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.typeform.com/to/YW0Nce&quot;&gt;Let us know&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interested in having a private office at Wayfare. We’d love to show you around!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="startups" /><category term="community" /><category term="office" /><summary type="html">You started something! That’s a big deal. Whether you’ve been at it for awhile or you are just starting out, you might find yourself exploring the idea of moving to your own office space. Next step…secure a lease, right? Maybe not. We’ve asked a few of the members that work out Wayfare full time why they have chosen to have their offices and build their team inside of the a shared workspace environment rather than in their own private office space. A few main themes came up: The Community, The Flexibility, and Business Opportunities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/coworking-as-a-team.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2 Phrases That Might Just Change Your Life (and the Lives of Others)</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/07/2-phrases-that-might-just-change-your-life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2 Phrases That Might Just Change Your Life (and the Lives of Others)" /><published>2017-02-07T01:37:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-07T01:37:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/07/2-phrases-that-might-just-change-your-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/07/2-phrases-that-might-just-change-your-life/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard it said that if there is a choice to be right or be kind, choose kindness. I love this sentiment and often encourage my kids (and myself for that matter) to think in this way. But in reality, don’t both matter? Truth without kindness tends to fall on deaf ears, and kindness without truth really isn’t kind, its flattery. True kindness comes from a desire for the best possible outcome for everyone involved. This usually entails working together. Not just tolerating someone who is occupying space in close proximity to you, but actually doing work in cooperation with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From people on your team at work, to people you rub shoulders with in a shared workspace (yay coworking!), to working with and advocating on behalf of others, working together is important. As we identify needs and consider how to help, it often means working with people who are different than us. This could mean working with the person or people responsible for the problem you are trying to solve. It could mean joining someone very different than you who feels called to the same work. It could mean working to keep relationships in tact even when we disagree on a lot. We all encounter moments when differences come to the surface and we need to work together to make progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If working together is important, how do we accomplish the important work? These two phrases may help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-why-not-both&quot;&gt;1. “Why Not Both?”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We make thousands of tiny decisions every day and most of the time we don’t even realize it. In these tiny instances “either/or” decision making is fairly inconsequential. Deciding on things like jeans or shorts, pizza or mac and cheese, and the freeway or surface streets can usually be solved easily and without much consequence. (Although as a side note: I do think mac and cheese pizza is pretty amazing. Don’t knock it until you try it. Unless you are lactose intolerant. Then definitely don’t try it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when it comes to the more significant things in life where a person’s personal, religious, or moral convictions come to the surface, that is where the tensions typically arise. So when these situations present themselves, turning off the autopilot of the “either/or” thinking we use thousands of times every day can be beneficial as we work together. These delicate situations entail more thoughtful work. This is where “both/and” thinking comes in handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core “both/and” thinking and decision making starts with listening to the other perspective and working together to see if there is a way to accomplish a positive outcome for each person, rather than choosing either one or the other. This often results in the emergence of a never before considered third way (I repeat: MAC AND CHEESE PIZZA!!!). It is fascinating to see what comes of asking the question, “Why Not Both?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, can a person BOTH hold their personal convictions strongly, AND respect the right of another to hold their own (differing) personal convictions just as strongly no matter how much they disagree? Absolutely. And in this very act…they can each find something on which they agree which a great place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently heard an eyewitness report of a protest happening at LAX regarding the executive order banning travel and immigration that the President recently made. The protestors were in the way of traffic. The police came and told the protestors that if they remained in the street, they would get arrested. Shortly thereafter, it was reported that an agreement was struck between the police and the protestors. It was decided that the protestors could alternate standing in the street for a specified amount of time thus allowing their protest to remain a protest and not just a demonstration. Then they would retreat to the sidewalk for a specified amount of time before taking the protest back to the street and so on. The police didn’t need to make mass arrests and the protestors were still able to protest in an effective way. While I wasn’t there and can’t speak first-hand to the validity of this report, this struck me as an example of “both/and” thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-help-me-understand&quot;&gt;2. “Help Me Understand”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a year ago I was feeling particularly frustrated as I found myself navigating a difficult friendship. I was seeking advice from a couple of friends and in our conversation I exclaimed, “It is just so messy!” To which they both responded. “When you’re interacting with real people, in real life, that’s exactly what it is…messy.”  And in their kindness they didn’t leave me hanging, but encouraged me to use these three words – “Help Me Understand”. I now use those three words at least weekly in a variety of circumstances. Some examples: “Help me understand your thought process.” “Help me understand how you reached this conclusion.” “Help me understand what your experience is like in this.” “Help me understand what benefits you see in this.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we aspire to work together to advance good in the world, these two simple phrases might make a world of difference.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="life" /><category term="common-good" /><summary type="html">I’ve heard it said that if there is a choice to be right or be kind, choose kindness. I love this sentiment and often encourage my kids (and myself for that matter) to think in this way. But in reality, don’t both matter? Truth without kindness tends to fall on deaf ears, and kindness without truth really isn’t kind, its flattery. True kindness comes from a desire for the best possible outcome for everyone involved. This usually entails working together. Not just tolerating someone who is occupying space in close proximity to you, but actually doing work in cooperation with one another. From people on your team at work, to people you rub shoulders with in a shared workspace (yay coworking!), to working with and advocating on behalf of others, working together is important. As we identify needs and consider how to help, it often means working with people who are different than us. This could mean working with the person or people responsible for the problem you are trying to solve. It could mean joining someone very different than you who feels called to the same work. It could mean working to keep relationships in tact even when we disagree on a lot. We all encounter moments when differences come to the surface and we need to work together to make progress. If working together is important, how do we accomplish the important work? These two phrases may help.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/2PhrasesBlog.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What’s Your Language?</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/20/whats-your-language/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What's Your Language?" /><published>2017-01-20T08:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-20T08:30:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/20/whats-your-language</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/20/whats-your-language/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today we’re hearing from Anna Kennedy from &lt;a href=&quot;mikacdc.org&quot;&gt;Mika CDC&lt;/a&gt; whose mission is to build whole relationships in Costa Mesa.  One way they’re doing this is through Language Learning Nights hosted by Wayfare Costa Mesa.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re anything like me, you talk about practicing your Spanish more than you actually find time to do it. For many people, it’s been since high school, which, is getting further and further away. Our lives are busy and sometimes it’s hard to figure out a time to practice a foreign language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same applies for many of our native Spanish speaking neighbors here in Costa Mesa. Because of this, &lt;a href=&quot;http://mikacdc.org&quot;&gt;Mika&lt;/a&gt; recently launched Language Learning Night.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
A night once a month where native English and Spanish speakers are both teacher and learner all in the same evening.  You get to feel awkward and unsure for half the evening and confident and helpful for the other half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mikacdc.org&quot;&gt;Mika’s&lt;/a&gt; mission is to build whole relationships. Part of building relationships is the ability to put ourselves out there and feel unsure. I love the quote by Nelson Mandela that says, “If you talk to a man in a language he understands, that goes to his head. If you talk to him in his own language, that goes to his heart.” It’s our desire to foster an environment during our Language Learning Nights to not only help people gain more practical knowledge, but to also hear from each other’s heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darren, one of the native English participants says this of his experience, “The language exchange is a beautiful opportunity to get to know our neighbors in a setting where we all feel a little vulnerable. Speaking a foreign language to native speakers can be nerve-racking, but as we go back and forth between English and Spanish, I’m reminded that we all are learning and practicing. I was worried about feeling dumb when I’m trying to speak Spanish, but everyone has been super patient and encouraging!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a native Spanish speaker, Loly has said this: “My experience at the Language Learning Night was amazing. This class is very important for me, not only because I have to learn English, but because is part of my daily lifestyle. Due to the way we practice a foreign language, it helps build my confidence with communicating with more people around me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all want to hear and be heard; to learn and share what we’ve learned. Are you ready to share your language and make some new friends? This is a free night of learning and relationship building hosted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io&quot;&gt;Wayfare Costa Mesa&lt;/a&gt;. Contact me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:anna@mikacdc.org&quot;&gt;anna@mikacdc.org&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interested in more details!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Anna Kennedy</name></author><category term="mika" /><category term="relationships" /><category term="community" /><summary type="html">Today we’re hearing from Anna Kennedy from Mika CDC whose mission is to build whole relationships in Costa Mesa. One way they’re doing this is through Language Learning Nights hosted by Wayfare Costa Mesa. If you’re anything like me, you talk about practicing your Spanish more than you actually find time to do it. For many people, it’s been since high school, which, is getting further and further away. Our lives are busy and sometimes it’s hard to figure out a time to practice a foreign language. The same applies for many of our native Spanish speaking neighbors here in Costa Mesa. Because of this, Mika recently launched Language Learning Night.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/mika-language-learning.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Say Goodbye to “Wayfare”</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/18/say-goodbye-to-wayfare/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Say Goodbye to &quot;Wayfare&quot;" /><published>2017-01-18T21:12:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-18T21:12:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/18/say-goodbye-to-wayfare</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/18/say-goodbye-to-wayfare/">&lt;p&gt;Hey there,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a new year and we have big news. We started dreaming about what Wayfare would become over three years ago. It was our vision to create a workspace and support for organizations that would birth movements for the common good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were forming the organization, we decided on the name Wayfare because it captured the heart behind our vision. The word Wayfare has a double meaning. It means the act of journeying. It also means provisions for the journey. This word clearly encompassed the community we envisioned—a community of creators, doers, and adventurers aspiring to pursue the common good and support each other in the journey.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
Around the same time that we decided to name our company Wayfare, another company with a different mission (they sell furniture) called Wayfair was on the rise. They sell furniture at “way fair” prices and made news as they received hundreds of millions in capital investment that year. As we became aware of their company, we explored the potential of any conflict associated with our names sounding the same. We didn’t see any conflict, and our lawyers agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently however, their lawyers did not. We appreciate great furniture as much as anyone, and we even have a few items procured through our very own orders from wayfair.com itself. However, we are faced with a decision. We must decide how much time, energy, and money we want to spend in legal fees (the quick answer is zero…nobody wants to pay legal fees) to continue down the path of fighting to keep our name. We’ve chosen a different path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our startup programs, we advise organizations to quickly assess environmental changes and the big picture when experiencing challenges – to make sense of the situation and rapidly adjust. So we’ve taken our own advice and have decided to change our name while staying true to who we are…who you are. We’re going to redirect our energy and steward our resources in a positive direction to rename this community, and we want you, the community, included in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the name Wayfare is a great representation of our mission and this community, when we look at the big picture, we are struck with the amazing people that form this community, the wonderful hearts you have, and world-changing work you are doing. For that reason, we are thrilled to invite you into the process of renaming Wayfare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are humbled and full of gratitude that the community of three who decided on the name is now a community of over 200 members who work out of the workspaces or are currently participating in the startup programs. There are thousands of others who serve as advisors, have attended events, or have joined us on social media. You’ve been a part of this journey so far, and we want to continue this adventure along with you. YOU are Wayfare and we’re happy to release the name, because the community and the journey we are all on together matter more. And that is where we want to continue to invest the resources we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, let’s go on another adventure together.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re having a contest to come up with a new name (yes, there are prizes) and we want &lt;strong&gt;ALL&lt;/strong&gt; the ideas. We invite you to submit a name (or 20) for our rebranding, and the guidelines are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The name captures our goals of having spaces where people can daily be supported in meaningful work (workspaces) AND simultaneously captures the mission of guiding founders and startups of missional enterprises and social good organizations (startup programs).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The name communicates the concept of adventure, journeying, support, and encouragement in pursuit of the common good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bonus points if the .com of the name is available or there’s an instagram/twitter handle available (but we can work around this, so if you have the perfect name submit it anyway)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extra bonus points if you submit a catchy hashtag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;action&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.typeform.com/to/DFBRl1&quot;&gt;Submit your ideas and an explanation&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submit as many ideas as you want as many times as you want.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anyone can participate (you don’t need to be a member to share your ideas)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All submissions must be received by January 31st at 10 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prize&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One winner will receive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A $500 credit to be used toward our &lt;a href=&quot;/startups&quot;&gt;Startup Programs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/workspaces&quot;&gt;Workspaces&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/workspaces&quot;&gt;Meeting Rooms&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;/events&quot;&gt;Event Fees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$50 gift certificate to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sidecardoughnuts.com&quot;&gt;Sidecar Doughnuts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$20 gift card to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neat.coffee&quot;&gt;Neat Coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swag bag of goods with new branding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our eternal gratitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So get your thinking caps on and let’s embark on the next phase of this journey together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With extreme gratitude and excitement for the world’s best future,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brandon Arbini &amp;amp; Jeff Tanner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Co-founders of the organization soon to be formerly known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io&quot;&gt;Wayfare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Arbini</name></author><category term="creativity" /><category term="rebrand" /><category term="community" /><category term="collaborate" /><category term="contest" /><summary type="html">Hey there, It’s a new year and we have big news. We started dreaming about what Wayfare would become over three years ago. It was our vision to create a workspace and support for organizations that would birth movements for the common good. As we were forming the organization, we decided on the name Wayfare because it captured the heart behind our vision. The word Wayfare has a double meaning. It means the act of journeying. It also means provisions for the journey. This word clearly encompassed the community we envisioned—a community of creators, doers, and adventurers aspiring to pursue the common good and support each other in the journey.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/rebrand-blog-post.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Make What You Wish Existed</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/09/make-what-you-wish-existed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Make What You Wish Existed" /><published>2017-01-09T18:26:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-09T18:26:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/09/make-what-you-wish-existed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/09/make-what-you-wish-existed/">&lt;p&gt;Lots of people are saying 2016 was one of the worst years, and so they are looking at 2017 with hope, excitement and lots of plans to make big changes. I don’t know if 2016 was my worst year, but it was for sure my busiest. During overwhelming times like these, my dad says, “Life can feel like trying to drink out of fire hose. It all just comes at once and you feel like you may drown.” I was drowning this year! This year I was tasked with restarting a church that had experienced a huge decline and I published my first book where I was the primary author. The project included art, video and writing. So it was a crazy year where every other day I thought I was going under. Let alone feeling like I had a personal life. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s this thing about drowning: it only takes one hand to reach for you and pull you to safety. Last year that life-giving hand came in the applause of a three year old named “Willow.” Before I share her story, let me first share how I got to this moment of drowning. It all started with a sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Make what you wish existed.”&lt;/strong&gt; That sign hangs in the coworking space, &lt;a href=&quot;/workspaces/costa-mesa/&quot;&gt;Wayfare&lt;/a&gt;,  that I currently share in Costa Mesa. I am working out of Wayfare for several reasons, but my favorite reason is that I get to be surrounded by people making big changes in the world and as I have been tasked with building a church community that I actually want to go to - these are the people I want to be around. I have been working in this artistic and innovative space with lots of other startup pastors. Sometimes I overhear planning sessions of really creative worship services. As I hear the ideas pour forth, I get overwhelmed with trying to envision what my new church will look like. This feeling gets worse each time I pass the sign “Make what you wish existed”. I find myself doubting my ability to create anything anyone wishes existed. I have always dreamed of creating the church and worship services I wish for, but the excitement of that idea sure seems to fade in the face of daily community, building, financial and other resource issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These challenges show up in many ways. Our building is 100 years old and has no room for classrooms or fellowship other than worship itself, the existing congregation is in varying stages of being on board with anything new, and the surrounding community has great need but is hard to serve. When you add these obstacles on top of trying to work out a stream of income to keep the doors open, it gets difficult to imagine being creative enough to make anything, let alone something you wish existed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week of my rescue was a particularly hard week. That Monday I discovered that some contracts created before my appointment to the church were not working out as hoped – which was making the church’s financial situation, among many other things, much more challenging. Then on the same day, someone tried to break into the building…and a June bug flew in my car window. I am afraid of all bugs, but let’s just say I am never emotionally prepared for the ones that are the size of hummingbirds and fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting in my car about to cry, I began to pray. Then I remembered a tiny incident – a moment of proof that something that I do wish existed is being created…already. Worship as it was at that time was awkward, especially in the music department because, among other things, we had no worship leader. Instead, our accompanist played the hymns while all of us tried to sing along. Our accompanist was very talented, but without a worship leader we often felt like we are just stumbling through the music. Sometimes, in the middle of a service, I just want to stand up and declare: “Just wait! I know this is awkward, but hold tight – something new and great is coming!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other awkward part of this whole “new church in an old church” setting is that is that although the church has a few rooms other than the sanctuary, they are currently full of pipe organ parts. One tiny office is too small to house a class. So when new families show up, we have no classroom space for their children and they sit and worship with their parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two awkward components crashed into each other this week in a life-giving moment that saved me from drowning in my own doubt. It was Willow’s first week at our church. This little darling showed up excited for church in a beautiful dress and shiny shoes. Her parents seemed worried about her chattering mid-worship, but I loved it. During the time of the offering the accompanist played a beautiful piece. When she was done instead of the usual silence that fills that huge sanctuary, Willow was overcome and clapped, exclaiming “Good job!” Overwhelmed by her enthusiasm and the beauty of the song, everyone else joined in the applause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I sat in my car staring at my beautiful hot mess of a church, Willow’s joyous applause came flashing back to me. In that moment, I could see the beauty and joy of who we were becoming. We are an absolute mess, but we are also beautiful and joyful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with that tiny clap, Willow saved me from drowning. So I am pressing on with God, Willow and the rest of my congregation to &lt;strong&gt;“make something both Willow and I wish existed.”&lt;/strong&gt; And I guess it is working because on Christmas Eve there were 80 people huddled together in this church to celebrate. It has been years since the church has seen these numbers. But the best part was, as I scanned the crowd, I saw the most diverse gathering of people I have seen and they are the type of people I want to spend time with. I have actually started to build the very thing I needed. So 2017, look out I am coming for you and together we are going to build something amazing!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah Heath</name></author><category term="creation" /><category term="building" /><category term="church" /><category term="innovation" /><category term="creativity" /><category term="beauty" /><category term="joy" /><category term="busy" /><category term="new year" /><summary type="html">Lots of people are saying 2016 was one of the worst years, and so they are looking at 2017 with hope, excitement and lots of plans to make big changes. I don’t know if 2016 was my worst year, but it was for sure my busiest. During overwhelming times like these, my dad says, “Life can feel like trying to drink out of fire hose. It all just comes at once and you feel like you may drown.” I was drowning this year! This year I was tasked with restarting a church that had experienced a huge decline and I published my first book where I was the primary author. The project included art, video and writing. So it was a crazy year where every other day I thought I was going under. Let alone feeling like I had a personal life.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/make.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Starting 2017 With Your Legacy in Mind</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/02/starting-with-the-end-in-mind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting 2017 With Your Legacy in Mind" /><published>2017-01-02T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-02T17:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/02/starting-with-the-end-in-mind</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/02/starting-with-the-end-in-mind/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been pondering the concept of legacy a lot lately. Perhaps because I just had my second daughter-and I’m overly intentional about the words that come out of my mouth towards and about them. I want every day, every moment, to be wrapped around intention because, truth is, girls still need to hear that they can and should do the hard and holy things in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s another side to legacy that drives me. My mom. She is not my hero. No, the complete opposite. Her life was an example of everything I never want to be-selfish, addict, abusive, promiscuous…lost. My birth mom raised me to fear the world, fear her hand, fear her words. She made me believe my worth is in my sexuality and I’m only as good as the attention I received from guys. To go to college, to have a life long spouse, to do better for myself, well, this was selfish and wrong and I obviously thought I was better than everyone for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved out when I was sixteen. With a black-eye and a battered heart, I moved in with my now family. Three years later I graduated college. Six years later I met a man that is good, and stable, and strong and thinks I’m lovely and smart and worth loving because, I just am. Nine months later we welcomed our first little girl, and now we are a tribe of seven (we picked up three more kids along the way). My husband has never laid a harmful hand on me or raised his voice-like my birth mom promised the man I was bound to marry would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, growing up with such volatile words and fists constantly being thrown my way, I know the affect of words. Because of that broken record of her voice, I let opportunities and chances pass by out of fear of failure, or, worse, becoming someone just like her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look at my two girls, one just over one and another just three months young, and I see their little personalities and strengths start to bloom-one is strong and fearless, trying to pick up bees (I’m serious) and the other is a softer kind of strong. T, our three month old, is tender and sensitive and doesn’t like to be messed with but my, oh my, does she love to stare at smiling faces. I see them. I see people within them, and I want to nurture that which I see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The legacy my mother left me was one of injure-I was promised failure and abuse and heartache. I get to rewrite the course for my kids. I called a halt to that legacy and yelled out, with my life, No (more accurately, hell no), and started a new route. The legacy I leave for my daughters is one of art and music and you cans because I did. I took leaps and pursued dreams, and did they always succeed? No. But I tried and they will too. They may be babies, but the words I speak to them, the words I speak over them today will follow them through high school, through their twenties and thirties, and through their own journey as a wife, mother, friend, sister. This is the legacy I get to be a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting a new year and all of its resolutions is a good thing. It’s good to have short term goals in mind-I want to go to yoga more regularly, start waking up at 4am (because…babies) to get some alone time, and to date my husband more regularly. I want to land three more clients by the end of each month and write a book proposal and blog for my heart more regularly. These are all really good things and goals to have. But, my biggest goal this year is to keep the end in mind-what is my end goal? To look back in fifty years and know that I left a legacy for those watching to enjoy and learn from.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sally Kim</name></author><category term="goals" /><category term="new year" /><category term="legacy" /><summary type="html">I’ve been pondering the concept of legacy a lot lately. Perhaps because I just had my second daughter-and I’m overly intentional about the words that come out of my mouth towards and about them. I want every day, every moment, to be wrapped around intention because, truth is, girls still need to hear that they can and should do the hard and holy things in the world. There’s another side to legacy that drives me. My mom. She is not my hero. No, the complete opposite. Her life was an example of everything I never want to be-selfish, addict, abusive, promiscuous…lost. My birth mom raised me to fear the world, fear her hand, fear her words. She made me believe my worth is in my sexuality and I’m only as good as the attention I received from guys. To go to college, to have a life long spouse, to do better for myself, well, this was selfish and wrong and I obviously thought I was better than everyone for doing so.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/ojvirvbkwp8-lukas-becker.jpg" /></entry></feed>