<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://wayfare.io/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://wayfare.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://wayfare.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-11-11T17:48:08+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io//</id><title type="html">Wayfare</title><entry><title type="html">On Becoming Mom: Sally Kim’s Journey Toward Adoption</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/11/on-becoming-mom-sally-kims-journey-toward-adoption/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Becoming Mom: Sally Kim's Journey Toward Adoption" /><published>2016-11-11T09:38:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-11T09:38:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/11/on-becoming-mom-sally-kims-journey-toward-adoption</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/11/on-becoming-mom-sally-kims-journey-toward-adoption/">&lt;p&gt;When I was engaged, I once had a woman tell me that I would never understand what being a mom meant until I birthed my own child. That I would never understand the true depths of the heart of a mother, the very heartbeat of motherhood, until my body carried, delivered, and nursed a baby of my very flesh-made in love and intention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know how to respond. I had just lost two precious children as a foster mom. They were my biological half brothers and my foster sons at the same time, and they were reunified with our birth mom, a devastating decision by the Orange County Juvenile Courts, for me and for them. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were mine to love for two years. I bottle weaned, potty trained, and endured the storm of tantrums for one. I laid on the ground soiled with the tears of meltdowns and helped with math and reading, and sat in parent teacher conferences with another. My body was exhausted all the time. The bags under my eyes felt beyond just an expression of tiredness-I felt them physically weighing me down. My body did not deliver these boys, but my body felt motherhood deeply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After losing them, my body turned more exhausted, more tired; my mind turned over the events daily, and my bed became a place where I imagined what their new life looked like without our stability and love. I’m not anti-second chances, but I am for the child, not the birth parent, first. Unfortunately, this circumstance favored only the mom who still drank, still hit, still screamed, still left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the midst of our loss, my husband and I found out we were expecting our first. I carried our daughter for nine months and ate all my greens and had the experience of birthing her and nursing her and experiencing the helpless neediness of a newborn babe. She’s forever my girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, the birthing, the nursing, and the physical act of carrying her in my womb didn’t replace the loss of the two I carried in my heart. No; if anything, it made the loss all the deeper for those nine months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward some time-we have an eleven month old, are expecting baby number two, and receive an unexpected, but oh-so-hoped-for phone call from Child Protective Services-the situation worsened and it’s time to bring our boys home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two years of not seeing and not hearing from them; not knowing who was tucking them in, or if they even had a bed to be tucked into. Two years of not knowing who was reading them stories or crying with them when life felt too heavy for such a little heart…not being able to comfort or scare away the monsters (both real and imaginary)-they were coming home, maybe this time for good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And something interesting has haunted (for lack of a better word) my mind these last six months of having our boys home. We now have a house of seven, three adopted, two birthed, one still nursing, one enjoying her new found favorite word, “no…” and there has never been a moment where I look at one child as more “mine” than the other. My sons are not less ours because we didn’t birth them. They have a background we must fight to understand, yes-But our hearts do not lack a deep love for them because they were not brought home from the hospital with us. Our daughters are not more ours because we experienced the 30 hours in the hospital of laboring and waiting and yearning for them. Yes, that’s an experience to treasure and remember-but so is the anticipation we experienced on our drive to Orangewood to pickup our sons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are different chapters of the same book; different layers of the same love. One does not make me more of a mother than the other. Each child has initiated me into this role of mommy-hood-releasing in me the fire to fight for whatever is needed for one the power to love at any cost for all, and the soft whisper of nurturing that is birthed with becoming Mom-no matter how the title was given.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sally Kim</name></author><category term="adoption" /><category term="motherhood" /><category term="family" /><category term="children" /><category term="birth" /><category term="foster-care" /><summary type="html">When I was engaged, I once had a woman tell me that I would never understand what being a mom meant until I birthed my own child. That I would never understand the true depths of the heart of a mother, the very heartbeat of motherhood, until my body carried, delivered, and nursed a baby of my very flesh-made in love and intention.

I didn’t know how to respond. I had just lost two precious children as a foster mom. They were my biological half brothers and my foster sons at the same time, and they were reunified with our birth mom, a devastating decision by the Orange County Juvenile Courts, for me and for them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/on-becoming-mom.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Journey Toward Impact</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/08/a-journey-toward-impact/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Journey Toward Impact" /><published>2016-11-08T22:53:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-08T22:53:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/08/a-journey-toward-impact</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/08/a-journey-toward-impact/">&lt;p&gt;“My story has been one marked by journey. Journey through a sea of unknowns, intricate passions, and deep questions. I’ve always been fascinated by people, and I’ve always loved business. Since I was little, I’ve always sought to get understanding at the root, and to be apart of people’s journeys.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within minutes of my conversation with Kalee, I recognize an immense amount of experience, depth, and passion. After graduating from Southern Methodist University as a communications and PR major, Kalee dove right into a career in marketing at a sports entertainment firm. With clients like Puma, ATNT, and other big name companies, Kalee was balancing a lot of responsibility, traveling constantly, and often working 60-80 hour weeks. 
“When you’re working that much and you’re traveling that much, it can also be really lonely and isolating. So I came to this place… if I’m going to be working this much, I should at least be doing something I really care about.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeking more meaning and purpose in her work meant living through a nine month journey of asking hard questions to find out what her best contribution to the world could be.&lt;br /&gt;
“What are my skills? What are my gifts? What do I like? I didn’t even know, to be honest, and it was really disorienting.” 
Through asking hard questions, allowing people to speak into her life, and a pivotal conversation with her mom, Kalee came to realize she wanted to be a therapist. She didn’t even know what a marriage and family therapist was at the time, but Kalee knew she had experienced a lot of healing in her life, so she wanted to be able to offer that to people.What Kalee was stepping into didn’t make sense at first, and she didn’t have a complete picture of what she was walking into, but isn’t that where the adventure is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After completing her program and powering through the grind of getting her hours, Kalee launched her own private practice in January of this year. “What I say I will never do, tends to be what I do. This whole journey has been one of open hands, and I’ve really grown. In getting to be in private practice, in in-patient psych, in trauma work, and in getting to see how people’s stories play out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After launching her practice, Kalee knew there was still more - something different, something bigger she needed to step into. Kalee asked, “What are the parts of me that I want to play in? I have this kingdom to play in, where do I say ‘yes’ and where do I say ‘no way?’”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this whole season, Kalee had always been involved at Wayfare on different levels. “I realized I love business strategy, it excites me. But I also love leaders. I understand the nuances and complexities of being a leader. Whether you’re the CEO for a for-profit, whether you’re the executive director of a non-profit, or you’re leading a church… whatever it is, there are a lot of things that go with that. It can be a very isolating place, and it’s really  hard to live into the fullness of who you are because of the expectation, because of the pressure, because of the burdens. You can’t be fully known, because of the expectations at play.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And out of Kalee’s heart, her background, and her first hand experience in leadership, Wayfare’s Impact Program was born. She began asking the question, “What does it look like to create a space for leaders to be fully human and flourish for themselves, but then also for their relationships and their organizations to flourish?”  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Kalee came to Jeff Tanner, co-founder of Wayfare, with this vision, and it catalyzed. She entered Launch, one of Wayfare’s startup programs, and began a 15 week journey to grow the Impact Program from an idea to an organization, to help leaders sustain impact. Kalee’s heart bleeds with the passion to change the culture of work by providing leaders with a space to live in the fullness of who they are and lead their organizations out of that place - instead of a place of isolation, burnout, exhaustion, and failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“One thing we believe is that a lonely leader won’t sustain impact. If you’re living detached from who you are, then you’re not going to be able to continue leading and impacting well. Your impact may actually become destructive, and you will start to implode. That may be a slow deterioration, or it may be an accelerated deterioration. With that, you also start to see the breakdown in family, the breakdown in an organization, as well as personal breakdown.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By providing practical and integrated support, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wayfare.io/startups/&quot;&gt;Impact&lt;/a&gt; provides a space for leaders to lead sustainably. Leaders who are apart of the Impact program are placed in locationally based cohorts to meet once a month. Groups are led by a business guide and an integration guide, and participants will engage in discussion on organizational victories, unique challenges, and questions so that they begin to have a bigger picture of what they’re operating out of. The experience is very collaborative, organic, and it’s a very in-process format. Through facilitated conversation, shared meals, and guided self-reflection, the Impact Program is a tool for leaders to be able to invest intentionally in their lives and in their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kalee’s mission is that as leaders begin to live into the fullness of who there are, they begin to work in meaning and interact with one another in a way that starts to define the new vocabulary that they’re bringing into their own organization. As they model this in their leadership, their employees will be empowered and start to ask questions and realize that who they are is so incredibly intertwined with the way they work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Kalee prepares to launch the Impact Program this Thursday at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/wayfare-labs-pitch-night/&quot;&gt;Wayfare’s Pitch Night&lt;/a&gt;, she invites people into her vision - to take a step toward sustainable impact for themselves, or encouraging a leader they know to step into it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="life" /><category term="startups" /><summary type="html">“My story has been one marked by journey. Journey through a sea of unknowns, intricate passions, and deep questions. I’ve always been fascinated by people, and I’ve always loved business. Since I was little, I’ve always sought to get understanding at the root, and to be apart of people’s journeys.”

Within minutes of my conversation with Kalee, I recognize an immense amount of experience, depth, and passion. After graduating from Southern Methodist University as a communications and PR major, Kalee dove right into a career in marketing at a sports entertainment firm. With clients like Puma, ATNT, and other big name companies, Kalee was balancing a lot of responsibility, traveling constantly, and often working 60-80 hour weeks. 
“When you’re working that much and you’re traveling that much, it can also be really lonely and isolating. So I came to this place… if I’m going to be working this much, I should at least be doing something I really care about.”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/a-journey-toward-impact.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">That Marriages Would Thrive: From Crashing to Connecting</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/04/that-marriages-would-thrive-from-crashing-to-connecting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="That Marriages Would Thrive: From Crashing to Connecting" /><published>2016-11-04T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-04T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/04/that-marriages-would-thrive-from-crashing-to-connecting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/04/that-marriages-would-thrive-from-crashing-to-connecting/">&lt;p&gt;What do you think of when the word marriage comes up? Long flowing white dress? Small house in the suburbs? Two individuals who are devoted to spending the rest of their lives together? &lt;!-- more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Casey and Meygan met each other in college, it was love at first sight. Young and in love, they decided to get married just two years later. The young couple went into their new stage of life full of wonder and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While marriage is a beautiful union, it is not at all what the movies depict it to be. Between both sets of parents, there were 12 marriages. They knew firsthand the troubles, the pain, and the brokenness of marriage. Refusing to let those failed marriages affect their future, Casey and Meygan dove into their marriage headfirst to prove to themselves that marriage can work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That idealized view came crashing down soon enough as their lives became plagued with arguments after arguments. Wasn’t marriage the answer to happiness? Why was it suddenly so difficult to maintain happiness after they said “I do”? They vowed that divorce was not an option, but things seemed so bleak and the first three years of the marriage progressively became worse and worse. They were missing connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is not where their story ends. Casey and Meygan knew it was time for a change. But what would help rekindle their marriage? They surrounded themselves with mentors that guided them through this difficult season. They sought to improve and work on themselves before finding fault in the other. They read any book they could get their hands on and attended a marriage boot camp! In many ways, they started dating each other again, discovering what made the other person tick, learning how to communicate better, taking up hobbies together, to back when they were two wide eyed college lovers. They were committed to connecting again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through commitment and connecting, they learned that great marriages don’t just happen by accident. It takes a lot of work, intentionality 365 days a year; thus Marriage365 was born! Casey and Meygan are continually striving to help keep marriages thriving to help out similarly struggling couples, whether that’s through their monthly podcast, online courses, or even being coaches and mentors. They want to see marriages last a lifetime and be a part of the solution. Too often marriage counseling hovers on two extremes; focusing on only family and not the underlying problems or too individualistic, often resulting in divorce. &lt;a href=&quot;http://marriage365.org&quot;&gt;Marriage365&lt;/a&gt; uniquely places itself in the middle, getting down to the raw issues while focusing and family and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their advice for struggling couples? “Many married couples do not want to spend time or money on their marriage until it’s too late. They don’t see the value of regular maintenance with their relationship. The biggest advice we would give is that money, careers, your home, your car all can come and go but your relationships with others is where you’ll find true happiness and contentment. It’s truly how you should measure your success in life.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This mission is not an easy one; each couple is unique and success looks different for each one.  No one should have to deal with life’s hardships alone and this organization has so many resources that can aid your journey with your spouse. Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://marriage365.org&quot;&gt;marriage365.org&lt;/a&gt; for marriage resources, to refer your friends, and donate. Commit to connecting again with helpful resources, including online courses, private coaching, monthly webcasts, and e-books like one of their most popular: “Naked Dinners”.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="life" /><category term="common good" /><category term="work" /><summary type="html">What do you think of when the word marriage comes up? Long flowing white dress? Small house in the suburbs? Two individuals who are devoted to spending the rest of their lives together? 

When Casey and Meygan met each other in college, it was love at first sight. Young and in love, they decided to get married just two years later. The young couple went into their new stage of life full of wonder and love.

While marriage is a beautiful union, it is not at all what the movies depict it to be. Between both sets of parents, there were 12 marriages. They knew firsthand the troubles, the pain, and the brokenness of marriage. Refusing to let those failed marriages affect their future, Casey and Meygan dove into their marriage headfirst to prove to themselves that marriage can work.

That idealized view came crashing down soon enough as their lives became plagued with arguments after arguments. Wasn’t marriage the answer to happiness? Why was it suddenly so difficult to maintain happiness after they said “I do”? They vowed that divorce was not an option, but things seemed so bleak and the first three years of the marriage progressively became worse and worse. They were missing connection.

But this is not where their story ends. Casey and Meygan knew it was time for a change. But what would help rekindle their marriage? They surrounded themselves with mentors that guided them through this difficult season. They sought to improve and work on themselves before finding fault in the other. They read any book they could get their hands on and attended a marriage boot camp! In many ways, they started dating each other again, discovering what made the other person tick, learning how to communicate better, taking up hobbies together, to back when they were two wide eyed college lovers. They were committed to connecting again.

Through commitment and connecting, they learned that great marriages don’t just happen by accident. It takes a lot of work, intentionality 365 days a year; thus Marriage365 was born! Casey and Meygan are continually striving to help keep marriages thriving to help out similarly struggling couples, whether that’s through their monthly podcast, online courses, or even being coaches and mentors. They want to see marriages last a lifetime and be a part of the solution. Too often marriage counseling hovers on two extremes; focusing on only family and not the underlying problems or too individualistic, often resulting in divorce. Marriage365 uniquely places itself in the middle, getting down to the raw issues while focusing and family and love.

Their advice for struggling couples? “Many married couples do not want to spend time or money on their marriage until it’s too late. They don’t see the value of regular maintenance with their relationship. The biggest advice we would give is that money, careers, your home, your car all can come and go but your relationships with others is where you’ll find true happiness and contentment. It’s truly how you should measure your success in life.”

This mission is not an easy one; each couple is unique and success looks different for each one.  No one should have to deal with life’s hardships alone and this organization has so many resources that can aid your journey with your spouse. Visit marriage365.org for marriage resources, to refer your friends, and donate. Commit to connecting again with helpful resources, including online courses, private coaching, monthly webcasts, and e-books like one of their most popular: “Naked Dinners”.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/IMG_8700.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Orange County, United</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/01/orange-county-united/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Orange County, United" /><published>2016-11-01T16:55:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-01T16:55:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/01/orange-county-united</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/11/01/orange-county-united/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org&quot;&gt;OC United&lt;/a&gt; is just that… Orange County, United. They are driven to unite north Orange County and provide a place for restorative relationships and life skills training to create empowered lives for OC’s most vulnerable. Founders Jay Williams and Amy Gaw are currently participating in the Launch phase of Wayfare’s &lt;a href=&quot;wayfare.io/startups&quot;&gt;Startup Programs&lt;/a&gt;, and we’ve been inspired by them since day one… in the unique way they are pursuing the common good, their humility and solidarity in standing with the vulnerable, and in the way they invite and unite the communities they live and work in. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re all neighbors. We live in the same space and share the same resources. But some of us don’t have homes. Some of us don’t have families. Some of us are isolated despite being surrounded by others. We were tired of feeling helpless when presented with heartbreaking needs, so we decided to do something about it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org&quot;&gt;OC United&lt;/a&gt; team is made up of a collection of citizens, non-profits and churches that believe they can accomplish more working together than apart. They are based in Christian faith but “welcome anyone with a pulse”. They currently work with the vulnerable in 4 different contexts: those from foster care, those experiencing homelessness, victims of domestic abuse, and families in under-resourced neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of organizations exist to serve vulnerable groups and individuals through various programs and services, but few address the root issue of the problem. &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org&quot;&gt;OC United&lt;/a&gt; believes that people become vulnerable because they are experiencing the breakdown of the family unit. The ramifications of this breakdown are all around us in society, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org&quot;&gt;OC United&lt;/a&gt; seeks to rebuild and restore the family units by loving support and transitional empowerment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We believe that lasting change occurs by coming alongside the vulnerable in long-term relationship, not through programs alone. As we continue to make strategic decisions, we want to ask ourselves: How are we helping to heal and restore those affected by broken family units?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org&quot;&gt;OC United&lt;/a&gt; serves the vulnerable in a variety of contexts. Some of their programs include &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org/homeless/&quot;&gt;facilitating family fun nights and kids clubs for motel families&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org/homeless/&quot;&gt;mobile laundry and showers for the homeless&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org/neighbors/&quot;&gt;after school tutoring and ESL classes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org/homeless/&quot;&gt;empowering homeless with life skills and career building&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org/foster-care/&quot;&gt;supporting foster families with errands, childcare, encouragement, &amp;amp; tangible goods&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org/foster-care/&quot;&gt;mentorship&lt;/a&gt;, and so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are committed to building a strong foundation for the future and sustaining long term impact. Their vision for the future, as a direct result of their mission, is that by June 2017 they will further their impact by working in relationship with 500 individuals/families providing place for connection, support, and empowerment to build into healthy family units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join them in empowering the vulnerable by visiting &lt;a href=&quot;https://ocunited.org&quot;&gt;OCUnited.org&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; by attending &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/wayfare-labs-pitch-night/&quot;&gt;Pitch Night&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday, November 10th from 7-9pm at Wayfare’s new location in Fullerton, CA. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/wayfare-labs-pitch-night/&quot;&gt;RSVP here&lt;/a&gt; to hear Jay &amp;amp; Amy share their mission &amp;amp; vision and opportunities for partnership.&lt;/strong&gt; Hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="homeless" /><category term="foster-care" /><category term="foster" /><category term="pitch" /><category term="startup" /><category term="vulnerable" /><category term="nonprofit" /><category term="empowerment" /><category term="family" /><category term="neighbors" /><category term="neighborhood" /><category term="solidarity" /><category term="community" /><category term="Orange-County" /><category term="fullerton" /><category term="motel" /><category term="church" /><summary type="html">OC United is just that… Orange County, United. They are driven to unite north Orange County and provide a place for restorative relationships and life skills training to create empowered lives for OC’s most vulnerable. Founders Jay Williams and Amy Gaw are currently participating in the Launch phase of Wayfare’s Startup Programs, and we’ve been inspired by them since day one… in the unique way they are pursuing the common good, their humility and solidarity in standing with the vulnerable, and in the way they invite and unite the communities they live and work in.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/oc-united.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Valuing the Introvert in you</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/21/valuing-the-introvert-in-you/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Valuing the Introvert in you" /><published>2016-10-21T23:37:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-21T23:37:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/21/valuing-the-introvert-in-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/21/valuing-the-introvert-in-you/">&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a quiz! Answer yes or no to the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I prefer one-on-one conversations to group activities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I often prefer to express myself in writing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I dislike small talk, but I enjoy talking in-depth about topics that matter to me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People tell me that I’m a good listener.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoy work that allows me to “dive in” with few interruptions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I like to celebrate birthdays on a small scale, with only one or only a few friends.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People describe me as “soft-spoken” or “mellow.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I prefer not to show or discuss my work with others until it’s finished.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I dislike conflict.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I do my best work on my own.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I tend to think before I speak.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I feel drained after being out and about, even if I’ve enjoyed myself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If I had to choose, I’d prefer a weekend with less to do rather than too much. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were like me and were shaking your head vigorously yes to most of these questions, then congratulations! You are an introvert!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were also like me, then this result would have repulsed you. On almost every one of my report cards, my teachers would write, “Emily needs to come out of her shell.” I recall the first time my mother confronted me about this, gripping the report card in her hand. “Why can’t you be like the other kids? You will not be successful if you are quiet!” These are not words that eight year olds want to hear, or can even comprehend. Even a newly immigrated Chinese woman who barely spoke English knew that there was something “wrong” with being an introvert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on this feedback, I felt the need to correct myself and become a “learned extrovert”. I forced myself to raise my hand and talk in class. I forced myself to be the “leader” in group projects. I forced myself to mingle and hang out in large group settings. To the outside world, it might have seemed I was successful. But was I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I didn’t realize was that “shy” and “introvert” aren’t necessarily the same thing. &lt;strong&gt;Shyness is the fear of negative judgment, and introversion is a preference for minimally stimulating environments.&lt;/strong&gt; On the contrary,extraverts typically tend to enjoy human interactions and thrive off being around other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21st century Western culture revolves around extroversion. Classrooms are structured so that kids face each other in a table and many office spaces are designed in the same manner, to encourage students and coworkers to talk and work together.. We’ve become a culture of personality, where charisma and magnetism are highly favored traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I tried to jam myself into that extrovert mold, it was like trying to hold water on a flat plate: messy and useless. I’d flop onto my bed at the end of the day, feeling so drained that no amount of sleep would take away the empty feeling. It wasn’t until I read Susan Cain’s insights on introversion that I truly understood my personality type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her book, Quiet, was a game changer in my life. The title itself was so eye catching: Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking. I immediately picked up the book and saw this line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Don’t think of introversion as something that needs to be cured.&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d been told my entire life by my parents, teachers, and friends, to “come out of your shell”. Why was this an issue? Why was it a problem that instead of going to someone’s house on a weekend, I preferred to stay at home and read? Why was it a problem that I liked to think and work by myself before group projects? Why did anyone feel like it was necessary that I had to be an “extrovert”?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cain argues that introversion is not a problem at all, but can actually be a person’s greatest strength. Everyone has been given different abilities, and it’s just a matter of knowing yourself and putting yourself in the right environments. In fact, there have been a lot of very influential leaders that were introverts: Rosa Parks, Ghandi, and good old honest Abe! Introversion and leadership are not mutually exclusive. Cain brings up the example of Moses; “we don’t ask why God chose as his prophet a stutterer with a public speaking phobia. But we should. The book of Exodus is short on explication, but its stories suggest that introversion plays yin to the yang of extroversion; that the medium is not always the message; and that people followed Moses because his words were thoughtful, not because he spoke them well.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introverts are needed everywhere, even in business! It’s not just an extrovert’s stomping grounds anymore. Because of the overwhelming number of extroverts in the business world, Adrian Schumpeter of The Economist argues that this is why more and more companies need the reflective and long term qualities of an introvert. We need more Mark Zuckerbergs and Bill Gates in a world filled with Steve Jobs and Sheryl Sandbergs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I embrace my introversion, I realize that some of my core strengths come from my introverted personality. My best work comes from my introspection. Creativity flows my from reflection. I strive to be the best version of myself, not a flimsy mold of what society deems is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This by no means is a simple task, and it’s still something I struggle with everyday. But with Cain’s “Quiet Revolution Manifesto”, I’m constantly being reminded that my introversion itself is a strength:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is a word for “people who are in their heads too much”— thinkers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solitude is a catalyst for innovation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The next generation of quiet kids can and must be raised to know their own strengths.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sometimes it helps to be a pretend-extrovert. There is always time to be quiet later.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But in the long run, staying true to your temperament is the key to finding work you love and work that matters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One genuine relationship is worth a fistful of business cards.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s okay to cross the street to avoid making small talk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Quiet leadership” is not an oxymoron.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Love is essential; gregariousness is optional.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“In a gentle way, you can shake the world.” —Mahatma Gandhi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So take pride in your personality, introverted or extroverted, because you have the power to change the world as long as you are passionate. It may manifest itself in different ways but the potential is not restricted to how you enjoy your free time. As Susan Cain beautifully states, “we know from myths and fairy tales that there are many different kinds of powers in this world. One child is given a light saber, another a wizard’s education. The trick is not to amass all the different kinds of power, but to use well the kind you’ve been granted.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="introversion" /><category term="introvert" /><category term="personality" /><category term="quiet" /><category term="susan" /><category term="cain" /><category term="shy" /><category term="western" /><category term="culture" /><summary type="html">Let’s take a quiz! Answer yes or no to the following questions:


  I prefer one-on-one conversations to group activities.
  I often prefer to express myself in writing.
  I dislike small talk, but I enjoy talking in-depth about topics that matter to me.
  People tell me that I’m a good listener.
  I enjoy work that allows me to “dive in” with few interruptions.
  I like to celebrate birthdays on a small scale, with only one or only a few friends.
  People describe me as “soft-spoken” or “mellow.”
  I prefer not to show or discuss my work with others until it’s finished.
  I dislike conflict.
  I do my best work on my own.
  I tend to think before I speak.
  I feel drained after being out and about, even if I’ve enjoyed myself.
  If I had to choose, I’d prefer a weekend with less to do rather than too much.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/valuing-the-introvert-in-you.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Buy Jewelry, Change Lives</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/13/buy-jewelry-change-lives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Buy Jewelry, Change Lives" /><published>2016-10-13T21:31:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-13T21:31:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/13/buy-jewelry-change-lives</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/13/buy-jewelry-change-lives/">&lt;p&gt;Modern-day slavery exists in every country in some form or another. Sweatshops, prostitute rings, and domestic work are a few examples of the enslavement of men, women and even children. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ilo.org/global/lang--en/index.htm&quot;&gt;International Labour Organization&lt;/a&gt;, around 21 million individuals are forced into slavery each year around the world, and the impact of slavery is evident in nearly every aspect of our lives. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Slaves harvest cocoa in West Africa, and it ends up in our chocolate. Slaves make charcoal in Brazil, which is used to run smelters that make steel for our cars. Many food products and raw materials are tainted by slavery—such as tomatoes, tuna, shrimp, cotton, diamonds, iron, sugar, and gold.” – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freetheslaves.net&quot;&gt;Free The Slaves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bringing an end to modern-day slavery is a fight that isn’t over, and we stand with the warriors around the world fighting on the frontline for complete redemption and freedom for all people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the many incredible organizations that is committed to ending modern slavery is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purposejewelry.org&quot;&gt;Purpose Jewelry&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary’s&lt;/a&gt; social enterprise. They are dedicated to helping every single woman they can, by giving her a second chance at life. 100% of their jewelry proceeds benefit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;International Sanctuary&lt;/a&gt;, their parent non-profit organization, which provides holistic care for young women rescued from sex trafficking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among many other world-changing social enterprises, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purposejewelry.org&quot;&gt;Purpose Jewelry&lt;/a&gt; provides everyday opportunities for consumers like you and I to directly empower women in need worldwide. By buying a piece of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purposejewelry.org&quot;&gt;Purpose Jewelry&lt;/a&gt;, you directly affect the life of a young survivor of sex trafficking across the world in six specific ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Medical &amp;amp; Dental Care&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary&lt;/a&gt; provides much needed medical and dental care to the women rescued from sex trafficking. This care can be for something as minor as a check-up to life-saving procedures. By buying a necklace, you could very well save someone’s life and help her stay healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary&lt;/a&gt; has started an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org/academy/&quot;&gt;Academy program&lt;/a&gt;, which provides every young woman in the program with opportunities to dream of a sustainable future by setting educational and personal development goals in four core areas, while earning an income. Many girls who escape or are rescued from modern-day slavery are hindered by their lack of education and employable skills. By buying a piece of jewelry and thus giving these girls and women an education, you are opening up doors to a better future and life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scholarships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to providing education to the women they work with, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary&lt;/a&gt; also provides scholarships. With these scholarships, the women are given the opportunity to further their education, either through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org/academy/&quot;&gt;The Academy&lt;/a&gt; or to attend university. These scholarships are funded by your purchases from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purposejewelry.org&quot;&gt;Purpose Jewelry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Counseling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After experiencing the horrors of modern-day slavery and the sex trade, a woman needs a safe space to work through her experiences and feelings. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary&lt;/a&gt; provides support and counseling, helping the women heal. In addition to counseling, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary&lt;/a&gt; provides one-on-one mentoring and life skills training so women can confidently get back on their feet and regain independence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Micro-loans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To regain independence, it is crucial that the survivors of modern-day slavery have basic financial skills and can financially support themselves. When necessary, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.isanctuary.org&quot;&gt;iSanctuary&lt;/a&gt; provides loans to the young women who need them. At the same time, the women are taught financial skills and are helped in opening their own bank account so that they can be financially stable and independent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stability and routine is very important to a woman overcoming the trauma of modern-day slavery, and employment provides this stability. Through working for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purposejewelry.org&quot;&gt;Purpose Jewelry&lt;/a&gt;, these survivors receive job training and paychecks. As a result, they don’t have to worry about job searches or finances, and they can focus on their healing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re invited to join us for a first look at the NEW Purpose Signature Collection tonight at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/purpose-signature-collection/&quot;&gt;Purpose Signature Collection Launch Party&lt;/a&gt; here at Wayfare Costa Mesa. This special collection of five pieces stands for FREEDOM, and we’re encouraging you all to make a fashion statement: wear PURPOSE, wear freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll get a chance to shop the Autumn &amp;amp; Signature collection in person, enjoy delicious food from the Waffle-icious food truck, hear live music by Megan Tibbits, and participate in a raffle with sweet prizes. They’ll also be showing an exclusive first viewing of their PURPOSE brand video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You won’t want to miss this amazing night! The event is free, but please &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/purpose-signature-collection/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt; and invite your friends and family! The first 30 people to show up at the party get FREE swag bags!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="common-good" /><category term="social-enterprise" /><category term="trafficking" /><category term="jewelry" /><category term="enterprise" /><category term="good" /><category term="world" /><category term="slavery" /><category term="empowerment" /><category term="education" /><category term="counseling" /><category term="india" /><category term="women" /><category term="freedom" /><summary type="html">Modern-day slavery exists in every country in some form or another. Sweatshops, prostitute rings, and domestic work are a few examples of the enslavement of men, women and even children. According to the International Labour Organization, around 21 million individuals are forced into slavery each year around the world, and the impact of slavery is evident in nearly every aspect of our lives.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/buy-jewelry-change-lives.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Seeing People Who Feel Invisible</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/04/seeing-people-who-feel-invisible/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seeing People Who Feel Invisible" /><published>2016-10-04T16:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-04T16:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/04/seeing-people-who-feel-invisible</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/04/seeing-people-who-feel-invisible/">&lt;p&gt;“His scream was ear-splitting. The stairwell in our apartment building acted as an amplifier, his cry blatantly bouncing of our building’s walls. My wife and I shamelessly named him “the screaming homeless man”.
There was one afternoon when his scream traveled upstairs and found its home in our living room as I was sitting on my couch reading this book about love - Love Does. The book was talking about loving your neighbor, and it hit me: he was my neighbor. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I went down to talk to him for the first time. His name was Matt. In that moment of speaking with him I had this overwhelming sense that I needed to paint his portrait. He had such an interesting face. This big beard. You could see the struggle on Matt’s face, and I saw beauty in it.
I hadn’t painted in eight years, but I envisioned his story coming alive on the canvas in cool blues and deep yellows. From Matt’s story of ambition, failure, and isolation, &lt;strong&gt;The Faces of Santa Ana&lt;/strong&gt; was born. I call it a family before anything, because that’s what it’s become. I meet them, I build trust, I paint them, and they become family. We have imperfect relationships, there are hard moments. There are easy moments. There are great moments.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian Peterson, founder of the Faces of Santa Ana, studied car design at the Cleveland Institute of Art, and currently works at KIA design center. As I listened to Brian relay Matt’s story, I can tell he’s living out of an unbridled passion to make the invisible seen. In Brian’s case, his medium of choice is oil on canvas, and his process is unlike any other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The painting starts the minute I say hello, before I even buy the canvas. Sometimes, when I meet them I already know what color it’s going to be. I met a lady the other day and I told her, “Red. I have to paint you with Red.” Only after learning their stories can I go home and paint. The painting embodies who they are. Their experiences. I take all of that with me when I go home to paint in my living room. I want what’s coming onto the canvas to be them. Each painting takes between 12 and 16 hours, and then I take it out to them in the streets wherever they may be sleeping, living, or standing. Then they get to sign the painting. That’s important, because I want them to know that they’re part of this story. You can tell some of them forget how to sign their signature. These are people who have been outcast by their families, by society, by everyone that walks by - when I follow through and show them the finished product, trust is built.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a year since his encounter with Matt, and Brian is on his fifteenth FOSA painting, each 30x40inch masterpiece being sold at an average of $2,500. The money from the purchase goes to meet a direct need of the person featured in the painting. How does Brian decide which need to meet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I usually ask them. Along the way I’ve learned a lot, but I want to know their hopes and dreams, I want to know the things that are keeping them in the chains that they’re experiencing.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the Faces of Santa Ana, Brian had never sold a painting. His art was always a selfless expression of love towards people he cared about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I gave a piece of art to the financial director at my college, and I gave a bunch of my paintings in college to my friends. I never thought of it as a way to make money, so this is new for me. If you go to my father’s house… his house is all full of my paintings. If I love someone, I give them a painting. I think we all have a unique way to show people love, we all have that capacity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We’re all born with the capacity to love someone. What’s your medium?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come hear Brian Peterson first hand as he speaks at Q-Commons on, &lt;strong&gt;“Seeing People Who Feel Invisible.”&lt;/strong&gt;  To Register for Q-Commons, visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qcommons.com/costamesa&quot;&gt;Q-Commons Costa Mesa website&lt;/a&gt;. Discounted &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.qcommons.com/costamesa&quot;&gt;tickets&lt;/a&gt; are available for Wayfare members, students, couples and groups of 8 or more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="art" /><category term="non profit" /><category term="homelessness" /><category term="stories" /><summary type="html">“His scream was ear-splitting. The stairwell in our apartment building acted as an amplifier, his cry blatantly bouncing of our building’s walls. My wife and I shamelessly named him “the screaming homeless man”.
There was one afternoon when his scream traveled upstairs and found its home in our living room as I was sitting on my couch reading this book about love - Love Does. The book was talking about loving your neighbor, and it hit me: he was my neighbor.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/Matt%20Faris.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Novelty isn’t Creativity… at Least not all of it</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/04/novelty-isnt-creativity-dot-dot-dot-at-least-not-all-of-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Novelty isn't Creativity... at Least not all of it" /><published>2016-10-04T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-10-04T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/04/novelty-isnt-creativity-dot-dot-dot-at-least-not-all-of-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/10/04/novelty-isnt-creativity-dot-dot-dot-at-least-not-all-of-it/">&lt;p&gt;My wife and I are big fans of Project Runway. Not only do we like design and fashion, but it’s also a fascinating inspection of culture. And we like to predict the winners and losers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each season, there’s a designer who the judges almost kick off but keep around because they have “a very specific point of view.” And because of ratings, I’m sure. Viewers love a good tragedy.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorites was a Japanese guy named Kooan. He specialized in what I vainly attempt to describe as a caricature of California surf culture, Pokemon, and the worst of the 80s. He called it Japanese street wear. The judges didn’t know what to call it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the point. He makes novel clothes. They have a specific point of view, but the judges almost kick him off on the first day of competition. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m concerned he makes crazy clothes for the sake of being crazy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He may just want to be the center of attention.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were concerned that his creativity is limited to the novelty of his clothes—their newness, and they want to know if his creations are also effective. At what? Evoking positive emotion, and making a woman feel beautiful, confident, strong, and noticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reminded me of an important rule: Creativity requires but does not equal novelty. Creativity also requires purpose—purpose that is selfless…other-oriented. Creativity is at least the combination of newness + purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The judges’ common descriptions (paraphrased) for the top designers each week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Any girl would want to wear this dress.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I clearly see a point of view you embody and that others want to be.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you watch the show, you’re probably thinking Patricia and Sandhya of more recent seasons also fall into this category—designing more for themselves and not caring as much about who will actually have to wear their clothes. They were also labeled as crazy by their fellow designers and the judges on more than one occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Observing these designers prompted a key question about the nature of creativity—and about my own inclinations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there times when I care more that my ideas are new than I care if they actually meet the real needs of others? Guilty as charged. I’m adding a new filtering question to my list of “good” ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In coming posts, I’ll continue to explore the nature of creativity. Stay tuned, and jump over to your favorite social channel to share your perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="novelty" /><category term="creativity" /><category term="original" /><category term="ideas" /><category term="design" /><category term="fashion" /><category term="purpose" /><summary type="html">My wife and I are big fans of Project Runway. Not only do we like design and fashion, but it’s also a fascinating inspection of culture. And we like to predict the winners and losers.

Each season, there’s a designer who the judges almost kick off but keep around because they have “a very specific point of view.” And because of ratings, I’m sure. Viewers love a good tragedy.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/novelty-isn't-creativity.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum, by Wayfare | Learning from the Art of Companion Gardening</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/27/introducing-forum-by-wayfare-learning-from-the-art-of-companion-gardening/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum, by Wayfare | Learning from the Art of Companion Gardening" /><published>2016-09-27T09:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-27T09:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/27/introducing-forum-by-wayfare-learning-from-the-art-of-companion-gardening</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/27/introducing-forum-by-wayfare-learning-from-the-art-of-companion-gardening/">&lt;p&gt;My dad is a man whose hands were perpetually rough with calluses and deep cracks, whose fingernails were cut dangerously short,left with barely enough room to be lined with dirt. He spent his evenings after work and his weekend mornings in our garden, wrist deep in the familiar warmth of soil that was nourished by our friendly hens and the roots of our thriving plot of vegetables. I inherited my dad’s deep love for the earth and some small part of his green thumb, which instinctively drove me to write my senior thesis on the dynamics of sustainable agriculture in Orange County. From that research arose one of my lifetime heroes: Dan Barber, co-owner of Blue Hill Farm and a leader in the world of food culture and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his riveting ethnography titled ‘The Third Plate: Field Notes on the Future of Food’, Barber comments boldly on the current state of our agricultural system. “In the rush to industrialize farming, we’ve lost the understanding, implicit since the beginning of agriculture, that food is a process, a web of relationships, not an individual ingredient or commodity.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the wave of monocultures that struck our nation in the early 1900s, agriculture was characterized by small farms that were home to a community of livestock and a diverse range of crops grown on the same plot. Each plant was dependent on the other to thrive. An ancient Native American technique called companion gardening is the purest example of this symbiotic relationship that exists between plants. Certain plants complement each other especially well, such as beans, squash, and corn. Each were planted in close proximity to one another to support each other in each stage of growth. Beans fix nitrogen in their roots, improving the fertility of the plot. Shallow squash roots act as living mulch, and their spiky leaves ward off pests. Corn acts as a natural pole for the beans to climb, and in turn the beans stabilize the corn stalk. Their relationship is not ambiguous, but rather a symbiotic partnership where there needs to be equal levels of dependence between each plant, intentionality on behalf of the gardener, and creativity in designing the plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the idea of companion gardening, we introduce to you: Forum, by Wayfare. Forum is built on the idea that we are all believers in the beauty of work and the necessity of learning. As we strive to advance the common good, our weakness is self-dependency. Without inspiration, support, and opportunities to challenge our thinking, we wither. We are not to be a wash of industry-specific monocultures, bound by the limitations of self-sufficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forum is a free for Global members! Bring your own lunch and be a part of a culture of people who crave opportunities to challenge each other and build a community around a shared interest in the common good. Join us at Wayfare HQ in Costa Mesa as we launch our first Forum from 12-1pm on Monday, October 3rd. Not local? Participate on your own time via podcast or join us in new locations as we continue to expand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October’s topics + speakers are listed below, so you can save the date. Also - great news! Our first Forum is open to EVERYONE - not just Wayfare members! So bring a friend and learn together over lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October 3 Joel Beukelman, “Do Something: The Power of Personal Branding”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October 10 Jeff Tanner, “Redeeming Work: Exploring the Future of Work as a Tool for Creating the World’s Best Future”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October 17 Jonathan Menkes + Thomas Yee, “10 IP Pitfalls Every Startup Should Avoid”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October 24 Steven + Amber Cowell, “Dropping’ Mics on Open Adoption”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October 31 Emily McLaughlin, “How to Improve Your Company Culture Without Spending a Dime”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="learning" /><category term="forum" /><category term="lunch" /><category term="collaborate" /><category term="speakers" /><category term="inspiring" /><category term="community" /><category term="gardening" /><category term="novelty" /><summary type="html">My dad is a man whose hands were perpetually rough with calluses and deep cracks, whose fingernails were cut dangerously short,left with barely enough room to be lined with dirt. He spent his evenings after work and his weekend mornings in our garden, wrist deep in the familiar warmth of soil that was nourished by our friendly hens and the roots of our thriving plot of vegetables. I inherited my dad’s deep love for the earth and some small part of his green thumb, which instinctively drove me to write my senior thesis on the dynamics of sustainable agriculture in Orange County. From that research arose one of my lifetime heroes: Dan Barber, co-owner of Blue Hill Farm and a leader in the world of food culture and sustainability.

In his riveting ethnography titled ‘The Third Plate: Field Notes on the Future of Food’, Barber comments boldly on the current state of our agricultural system. “In the rush to industrialize farming, we’ve lost the understanding, implicit since the beginning of agriculture, that food is a process, a web of relationships, not an individual ingredient or commodity.”

Before the wave of monocultures that struck our nation in the early 1900s, agriculture was characterized by small farms that were home to a community of livestock and a diverse range of crops grown on the same plot. Each plant was dependent on the other to thrive. An ancient Native American technique called companion gardening is the purest example of this symbiotic relationship that exists between plants. Certain plants complement each other especially well, such as beans, squash, and corn. Each were planted in close proximity to one another to support each other in each stage of growth. Beans fix nitrogen in their roots, improving the fertility of the plot. Shallow squash roots act as living mulch, and their spiky leaves ward off pests. Corn acts as a natural pole for the beans to climb, and in turn the beans stabilize the corn stalk. Their relationship is not ambiguous, but rather a symbiotic partnership where there needs to be equal levels of dependence between each plant, intentionality on behalf of the gardener, and creativity in designing the plot.

From the idea of companion gardening, we introduce to you: Forum, by Wayfare. Forum is built on the idea that we are all believers in the beauty of work and the necessity of learning. As we strive to advance the common good, our weakness is self-dependency. Without inspiration, support, and opportunities to challenge our thinking, we wither. We are not to be a wash of industry-specific monocultures, bound by the limitations of self-sufficiency.

Forum is a free for Global members! Bring your own lunch and be a part of a culture of people who crave opportunities to challenge each other and build a community around a shared interest in the common good. Join us at Wayfare HQ in Costa Mesa as we launch our first Forum from 12-1pm on Monday, October 3rd. Not local? Participate on your own time via podcast or join us in new locations as we continue to expand.

October’s topics + speakers are listed below, so you can save the date. Also - great news! Our first Forum is open to EVERYONE - not just Wayfare members! So bring a friend and learn together over lunch.

October 3 Joel Beukelman, “Do Something: The Power of Personal Branding”

October 10 Jeff Tanner, “Redeeming Work: Exploring the Future of Work as a Tool for Creating the World’s Best Future”

October 17 Jonathan Menkes + Thomas Yee, “10 IP Pitfalls Every Startup Should Avoid”

October 24 Steven + Amber Cowell, “Dropping’ Mics on Open Adoption”

October 31 Emily McLaughlin, “How to Improve Your Company Culture Without Spending a Dime”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/B1.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Brain Food vs. Drain Food: 3 Meals That Will Skyrocket Your Productivity</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/20/brain-food-vs-drain-food-3-meals-that-will-skyrocket-your-productivity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Brain Food vs. Drain Food: 3 Meals That Will Skyrocket Your Productivity" /><published>2016-09-20T09:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-20T09:45:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/20/brain-food-vs-drain-food-3-meals-that-will-skyrocket-your-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/20/brain-food-vs-drain-food-3-meals-that-will-skyrocket-your-productivity/">&lt;p&gt;It’s obviously no new concept that the way we eat has incredible implications on the way we perform and feel, but fueling our body with foods that increase our overall mental and physical health can often seem expensive or inconvenient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how much more costly and inconvenient is it when we’re not able to perform effectively because of a lack of energy or drive? &lt;!-- more --&gt; When we’re in that 2pm slump, we often turn to quick &amp;amp; easy ways to glean energy, like a pop tart or shot of espresso. Foods that are high in carbs and simple sugars like pop tarts are high in glucose. After eating the pop-tart, glucose is released into our blood in record speed. Unfortunately, the effects are a measly 20 minutes of alertness. After that, we experience a crash where our glucose levels drop dramatically, causing an inability to focus or be motivated. When I think about the ultimate glucose crash, I think about Thanksgiving dinner. Can you imagine working a full eight hour day after indulging in a meal like that? Me either. Our bodies weren’t designed to be productive after fuel like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your quest for the ideal workday meal ends here! I’ve curated a menu specifically designed to help you to eat your way to maximum productivity and provide your body with the right vitamins and minerals to get your wheels turning from the moment you wake up (and whatever you do, don’t skip breakfast).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BREAKFAST: CHIA AND BROWN RICE PUDDING TOPPED WITH BLUEBERRIES, RAW COCOA, AND CHOPPED WALNUTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1/2 cup of brown rice&lt;/strong&gt; cooked in 1 cup boiling water - brown rice is a whole grain filled with vitamins like magnesium that improve your cognitive health. A complex carb, whole grains are designed to give you sustained energy rather than temporary energy like simple carbs do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 tablespoons chia seeds&lt;/strong&gt; - Chia seeds are rich in fiver, omega 3 fats, and protein to boost your energy and metabolism&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handful of raw blueberries&lt;/strong&gt; - blueberries are rich in antioxidants, which improve your memory and motor coordination&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 tablespoon of raw cocoa&lt;/strong&gt; - Here’s permission to eat chocolate for breakfast! dark chocolate contains antioxidants that specifically enhance your focus and concentration.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Handful of &lt;strong&gt;raw, chopped walnuts&lt;/strong&gt; - Walnuts are one of the most beneficial nuts you can eat. With vitamin E, melatonin, omega-3 fats, and tons of antioxidants, walnuts support overall brain health, fight stress, and increase your ability to reason logically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LUNCH: SLICED TURKEY SANDWICH ON WHOLE GRAIN BREAD WITH AVOCADO AND A HARD BOILED EGG&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whole Grain bread&lt;/strong&gt;: Like we said, if you’re going to consume carbs, whole grains are the way to go. In addition to improving your cognitive performance, they’re high in fiber which aids in digestion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3-4 slices of &lt;strong&gt;hormone/antibiotic free turkey meat&lt;/strong&gt;: Turkey meat is an ideal source of vitamin B6 and niacin, which are critical to help your body produce natural energy. Why buy hormone/antibiotic free meat? Added hormones in any food interfere with your body’s natural hormone production and can cause anything from mood swings to an increased risk for cancer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sliced avocado&lt;/strong&gt;: Commonly known as one of the most healthy foods you can eat, avocados are packed with fiber, vitamin K, copper, vitamin B6, potassium, and Vitamin E and C. On top of that, they are great for long-term eye health, especially if you’re in front of a computer most of your day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard boiled egg&lt;/strong&gt;: Not only can you get quick protein from a hard boiled egg, but they contain a unique, fatty B-viatmin called choline. Choline boosts your memory and reaction time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DINNER: BAKED SALMON, BAKED SWEET POTATO FRIEDS, STEAMED KALE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 oz &lt;strong&gt;fresh salmon, topped with dill, olive oil, and lemon juice&lt;/strong&gt; and baked at 400 for 20 minutes: Salmon is packed with omega 3s, essential proteins, and tons of B vitamins. Each of these help you gain optimum memory and focus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 Sweet potato&lt;/strong&gt;, sliced, drizzled in olive oil and sea salt, and baked at 400 for 30 minutes: Sweet potatoes have endless health benefits, but since you’re winding down for the night it’s important to note that they are an incredible source of magnesium. Magnesium is the mineral that allows our bodies to relax and de-stress.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steamed kale&lt;/strong&gt;: Dark leafy greens are loaded with vitamins, minerals and phytonutrients like Iron. Iron transports oxygen to your brain and improves your cognitive control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Missed the first Brain Food post? Read our &lt;a href=&quot;http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/14/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity/&quot;&gt;Snack Plan for a Productive Workday&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/09/14/brain-food-vs-drain-food-how-to-snack-your-way-to-productivity/&quot;&gt;6 Quick Health Tips for improving brain function at work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="productivity" /><category term="health" /><category term="nutrition" /><category term="wellness" /><category term="work" /><category term="brain" /><category term="snacks" /><category term="mealplan" /><category term="meals" /><category term="mealprep" /><category term="food" /><category term="lunch" /><summary type="html">It’s obviously no new concept that the way we eat has incredible implications on the way we perform and feel, but fueling our body with foods that increase our overall mental and physical health can often seem expensive or inconvenient.

But how much more costly and inconvenient is it when we’re not able to perform effectively because of a lack of energy or drive?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/brain-food-vs-drain-food-3-meals-that-will-skyrocket-your-productivity.jpg" /></entry></feed>
