<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://wayfare.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://wayfare.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-05-15T16:21:44+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/</id><title type="html">Wayfare</title><entry><title type="html">Orphans and Mothers</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/05/12/orphans-and-mothers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Orphans and Mothers" /><published>2017-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/05/12/orphans-and-mothers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/05/12/orphans-and-mothers/">&lt;p&gt;Spring is a season full of dichotomies. The weather has been extreme (at least here in Southern California)—two days ago it was nearing 90 degrees; today, it’s raining across Orange County. Flowers and Super Blooms and all that green and splashes of color are rising; as are everyone’s allergies. It’s a beautiful season, but it’s complicated and sometimes an irritant, as we adjust from the thrills of winter and navigate this season of now, and not yet, that is Spring. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May, specifically, is an interesting one for me. It’s Mother’s Day month; where my husband will attempt something sweet, and our kids will bring home cards from school, and our daughter might give me some extra snuggles. We’ll probably do some extended family time and I’ll get to hear some innocent and thoughtful affirmations from our sons. I’ll remember that two years ago, I hated this holiday because I experienced severe loss of our two sons (they were reunified from our foster home, and brought back to us last year). And I reflect on how much can change in a year, or in a day, and how we almost lost our kids forever. How I started, after two years of not hearing from them or seeing them, finally taking down all their pictures and drawings that still decorated, and, in some ways, haunted our house. It felt like the right time to move on, to pack it all up, and focus what was in front of me. Until a few days later, when it wasn’t. Now, our fridge is full of their drawings; every frame filled with memories of our full, and complete, reunited and restored family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May is also Foster Care Awareness Month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m not sure who decides what months are awareness months, and why they chose May, but I can’t look past the irony (or intentionality) of Mother’s Day residing smack in the middle of a time to bring attention to orphans in our neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each Mother’s Day I’m faced with a challenge and a push back residing within myself—I feel unable and numb to fully enjoy the day since becoming a biological mom to my daughters, because I remember the loss of our two foster sons. Now that they are back with us, and that we are in the process of adoption, I can’t help but remember those days. Call it trauma or a grudge or whatever, but I call it perception, hindsight, and (growing) wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want to go back to days without grief present. I don’t want to let my grief rule or drive me, but I never want to forget that pain of yesterday because (a) my joy today is more genuine because of it and (b) because there are still 400,000 kids across the nation in limbo (aka the foster care system) and (c) I still have countless friends made because we shared this in common: we loved and lost children—whether through miscarriage, failed adoption, foster care, or all the other painful ways mothers have unwillingly said goodbye to someone tiny they loved dearly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must do better on this day. We must see others more. We must tread more carefully and intentionally in how we approach Mother’s Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must do better for foster kids. The 400,000 across the nation. The 20,000 throughout California; the 3,000 in Orange County. The ones who are emancipating to no home, who are finding shelter in a jail cell or finding love in a risky relationship. We are not doing enough and what we are doing now is not working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, let’s get creative. Let’s be awkward and ask questions of how to better love the moms that have lost. And let’s be vigilant and strong, and loud, and risky, for the ones who have no one speaking up for them this month. This is our month to do something, to say something and be shelter for the orphans who are our neighbors, and the mothers, who are our sisters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we do something?  I recommend getting to know more about these organizations that are doing good work. They need more people to join them and support them. Will you consider what role you can play?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://teenleadershipfoundation.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teen Leadership Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Teen Leadership Foundation works directly with the most vulnerable in our county by offering sustainable housing and empowering mentorships for foster youth that have aged out of the system’s support (usually at 18 years old).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ezrahshands.org/introducing-ezrahs-hands/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ezrah’s Hands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
Ezrah’s Hands assists kinship families (relatives or family friends that step in to provide stable loving homes for children whose parents are no longer able to care for them). Often times kinship families face additional hardships without any financial or community support by the system; these are the foster children and families that fall through the cracks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.home4good.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Home4Good&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
If you’re looking to buy or sell a house, this team of realtors lowers their own commission and uses the difference to fund adoptions and support foster families.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://safe-families.org/about/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safe Families&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Safe Families connects vulnerable children with temporary host families, preventing the need for foster care. They create extended-family–like supports for desperate families through a community of devoted volunteers to keep families together.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sally Kim</name></author><category term="foster care" /><category term="common good" /><category term="mother's day" /><category term="adoption" /><summary type="html">Spring is a season full of dichotomies. The weather has been extreme (at least here in Southern California)—two days ago it was nearing 90 degrees; today, it’s raining across Orange County. Flowers and Super Blooms and all that green and splashes of color are rising; as are everyone’s allergies. It’s a beautiful season, but it’s complicated and sometimes an irritant, as we adjust from the thrills of winter and navigate this season of now, and not yet, that is Spring.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/SallyRaeKim%20Headshot%20resized.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">3 Simple Ways to Conquer Writer’s Block</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/05/10/writers-block/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3 Simple Ways to Conquer Writer's Block" /><published>2017-05-10T08:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-10T08:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/05/10/writers-block</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/05/10/writers-block/">&lt;p&gt;The majority of my job is writing and editing. I like to write and I like to read. So, you’d think I’d be all about managing a blog, getting guest submissions, and writing posts. But lately I’ve let this blog go to the side. I’ve justified it as I’ve been focusing on other writing projects for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/goodbyehelloparty/&quot;&gt;new name reveal&lt;/a&gt; and for some exciting things coming up in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/startups/&quot;&gt;startup programs&lt;/a&gt;. The truth is I’m feeling a really big case of writer’s block lately. I have a whole lot of thoughts in my head, but when I go to put pen to paper (or fingers to keyboard) I feel stuck. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I was having an impromptu lunch with one of our members and we were catching up on life. Joanna Waterfall is the founder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://yellowco.co&quot;&gt;Yellow Co.&lt;/a&gt;, a company she started to bring together and equip creative entrepreneurial women to use their gifts and talents to be agents of good in the world. (If this is you…check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://yellowco.co/conference/&quot;&gt;The Yellow Conference&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://yellowcollective.co&quot;&gt;The Yellow Collective&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://yellowco.co/blog/&quot;&gt;the blog&lt;/a&gt;.) Joanna is also a graphic designer and does a fair amount of writing herself, so she seemed like a really good person to talk to about creative blocks and such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She asked how I was doing I told her I was having a hard time writing all of the things that I wanted to. She gave me a solid piece of very simple advice (she’s really good at that) and then my wheels got turning a little bit. So I’m passing along three very simple things that you can do today to help navigate the blocks that can often come when trying to produce good work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-do-something-even-if-it-is-horrible&quot;&gt;1. Do something, even if it is horrible.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a pretty well known idea in the writing world called a Bad First Draft (others have more colorful language for said first draft, but I’m keeping it G rated today). We often put so much pressure on ourselves to write something amazing right out of the gate. Joanna reminded me that writing something, even if it is terrible, is an essential element to forward movement. You’ll obviously need to go back and edit it, or perhaps change it almost entirely. But getting it out there is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept can obviously apply to more than writing. I recommend it for any form of work frustration. Getting something out there keeps things moving. And forward movement does more than just get something out there. It helps you keep at it, even when you want to throw in the towel. Be okay with something, even if its really, really bad. Then go back later and revise it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-step-away&quot;&gt;2. Step Away&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve gotten it out there, step away. Go do something else. Grab coffee, go for a walk, hit the gym, head to the beach. Whatever it is, do something that clears your mind and takes you away from what you wrote so you can go back and look at it with fresh eyes and a clearer mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-talk-to-someone&quot;&gt;3. Talk to someone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In taking to Joanna and my husband about my frustrations, they not only had some good and simple advice, but they were very encouraging. Never underestimate the value of others speaking into your experience, both practically and emotionally. Talking it out helped me articulate exactly what I was experiencing and also allowed others to give me a perspective outside my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it. A few tips on what to do when you just don’t think you can do it. Obviously writer’s block isn’t even close to among the most pressing problems in the world. But I think these principles can apply to so many more situations. When we work to bring goodness to the world, we’ll naturally face resistance in many forms. So keep doing something, take time to step away, talk to others, and then come back to it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jill Arbini</name></author><summary type="html">The majority of my job is writing and editing. I like to write and I like to read. So, you’d think I’d be all about managing a blog, getting guest submissions, and writing posts. But lately I’ve let this blog go to the side. I’ve justified it as I’ve been focusing on other writing projects for the new name reveal and for some exciting things coming up in our startup programs. The truth is I’m feeling a really big case of writer’s block lately. I have a whole lot of thoughts in my head, but when I go to put pen to paper (or fingers to keyboard) I feel stuck.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/annie-spratt-197448.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Goodbye Wayfare, Hello New Name</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/05/08/goodbye-wayfare-hello-new-name/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goodbye Wayfare, Hello New Name" /><published>2017-05-08T19:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-05-08T19:18:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/05/08/goodbye-wayfare-hello-new-name</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/05/08/goodbye-wayfare-hello-new-name/">&lt;p&gt;Remember back in January when &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/18/say-goodbye-to-wayfare/&quot;&gt;we announced we were changing our name&lt;/a&gt;?!?! We asked for your submissions, and you delivered! However, we’ve been kinda quiet about things on these here interwebs…our lawyers told us to be hush hush, and we decided to obey. But we’ve been at work behind the scenes deciding on a name&lt;!-- more --&gt;,(no big deal, except it took us a lot longer than we thought it would), doing a whole bunch of paperwork (blech!), designing a lot of fun stuff (yay!), staying up really late (yawn), and even crying some legit tears (boo!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah, we’ve also been recording every step of the way for a podcast all about how to pivot when an unexpected business challenge comes your way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time is coming to announce the new name! We’re throwing a party for the big reveal and we’ll be announcing a winner of the naming contest. It’s all happening on May 18th and we couldn’t be more excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will you join us for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/goodbyehelloparty/&quot;&gt;Goodbye Wayfare, Hello New Name Party&lt;/a&gt;? One party, two locations. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/goodbyehelloparty/&quot;&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt; to Fullerton or Costa Mesa. Free lunch. Be in the know. And help us spread the word. Wayfare will soon be…???&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jill Arbini</name></author><summary type="html">Remember back in January when we announced we were changing our name?!?! We asked for your submissions, and you delivered! However, we’ve been kinda quiet about things on these here interwebs…our lawyers told us to be hush hush, and we decided to obey. But we’ve been at work behind the scenes deciding on a name</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/7-18-16%20Wayfare%20Photos-160.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cultivating Curiosity: 6 Ways to be a Lifelong Learner</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/04/14/cultivating-curiousity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cultivating Curiosity: 6 Ways to be a Lifelong Learner" /><published>2017-04-14T13:20:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-14T13:20:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/04/14/cultivating-curiousity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/04/14/cultivating-curiousity/">&lt;p&gt;As a college student, most of my learning currently takes place inside a classroom or in a textbook assigned by my professors. I’m constantly pushed to improve my skills and strengthen my academic voice as I write papers and finish major projects. Throughout college, one of the most valuable things I have learned is to always seek truth and to raise questions, no matter how big or small they might be. 
&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once college is over, I am sure it’s easy to believe that the part of your life devoted to learning is over. Upon finishing a degree, learning could quickly become less of a priority in the face of job and family responsibilities. While the temptation to mold life into an anticipated routine is overwhelmingly strong, the choice to instead challenge yourself by continually pursuing curiosity throughout your adult life can yield incredible results and give you an excitement for life that is unmatched. I’ve watched others do this, and I strive to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve started to think about this process of what it means to cultivate curiosity in my life outside of college course requirements, I’ve thought about how to pursue my passions well. A little less than two years ago, I picked up a camera for the first time and began shooting pictures regularly. Now, photography is a great passion of mine because it’s such a beautiful storytelling mechanism. Photos connect people and create important memories that are imprinted in time. I didn’t learn to love photography through my college courses. I learned to love photography because I was interested in developing a skill and an interest at my own speed.
 
While cultivating curiosity looks different for each person, there are a few different tactics that I’ve found helpful which can make learning more attainable and realistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen-to-a-story-about-curiosity&quot;&gt;Listen to a story about curiosity!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out this episode from the podcast &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/soundsgoodpodcast/jedidiah-jenkins-the-adventure-of-curiosity&quot;&gt;“Sounds Good”&lt;/a&gt; where Branden Harvey talks with Jeremiah Jenkins on The Adventure of Curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;start-reading&quot;&gt;Start Reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this takes the form of New York Times articles (the opinion section is my favorite) and every book I can possibly acquire. It’s exciting to tackle another chapter and feel the satisfaction of finally closing a book you’ve worked hard to finish reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;at-the-end-of-every-day-write-down-a-few-new-things-you-have-learned&quot;&gt;At the end of every day, write down a few new things you have learned!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t learned something new, try challenging yourself the next day! Maybe it’s as simple as googling why almond milk is better for your morning coffee than half n’ half or recalling something new that you learned about a person you know. Even small changes to your routine and to your perspective can help broaden the way you see the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;travel&quot;&gt;Travel!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking opportunities (however small or limited) to have a change of scenery can greatly expand one’s perspective on the world by teaching you how to communicate with people who are different from you and by physically showing you a very different landscape and way of life. Perhaps this means you can explore a new town close to your home, or it means you decide to take the leap of traveling to Japan like you’ve always dreamed. Travel is also important because it’s an experience that begs you to repeat it. Once you’ve started the journey of exploring new and unique places, you’ll never want to stop. This is a great way to fuel curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;always-ask-questions&quot;&gt;Always Ask Questions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to always keep learning is to ask people for their advice, for their stories, for their struggles. Continuing to ask questions opens up a world of possibilities and helps you learn new ideas every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;take-risks&quot;&gt;Take Risks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s obviously a great importance in approaching life with wisdom and a good deal of consideration, but stepping outside what is normal, comfortable, and familiar often leads to the most life-changing results. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/startups/idea-weekend/&quot;&gt;Maybe this risk is to start exploring a new idea you have for creating a business!&lt;/a&gt; Maybe the risk is to apologize to that friend and start fresh. Taking risks is hard, but it continually stimulates your brain and pushes you to be a better person by strengthening your goals and your work ethic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While cultivating curiosity can be a challenge at times, it is worth all the effort to engage the world and continue growing as an individual. The commitment to learning is one that brings surprises with every turn. Knowledge is an empowering pursuit and helps bring big ideas to life. Don’t forget to dream big dreams and turn them into your next plans! That is what curiosity is really all about.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Erin Wilson</name></author><summary type="html">As a college student, most of my learning currently takes place inside a classroom or in a textbook assigned by my professors. I’m constantly pushed to improve my skills and strengthen my academic voice as I write papers and finish major projects. Throughout college, one of the most valuable things I have learned is to always seek truth and to raise questions, no matter how big or small they might be.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/Cultiating%20Curiousity.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Starting Somewhere</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/04/11/starting-somewhere/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting Somewhere" /><published>2017-04-11T17:03:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-04-11T17:03:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/04/11/starting-somewhere</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/04/11/starting-somewhere/">&lt;p&gt;Everyone starts somewhere, right? I had just graduated college and was ready for a new adventure. Having fallen in love with the city during previous travels, I thought, “Why not London?” I packed my bags and took off for a three-month internship across the pond. However, upon landing, I immediately asked myself, “What am I doing here?” In all my travel experience, I had never felt homesick before. But rather than letting myself drown in loneliness, I chose to be intentional about connecting with the people I missed back in Orange County by starting an online magazine so that my friends and I could process this life transition together. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started Skyping with a good friend, Jane (whom I lovingly refer to as my “co” because she basically saved my life when it came to building a website and creating an online presence). We picked a website theme, created an Instagram account, and called up all of our recently-graduated friends to ask them how they were processing life after college. After convincing them to write it all down, we released the very first issue of &lt;a href=&quot;http://whilstmagazine.com&quot;&gt;Whilst&lt;/a&gt; magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst (besides being obnoxiously English) is the word that resides right in the middle of a sentence, the place most people don’t dwell in because they want to get back to the action. It signifies transition—whilst traveling, whilst working, whilst sipping your tea: it’s the word that moves us from the present to the action. That is what we’re about—we want to act as a catalyst for present thinking, to encourage individuals to mindfully enter into their own process and learn the practice of empathizing with others on the same journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew I wanted to take Whilst farther, to really dive into what the magazine stood for and how I could create a career out of this growing passion. I frequently found myself on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io&quot;&gt;Wayfare website&lt;/a&gt;, and it was during the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/startups/idea-weekend/&quot;&gt;Idea Weekend&lt;/a&gt; that I learned how to articulate what Whilst really is and how it could change lives. That’s when I knew I wanted to be a part of a community that exists to change the world for good and create beauty in whatever life stage we are journeying through. The next step, then, was to continue to press into what my vision was for Whilst—how far could this concept of being present in the midst really go? Through sitting down and talking it out with the Wayfare coaches and other entrepreneurs, I found my dreams were bigger than I had imagined. I am continuing to develop and refine my leadership skills now as I continue in &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/startups/launch-program/&quot;&gt;Wayfare’s Launch program.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has officially been a year since I took off on a plane and began learning for myself what it means to live in the midst of the process and engage with transition. Whilst Magazine is one year old and we are coming up on our fourth release, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/whilstmagazine&quot;&gt;available by subscription&lt;/a&gt; on April 14th! (SO SOON!) I can’t begin to describe how much &lt;a href=&quot;http://whilstmagazine.com&quot;&gt;Whilst&lt;/a&gt; has grown in the last year, let alone the last few weeks at Wayfare, and I am so thankful to be here whilst experiencing it all.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Devon Johnson</name></author><category term="Whilst" /><category term="Magazine" /><category term="Travel" /><category term="Creative" /><category term="Writing" /><category term="Idea Weekend" /><category term="Launch Program" /><summary type="html">Everyone starts somewhere, right? I had just graduated college and was ready for a new adventure. Having fallen in love with the city during previous travels, I thought, “Why not London?” I packed my bags and took off for a three-month internship across the pond. However, upon landing, I immediately asked myself, “What am I doing here?” In all my travel experience, I had never felt homesick before. But rather than letting myself drown in loneliness, I chose to be intentional about connecting with the people I missed back in Orange County by starting an online magazine so that my friends and I could process this life transition together.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/Whilst.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Cultivating a Rhythm of Rest and Work</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/03/29/cultivating-a-rhythm-of-rest-and-work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cultivating a Rhythm of Rest and Work" /><published>2017-03-29T11:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-29T11:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/03/29/cultivating-a-rhythm-of-rest-and-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/03/29/cultivating-a-rhythm-of-rest-and-work/">&lt;p&gt;Simplicity, Sabbath, Kon Mari, Minimalism, Balance…being in the creative industry, primarily in the blogging world, I hear these words &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt;. Oh, you too? I’m not surprised. From the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Life-Changing-Magic-Tidying-Decluttering-Organizing/dp/1607747308/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1489519329&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=life+changing+magic+of+tidying+up&quot;&gt;Life Changing Magic of Tidying Up&lt;/a&gt; to [Capsule Wardrobes], to &lt;a href=&quot;https://minimalismfilm.com&quot;&gt;Documentaries&lt;/a&gt;…there seems to be an incessant hunt for slowness. Here’s the thing, simplicity and rest are not trends; they are absolute necessities for our survival. 
&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many, many opinions and how-to’s on creating space to rest. You can go through all your clothes and throw away whatever doesn’t spark joy (the Kon Mari Method) and download the latest productivity apps (I’m totally into &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/minimalist-task-reminder-to-do-list/id993066159?mt=8&quot;&gt;MinimaLIST&lt;/a&gt; right now), but unless we get to the root of our busyness and constant waves of rush, we will never fully enter into rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My husband is a worship pastor, we have two children under two, and three in school. I work &lt;a href=&quot;https://lettersfromamister.com/what-i-do-i-write/&quot;&gt;freelance as a writer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://heritage-mercantile-co.myshopify.com/collections/events&quot;&gt;teaching workshops&lt;/a&gt; and coaching for blogs and non-profits. His job can take him anywhere from one to ten nights a month, and leaves me alone on the weekends, and mine takes consistent creative juice-flow while wiping high chairs and scrubbing cherrios off the floor (ok, you can’t actually scrub cherrios, but you get the concept, right?)…and, in between all of this, we are called to rest. Yes. Called to rest. Let’s eliminate the buzzword balance and replace it with dance. It is absolutely necessary for us to find the dance, the harmony, between work, and rest, because, if we do not learn to rest well, we cannot impact the world with our work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of telling you a list of things you must do, eliminate, or check to create a rhythm of rest in your life, here are some tools I’ve learned as I journey through our chaotic, creative, and beautiful life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop putting pressure on yourself to rest.&lt;/strong&gt; This totally debunks the purpose of it. We get so tangled in knots about making sure we’re resting that we are stressed about getting rest (huh?). Instead, lay out what your ideal routine looks like, then lay out what your survival routine looks like. You will experience both in your life, and it can be a consistent, and, dare I say, beautiful ebb and flow between the two as you navigate through life. Everyday will not be ideal. In fact, most days will not be ideal. Most days, especially those with little people in their care, will be sheer chaos. It’s how we journey through those days that count.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light a Candle.&lt;/strong&gt; I am, however, a huge fan of the Sabbath, and believe it’s something we’re called to do. I believe Sabbath and day offs are two different beasts to tackle; that one is for oil changes and raking leaves, and the other is for pausing and letting life happen around you, while you completely let go of your daily agenda, responsibilities, and worries to worship. How we do this is, come Sunday afternoon, after the busiest time of week for us (remember, pastor family), we light a candle to initiate the end of busy and the beginning of Sabbath. I make the same meal in the crockpot every single Sunday, I clean the house deeply so that come Sunday night and Monday morning I can breathe and be present with my family without noticing the crumbs on the floor, I delete social media from my phone and have our kids turn off their devices and put them in a drawer. We shut down, gathering around the table with a candle resting in the middle, and play the question game, then gather in the living room for board games or reading, or just being quiet, but present, together.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create quiet hours.&lt;/strong&gt; One thing we love to do, and don’t do nearly enough, are quiet hours. I have carried this false belief for years that I must be able to do anything, everything, always. No matter how crazy the kids are, or how insane my husband’s ministry is, or how close my work deadlines are, I thought I needed to roll with it to show how strong I am. The reality is, rest reveals strength. I had to come to terms with the fact that I need set, sacred spaces of total silence, or I will lose my (insert appropriate emoji here). We decided to implement quiet hours with our kids after realizing (one) we hate screens and (two) kids hate life without screens. We believe in the power of boredom, and that creativity can spring from giving ourselves, and our loved ones, spaces without forced stimulation. So, in our ideal schedule, we have an hour a day of no screens and of total quiet. Sometimes we’ll have some easy music on, and this usually takes place during the toddler’s naptime. Each person is responsible for finding their own silent activity, whether it’s making paper airplanes, reading a book, scrolling through a blog (for me! It’s a rule bend because it’s an important way I experience rest), making a slow, pour over coffee. This is not family play time, this is not time to engage, but rather to step back so we can come together and be fully, fully present with each other when we do choose to reconnect. Our kids have come to love it so much that if we don’t have it for a few days, they actually start to ask for it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is absolutely necessary for us to find the dance, the harmony, between work, and rest, because, if we do not learn to rest well, we cannot impact the world with our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, there is no simple formula or perfect way to create rhythms of rest in our lives. There are tools and opinions that can be helpful, but don’t bombard yourself with research in a hunt for the perfect experience. The secret, my secret, is to accept the season of life you are in at the present, and embrace what the dance between work and rest looks like for you today. Recognize your ideal rhythm, and implement a variation of that into your current season. By implementing sacred space to rest, your work will be more impactful and life-giving for not only yourself, but the world you are serving.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sally Kim</name></author><category term="rest" /><category term="minimalism" /><summary type="html">Simplicity, Sabbath, Kon Mari, Minimalism, Balance…being in the creative industry, primarily in the blogging world, I hear these words a lot. Oh, you too? I’m not surprised. From the Life Changing Magic of Tidying Up to [Capsule Wardrobes], to Documentaries…there seems to be an incessant hunt for slowness. Here’s the thing, simplicity and rest are not trends; they are absolute necessities for our survival.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/ValerieDenisePhotos(38of64).jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wearing Many Hats: The Reality of Work and Business</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/03/23/wearing-many-hats-the-reality-of-work-and-business/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wearing Many Hats: The Reality of Work and Business" /><published>2017-03-23T22:05:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-23T22:05:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/03/23/wearing-many-hats-the-reality-of-work-and-business</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/03/23/wearing-many-hats-the-reality-of-work-and-business/">&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.strengthsfinder.com/home.aspx&quot;&gt;Strengths Finder 2.0&lt;/a&gt; (of which I am a huge fan), my top strength is &lt;strong&gt;Achiever&lt;/strong&gt;. So when a day goes by where I haven’t achieved all of the things that I set out to do in a day, I have a hard time feeling like I have accomplished anything at all. This tends to be a problem for me because as the cofounder of a small, but growing organization, I know what it is like to have an entire day go by and to be left wondering where all of my time went! At the end of the day, even if I’ve been productive and I’ve clearly made progress in several small areas, if I spent very little time executing on my primary objectives it can feel defeating.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the things I’ve had to do as I’ve started and run various companies are: run payroll, file DBAs, register domain names, pay bills, build websites, create financial projections, open bank accounts, pull together tax information, communicate with lawyers, act as tech support, communicate with investors, mop up spills, schedule meetings, book travel plans, manage inventory, develop content, ideate on revenue streams, speak at events, pitch investors, order soap dispensers, plunge toilets, install thermostats, run sound, and build furniture. The list could go on, but you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Obviously the specific tasks you have to juggle vary depending on the nature of your business or organization and your role. But the reality is, you wear many hats. &lt;strong&gt;It it the nature of running a business. It is the nature of freelance work. It is the nature of starting something new. And it can be overwhelming.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this to say, I’m sure many of you can resonate with attempting to juggle the many things that go into running the various aspects of your business. Some you love, some you don’t. But you do them all, because they’re necessary for you to do… at least at first. We tell founders in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/startups/&quot;&gt;Launch program&lt;/a&gt; that whether you plan to stay small or grow, &lt;strong&gt;having your hand in everything at the beginning is an essential part of the process for the long run&lt;/strong&gt;. After having done many of the things, as time has gone on I’ve been able to better navigate exactly what to do myself, what to hire out, and who to hire to do some of these things. But having done many of them at first, helped me know who to hire for specific roles. It’s also helped me understand which methods and tools I use to help me manage what I need to get done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love learning about new methods and user-friendly web-based tools that can can help me manage all of the different categories of tasks that I find myself completing. However, researching the best methods and tools &lt;strong&gt;just takes more time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I’m thrilled to share this free downloadable guide called &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.activehosted.com/f/18&quot;&gt;16 Apps &amp;amp; Strategies for Streamlining Your Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that was written by one of our coworking members, &lt;a href=&quot;http://setterstudios.com&quot;&gt;Brandon Setter&lt;/a&gt;, filmmaker and unofficial king of efficiency. These are his current tried-and-true favorites. The descriptions and research have been done for you so you can just focus on doing your best work. But first &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.activehosted.com/f/18&quot;&gt;sign up to get the guide emailed to you&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brandon Arbini</name></author><category term="business" /><category term="freelance" /><category term="small business" /><category term="owner" /><category term="founder" /><category term="achiever" /><category term="tasks" /><category term="roles" /><category term="hiring" /><category term="apps" /><category term="efficiency" /><category term="automation" /><category term="tools" /><summary type="html">According to the Strengths Finder 2.0 (of which I am a huge fan), my top strength is Achiever. So when a day goes by where I haven’t achieved all of the things that I set out to do in a day, I have a hard time feeling like I have accomplished anything at all. This tends to be a problem for me because as the cofounder of a small, but growing organization, I know what it is like to have an entire day go by and to be left wondering where all of my time went! At the end of the day, even if I’ve been productive and I’ve clearly made progress in several small areas, if I spent very little time executing on my primary objectives it can feel defeating.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/16-apps-and-strategies-for-streamlining-your-work.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Voice of Comparison (and How to Stop it)</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/21/the-voice-of-comparison-and-how-to-stop-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Voice of Comparison (and How to Stop it)" /><published>2017-02-21T05:43:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-21T05:43:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/21/the-voice-of-comparison-and-how-to-stop-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/21/the-voice-of-comparison-and-how-to-stop-it/">&lt;p&gt;There’s a not so subtle voice that wells up inside of me more often than I’d like to admit. It’s the ugly voice of comparison. This voice leads to one of two problematic feelings for me: inferiority or superiority. Because the truth about comparison is that it goes both ways. It’s the voice that says what I do doesn’t matter, because someone else is doing something better. It is the voice that minimizes what others do because I don’t see the value in it or understand it. It’s the voice that tells me I don’t have anything to offer because I don’t have everything together. It’s the voice that also says I don’t need to feel too bad about my shortcomings, because at least I’m not quite as much of a mess as so-and-so. But today I’d like to boldly declare, regardless of what it says, &lt;strong&gt;the voice of comparison is a liar.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason we compare ourselves to others, for better or for worse, is ultimately because we want our lives to matter. I know that I am not alone in this and so today I’d like to invite you to join me in listening to a different voice. One that doesn’t guide us to a place of self-deprecation &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; to a place of arrogance, but to a place of considering the unique role that we each have. This voice asks the question, &lt;strong&gt;“What is your best contribution to the world?”&lt;/strong&gt; The answer to this question is always the same answer. For everyone. No matter what. The answer to the question, “What is your best contribution to the world?”, is quite simply, ‘You.” &lt;strong&gt;Your best contribution to the world is you.&lt;/strong&gt; Your abilities, your resources and talents, and your relationships and experiences are uniquely yours. And that matters. You can contribute to the world by doing what you can, with what you have, where you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s no need to compare yourself to somebody else in order to determine how much you matter, because the world needs you to be &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now that we have that cleared up. We face another question.  What happens if I don’t quite know what my abilities, resources or talents are?  What if I can’t make sense of the place I currently am or the relationships I currently have? Here’s the fun part. You go on an adventure of self discovery and try things out. Here are a few ways to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-what-you-like-to-do&quot;&gt;Find What You Like to Do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identify some activities or hobbies that you like. Find others that share those interests and build relationships with them. Here are a few ideas to start: Join a book club, attend a workout class, gather friends for a monthly supper club, sign up for a class or workshop, play basketball with some friends, play the guitar, learn a new craft that you’ve always wanted to try, take your dog to a dog park, take a walk around your neighborhood and talk to your neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find ways you can use what you like to better the life of someone else. Love to cook? Bring someone a meal. Love a certain sport? Gather some friends for an intramural league or volunteer to coach a youth team or help at a sports camp. Enjoy gardening? What neighbor or coworker wouldn’t love a homegrown bouquet or a few fresh tomatoes or oranges? Find something that you like and consider how to bless others or invite others in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;identify-your-strengths&quot;&gt;Identify Your Strengths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/StrengthsFinder-2-0-Tom-Rath/dp/159562015X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1487737297&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=strengths+finder+2.0&quot;&gt;The Strengths Finder 2.0&lt;/a&gt; is a great book and comes with a code that gives you access to a highly comprehensive online assessment tool to help you identify your strengths. The basic premise of this book is that we often can identify our short-comings easily and spend a lot of effort to overcome them.  However, there are parts of us where we naturally excel and most of our effort should go toward developing our strengths. At Wayfare, we use this book in our &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/startups/&quot;&gt;startup incubator&lt;/a&gt; and have found that it’s worth every penny. (And we don’t get paid a penny to promote this book. We just really love it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;contribute-in-everyday-life&quot;&gt;Contribute in Everyday Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may or may not be living where you want to, working where you want to, or are at the place you thought you’d be at this point in your life. Either way, no matter where you are, you can contribute to the world.  Your neighbors, your friends, your coworkers, your family and the people in your city can benefit from the fact that you are in their lives. My friend recently left a couple of balloons and a nice card with a treat attached for each of her neighbors in their driveways as they got home from work. Another person I know lives in a third-world country, doesn’t have running water, and helps provide medical care to people in her community.  Some other friends of mine love babies and step in to &lt;a href=&quot;http://safe-families.org&quot;&gt;help families in crisis&lt;/a&gt; by temporarily caring for their children. Another friend of mine makes school lunches for her boys. She’s started offering to make lunches for their classmates as well. Moms take her up on it and when asked why she does it she says, “Because I can. And if I’m doing it anyway I might as well make someone else’s life easier by helping them out.” &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facesofsantaana.com&quot;&gt;Someone else I know&lt;/a&gt; befriends people experiencing homelessness, uses his skills as an artist to paint their portraits, sells the paintings, and uses the funds to help his friends in a tangible way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me? Today, I made meals for my family, washed their clothes, and helped my son with math. Obviously I wrote a blog post too. It’s my hope that in my family they know they are loved and in turn, they love others. It’s my hope that in my writing, I can encourage others. I also went to the chiropractor. Because I have to take care of myself too. It isn’t much, but it isn’t &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; much, you know? It’s just me. Because it’s what &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; have to offer.  To my family, to my community, to myself in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We each have our roles. And they each matter. Let’s say ‘no’ to the voice of comparison, and ‘yes’ to contributing to the world in our own unique ways.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jill Arbini</name></author><category term="creativity" /><category term="purpose" /><category term="ideas" /><category term="world" /><category term="homeless" /><category term="strengths" /><category term="relationships" /><summary type="html">There’s a not so subtle voice that wells up inside of me more often than I’d like to admit. It’s the ugly voice of comparison. This voice leads to one of two problematic feelings for me: inferiority or superiority. Because the truth about comparison is that it goes both ways. It’s the voice that says what I do doesn’t matter, because someone else is doing something better. It is the voice that minimizes what others do because I don’t see the value in it or understand it. It’s the voice that tells me I don’t have anything to offer because I don’t have everything together. It’s the voice that also says I don’t need to feel too bad about my shortcomings, because at least I’m not quite as much of a mess as so-and-so. But today I’d like to boldly declare, regardless of what it says, the voice of comparison is a liar.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/comparison-blog-resized.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">“But What Do I Doooo?”: The Case for a Strong Mission Statement</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/19/but-what-do-i-doooo-the-case-for-a-strong-mission-statement/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="&quot;But What Do I Doooo?&quot;: The Case for a Strong Mission Statement" /><published>2017-02-19T17:27:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-19T17:27:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/19/but-what-do-i-doooo-the-case-for-a-strong-mission-statement</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/19/but-what-do-i-doooo-the-case-for-a-strong-mission-statement/">&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite movies is Disney’s “The Kid”. In the scene where big Russ is trying to explain his job as an image consultant and little Rusty is trying to understand what that means, he looks up and in a childish, drawn out tone says, “But what do I doooo?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This very phrase and in Rusty’s tone went through my head about 1,000 times as we started exploring re-articulating our mission statement. I was newly hired as the Executive Director of Mika Community Development Corporation but had been a part of the organization for 11 of our 12 years. Our work wasn’t changing but we needed to clarify and focus the most core part of our work, our mission.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, Mika’s mission statement read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mika exists to identify and equip leaders from low-income neighborhoods to build communities with VISION (Vision, Interdependent Relationships with God and with each other, Servant Leadership, Impact, Organization, and Networks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was not a bad mission statement. It served us well and directed our work for over a decade. However, besides myself and the previous Executive Director, no one could remember the thing. You’d ask 10 people what Mika did and you’d get 10 different answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to tell you this process of asking, “But what do we dooooo?” was simple and fast. But as with most things that are good, it took time. A lot of time. Just over a year to be exact. This was not a process to be rushed and clarifying the core problem we were addressing was the ONLY way we were going to know if our solutions were actually solving anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can be scary, because what if the answer is no? &lt;strong&gt;What if you get really clear on the problem only to find what you’ve been doing isn’t really solving the core problem?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my 12 years of working with and for multiple non-profits, I’ve seen that we’re often afraid of asking the hard questions. It could affect our funding. It could mean stopping or changing long term programs. It could mean saying no to funds that don’t align with our mission. It could mean people choosing not to partner with you anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many of you starting something new, this could also mean that your idea looks different than what you have been thinking about for years. But the freedom of clarity and focus far outweighs the anxieties and frustrations that come from lack of clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mika’s work draws heavily from Bryant Myers’ book “Walking With the Poor” where he presents the idea of relational poverty and its effect on economic poverty. He suggests that “poverty is a result of relationships that do not work, that are not just, that are not for life, that are not harmonious or enjoyable. Poverty is the absence of Shalom in all its meanings.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was made more accessible by the popular “When Helping Hurts” and explores the effects of the breakdown in relationship of our four primary relationships – our relationships with God, with self, with others, and with the rest of creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had been using this language to explain the core problem we were addressing and justify how we work, but hadn’t connected that the way we articulated our mission spoke more to strategy than mission fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leadership Development and Community Building (our core strategies) are wonderful things but they are tools to fulfilling a larger mission. We identified early on in the process that our core mission had to be articulated in relationship terms. If you’ve ever wordsmithed something for so long it makes your brain hurt, you’ll understand how we were feeling after months of not landing on something concrete. I could walk you through all the versions and would be happy to if you contact me directly, but where we finally landed was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mika exists to build whole relationships in Costa Mesa.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be fooled by the simplicity of this statement. There was a lot of time (and tears) that went into the final iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clarity this statement brought to me and to our team was incredible. It created a clear lens to evaluate every single thing we do. We asked: does this program build wholeness in relationship with God, self, or others? For 80% of what we did the answer was a resounding YES! If the answer was no, another set of questions followed. Not fitting into our core mission didn’t automatically mean we needed to stop doing something, but clarified what questions we should be asking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two of the hardest decisions I’ve made as Executive Director were closing a community center and changing a 10 year Christmas tradition that had become an institution in our city. I realized that even the most beautiful community development work can become a part of sustaining a need that has changed or may not even exist anymore. Once we became really clear on the problem we were addressing (broken relationships) we had to make sure our solutions (strategies and programs) were completely in line. To sum this up in one short post is oversimplifying a very difficult and timely process, but as one that’s still in it (and will hopefully always be asking the hard questions) I’m here to tell you it’s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I participated in Wayfare’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/startups/idea-weekend/&quot;&gt;Idea Weekend&lt;/a&gt; from a different perspective than most of the people in the room. I wasn’t starting something brand new but had a new idea for our already existing organization. We had done a lot of the above mentioned work and started asking some specific questions regarding funding and sustainability. It was inspiring to be with 14 other people who were vulnerable enough to ask the hard questions and do the hard work of clarifying their problem in order to know what the best solutions were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As was the case with many people in the room, what I started thinking was the problem was only scratching the surface and attending the Idea Weekend helped me to clarify.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What seems like a very scary and hard process of questioning is totally worth it in the end when you’re willing to do the work. Well done for diving in.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Keturah Kennedy</name></author><category term="startups" /><category term="startup" /><category term="insight" /><category term="mission" /><category term="statement" /><category term="why" /><category term="mika" /><category term="costa mesa" /><category term="the kid" /><category term="non-profit" /><category term="social enterprise" /><category term="when helping hurts" /><category term="leadership" /><category term="clarity" /><category term="focus" /><category term="sustainability" /><category term="funding" /><summary type="html">One of my favorite movies is Disney’s “The Kid”. In the scene where big Russ is trying to explain his job as an image consultant and little Rusty is trying to understand what that means, he looks up and in a childish, drawn out tone says, “But what do I doooo?” This very phrase and in Rusty’s tone went through my head about 1,000 times as we started exploring re-articulating our mission statement. I was newly hired as the Executive Director of Mika Community Development Corporation but had been a part of the organization for 11 of our 12 years. Our work wasn’t changing but we needed to clarify and focus the most core part of our work, our mission.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/but-what-do-i-do.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Coworking as Team? 3 Reasons Why it’s Good for You, Your Team &amp;amp; Your Organization</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/08/an-office-inside-an-office/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coworking as  Team?  3 Reasons Why it's Good for You, Your Team &amp; Your Organization" /><published>2017-02-08T05:06:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-08T05:06:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/08/an-office-inside-an-office</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/02/08/an-office-inside-an-office/">&lt;p&gt;You started something! That’s a big deal. Whether you’ve been at it for awhile or you are just starting out, you might find yourself exploring the idea of moving to your own office space. Next step…secure a lease, right? Maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve asked a few of the members that work out Wayfare full time why they have chosen to have their offices and build their team inside of the a shared workspace environment rather than in their own private office space. A few main themes came up: &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/membership/&quot;&gt;The Community&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/membership/faq/&quot;&gt;The Flexibility&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.io/startups/&quot;&gt;Business Opportunities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-community-for-you-and-your-team&quot;&gt;The Community (for you and your team)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We love having our own personal space, but I also love seeing how my team is part of the greater community of people within Wayfare. The community here is like-minded, which is a huge deal. They care about people and I think it helps my team have a better work experience than we’d have if our team was isolated in our own space without interaction and encouragement from others…It’s more than a workspace, it’s a family.”-Jon F., &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cappital.co&quot;&gt;Cappital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I came from working alone in a windowless office to a place where there is life happening to the fullest. I no longer leave my day exhausted and drained, but with new ideas, new questions, and a new sense of energy to take me into the next day.-Erica N., &lt;a href=&quot;http://redemptionchurch.org&quot;&gt;Redemption Church&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wayfare fosters a unique culture and brings together a big family. This aligns with the philosophy that’s deeply rooted in [our] business.-Han L., &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moraleagency.com&quot;&gt;Morale Agency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wholeheartedly agree! Running your own business or organization is hard and can be draining. It is great to be able to share some of the things that are going on in your work and receive encouragement from others who have walked or are walking the same path. Sometimes all you need is the encouragement to keep going or some insight that you’d likely never come up with on your own. That is where being surrounded by other people outside of your own organization is a huge help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;flexibility-in-team-growth&quot;&gt;Flexibility in Team Growth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When you are starting something new and growing your team it is impossible to know how quickly or how slowly you’ll grow. The month-to-month flexibility and the ability to add employees as we grow is the perfect solution for us. We don’t need to keep moving offices as we add more people. We keep our dedicated office and just add employees who can work out of the main coworking space and the office.-Jon. F., &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cappital.co&quot;&gt;Cappital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have a dedicated office space at Wayfare you are welcome to work in the main workspace as well. This is a great option if you are looking for a change of scenery or to accommodate a growing team.  As you make new hires, you can easily add them on without needing to move offices. At Wayfare you aren’t committed to an office lease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;opportunities-for-collaboration-and-business-growth&quot;&gt;Opportunities for Collaboration and Business Growth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“To put it simply, Neat Coffee would not currently exist without Wayfare. Not only have you provided me with a space in which to test out my dreams, but you have been so supportive and helpful from the second the idea was born. From creating projections for my business, to giving great advice on a weekly basis…you have played an integral role in making Neat Coffee successful.-Ally G., &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neat.coffee&quot;&gt;Neat Coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Having the ability to make connections and interact with people within the greater coworking community provides natural ways to connect and grow our business, gain customers and connections, and explore new ideas. Being a part of this community allows us to get to know other people who can speak into what we are doing and see things from a new perspective because they have an outside point of view that we don’t have.-Jon F., &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cappital.co&quot;&gt;Cappital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have  so many have stories of people within the workspace and the greater advisor network helping each other out with projects, gaining business through connections with fellow members, and receiving insight on how to run their organization more effectively by rubbing shoulders with others. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.typeform.com/to/YW0Nce&quot;&gt;Let us know&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interested in having a private office at Wayfare. We’d love to show you around!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jill Arbini</name></author><category term="work" /><category term="startups" /><category term="community" /><category term="office" /><summary type="html">You started something! That’s a big deal. Whether you’ve been at it for awhile or you are just starting out, you might find yourself exploring the idea of moving to your own office space. Next step…secure a lease, right? Maybe not. We’ve asked a few of the members that work out Wayfare full time why they have chosen to have their offices and build their team inside of the a shared workspace environment rather than in their own private office space. A few main themes came up: The Community, The Flexibility, and Business Opportunities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/coworking-as-a-team.jpg" /></entry></feed>