<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-09-07T16:59:30+00:00</updated><id>/</id><title>Wayfare</title><entry><title>4 Reasons Why We’re Excited to Share Our New Website</title><link href="/stories/2016/09/01/4-reasons-why-were-excited-to-share-our-new-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4 Reasons Why We&#39;re Excited to Share Our New Website" /><published>2016-09-01T22:14:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-09-01T22:14:00+00:00</updated><id>/stories/2016/09/01/4-reasons-why-were-excited-to-share-our-new-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="/stories/2016/09/01/4-reasons-why-were-excited-to-share-our-new-website/">&lt;p&gt;After a two month labor of love, we couldn’t be more excited to share the new Wayfare website with you today. Here are four reasons why…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-represents-two-years-of-growth---and-our-community-today&quot;&gt;1. It represents two years of growth - and our community today&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wayfare launched two years ago with an idea, a logo, a website with rates, an email address, and 5 wonderful coworking members (that are still with us today… shout out to the original 5! Love you all). What we lacked in space, furniture, members, and coworking expertise, we made up for in tireless drive, countless brainstorm meetings, lean flexibility, a readiness to fail and try again, and a steadfast vision for what Wayfare would be.
 
In the early days, we used to dream of a space filled with people committed to using their unique gifts to advance &lt;a href=&quot;/about/common-good&quot;&gt;the common good&lt;/a&gt;. We envisioned a space that went far beyond desks to park your laptop, but one that awakened people to their true calling and restored the culture of work. We dreamed of a community that would value and support one another, would be eager to work and partner together for the common good… and ultimately, a community that would give birth to new dreams and movements that drive social change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had the joy of seeing these visions for Wayfare not only come to life but become the daily norm in this space. On any weekday at Wayfare, you’ll encounter people collaborating and ideating over coffee, writing, pitching new startups in our &lt;a href=&quot;/startups&quot;&gt;startup programs&lt;/a&gt;, mentoring, working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.wayfare.io/2016/07/11/member-monday-emily-mclaughlin/&quot;&gt;alleviating poverty in Africa&lt;/a&gt;,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cappital.co&quot;&gt;building apps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.softboot.org&quot;&gt;creating engineering jobs for emancipated youth&lt;/a&gt;, designing, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.wayfare.io/2016/04/25/member-monday-bailey-van-tassel-of-abel-impact/&quot;&gt;helping companies develop powerful giving strategies&lt;/a&gt;, coaching, and eating ice cream over a game of cornhole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are inspired every day by this &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt;, the work created here, and the common thread of shared values for a better world- but our website didn’t have the same affect. Somewhere in the midst of two years of growth, building products and systems, refining Wayfare’s business model, serving our members, and consuming copious amounts of coffee, &lt;strong&gt;our website and branding took the back seat&lt;/strong&gt;. As our staff and membership has grown, it has become a top priority for us to create a new website that represents the dynamic, dimensional identity of &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;our community&lt;/a&gt; today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-shows-how-were-unique&quot;&gt;2. It shows how we’re unique&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get us wrong here. We love coworking, workshops, gatherings, and startups… but it’s the common mission and thread that binds them all together that really drives what we do. We’re not just in this for the ergonomic chairs or the leftover eucalyptus garlands… we’re in this to advance &lt;a href=&quot;/about/common-good&quot;&gt;the common good&lt;/a&gt;, to make the world a better place, to empower others, and to pursue the world’s best future… together. We’re excited to share this mission with you- and invite you to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the design aspect of the  website was important, the  website rebrand was less centered on the aesthetics as it was about communicating Wayfare’s unique mission and &lt;a href=&quot;/about/values&quot;&gt;community values&lt;/a&gt;. We put pen to paper, defined and refined who we are, and invited our members, friends, and clients to be a part of it… because they truly are the reason this community is what it is today. We’re excited for you to &lt;a href=&quot;/about/our-model&quot;&gt;read what they had to say&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;its-visual-and-fun-like-our-community&quot;&gt;3. It’s visual and fun (like our community)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design is such a key element in making a brand’s identity and energy come to life, and we’re excited for a new website and branding that portrays the inviting, adventurous, and communal spirit that embodies &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;the Wayfare community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a rebrand entails much more than slapping on a new logo, we decided it was a great place to start. Our first logo was great for the initial season, and we’re excited to carry forward it’s clean minimalism and the accelerating lines that depict “wayfaring” or journeying. The new logo represents this same adventurous spirit, with added warmth and fluidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the logo, we weaved this same sentiment throughout all the other design aspects of the new  website. We did this in a few ways: incorporating more color and adding a new color palette, becoming more visual in our storytelling, incorporating the adventurous, entrepreneurial spirit of the Wayfare community through adventure themed icons, and adding more white space to let our products speak for themselves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-shows-where-were-going-and-were-going-places&quot;&gt;4. It shows where we’re going… and we’re going places&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main drivers of our website overhaul was the rapid growth of the Wayfare coworking community. In two short years we’ve grown from 6 to 102 coworking members and our private offices are filled with small organizations that have become family (and there’s a waiting list)! We’ve hosted over one hundred gatherings from workshops to fundraiser dinners, birthed eight startups (and are launching four more in December), and have grown from a staff of three  to eleven. Our &lt;a href=&quot;/locations/costa-mesa&quot;&gt;HQ space&lt;/a&gt; is nearly at capacity and we not only needed a more robust website to handle the growth, but &lt;strong&gt;we needed to expand&lt;/strong&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve never been the type to shy away from a challenge and are always seeking ways to serve and empower more people, so we started brainstorming expansion. For us, expansion is not (and will never be) about fame or fortune. While we will always strive for global impact, expansion is not about beating competitors, having a distinguished world-class name, or swimming in profit. It’s always been about the common good. It’s about creating the most good for all people, empowering hungry leaders, giving birth to creation restoring movements, providing safe places for community to flourish, helping people walk into their true calling, and about building a world where the most vulnerable thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We thoughtfully decided that the best way to achieve our mission and maximum impact was to launch a &lt;a href=&quot;/membership&quot;&gt;new membership model&lt;/a&gt; and expand to more &lt;a href=&quot;/locations&quot;&gt;locations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a straightforward yet powerful next step for growth, a timely response to current demand, and a solution that is already proven in the marketplace. Our &lt;a href=&quot;/membership&quot;&gt;new membership&lt;/a&gt; now allows us to be more inclusive of our global market, provide practical and relational resources for those who don’t necessarily need workspace, and provide more flexibility (and locations) for those that do. To support this growth, we needed a website and platform that could handle multiple locations and streamline our services, as well as make the critical shift from a local coworking space to a global community that enables us to welcome more world changers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoy the new site &amp;amp; that it inspires and drives you towards a life of greater impact. &lt;a href=&quot;/membership&quot;&gt;Looking for community&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;/locations&quot;&gt;Need a workspace&lt;/a&gt;? &lt;a href=&quot;/startups&quot;&gt;Have an idea you’d like to turn into reality&lt;/a&gt;? We’d love to learn more about you, and we openly welcome any website &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.typeform.com/to/vn3h2H&quot;&gt;feedback and suggestions&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Caitlin Kraina</name></author><category term="website" /><category term="growth" /><category term="rebrand" /><category term="brand" /><category term="logo" /><summary>After a two month labor of love, we couldn&#39;t be more excited to share the new Wayfare website with you today. Somewhere in the midst of two years of growth, building products and systems, refining Wayfare&#39;s business model, serving our members, and consuming copious amounts of coffee, our website and branding took the back seat. As our staff and membership has grown, it has become a top priority for us to create a new website that represents the dynamic, dimensional identity of our community today.</summary></entry><entry><title>Our Kids, Our Future</title><link href="/stories/2016/08/29/our-kids-our-future/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our Kids, Our Future" /><published>2016-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/stories/2016/08/29/our-kids-our-future</id><content type="html" xml:base="/stories/2016/08/29/our-kids-our-future/">&lt;p&gt;The 2016-2017 school year is upon us and while Back to School is top of mind, we’re featuring various action steps that can be taken to support the kids, teachers, parents, and schools in our community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many ways that any person can use what they have to contribute to the flourishing of our kids.  Today we are focusing on several ways to support kids in our area where &lt;strong&gt;we each can play a role in raising up the next generation of leaders, creators, innovators, and world-changers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-hope-alliancewwwprojecthopeallianceorg-costa-mesa&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.projecthopealliance.org&quot;&gt;Project Hope Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, Costa Mesa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to their website, “Childhood homelessness is Orange County’s best-kept secret. Under its veil of affluence are the faces of more than 26,000 children experiencing homelessness and 126,000 children living in poverty. They say goodnight from motels, shelters, and couches.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Housing and education are inextricably linked to each other, but there is hope. By stabilizing families in their own homes and providing their children with an exceptional education, we can and will break the cycle of homelessness.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Step One // Volunteer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serve &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.projecthopealliance.org/secondsaturday/&quot;&gt;Second Saturdays&lt;/a&gt;: Second Saturdays are quarterly opportunities to help their offices with a range of projects, such as organizing the food pantry, stuffing backpacks, working on administrative tasks, or creating crafts or art projects for kids they serve. This help, although simple, is significantly far-reaching. These volunteer days are a time for individuals of all ages (even small kids), families, and groups to connect with Project Hope Alliance’s staff and mission while supporting the families they serve. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.projecthopealliance.org/secondsaturday/&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for more info or email &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#110;&amp;#110;&amp;#105;&amp;#101;&amp;#064;&amp;#112;&amp;#114;&amp;#111;&amp;#106;&amp;#101;&amp;#099;&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#108;&amp;#105;&amp;#097;&amp;#110;&amp;#099;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;&quot;&gt;Connie&lt;/a&gt; with any questions or to sign you or your group up to volunteer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Step Two // In-Kind Gifts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While financial donations are always appreciated, gifts of items, also known as in-kind gifts are also appreciated.  Their needs are frequently changing, so for an up to date list of current needs please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.projecthopealliance.org/in-kind-gifts/&quot;&gt;Project Hope webpage about in-kind gifts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-literacy-project-foundationhttpliteracyprojectfoundationorg-newport-beach-ca&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://literacyprojectfoundation.org&quot;&gt;The Literacy Project Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, Newport Beach, CA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact: Kimberly Vig&lt;br /&gt;
Email: kim@literacyprojectfoundation.org&lt;br /&gt;
Office Phone: 949.721.1319&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;http://literacyprojectfoundation.org&quot;&gt;The Literacy Project Website&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Currently 45 million Americans are functionally illiterate and cannot read above a 5th grade level.              50% of adults cannot read a book written at an 8th grade level.
57% of students failed the California Standards Test in English. 1/3 of fourth-graders reach the proficient reading level. 25% of six million kids in California school systems are able to perform basic reading skills. 85% of juvenile offenders have problems reading. 3 out of 5 people in American prisons can’t read. 3 out of 4 people on welfare can’t read
(Sources: National Institute for Literacy, National Center for Adult Literacy, The Literacy Company, U.S. Census Bureau).”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://literacyprojectfoundation.org&quot;&gt;The Literacy Project&lt;/a&gt; is leading the charge against growing illiteracy amongst school-age children. They are bridging the literacy gap by serving the literacy needs of struggling 2nd grade readers…the early makings of an at-risk student who may end up illiterate and lose all hope of living a productive adult life.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://literacyprojectfoundation.org&quot;&gt;The Literacy Project&lt;/a&gt; offers a comprehensive instructional program that improves both academic and attitudinal levels of students performing far below English proficiency standards. The program is aligned with Common Core and collaborative learning methods, and is administered by Master Teachers who are product-trained experts and highly credentialed as reading and language arts specialists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program is provided at no cost to both the school and qualified students in the 2nd grade. This program teaches the fundamental principles of phonics in all three learning modalities - auditory, visual and tactile - critical to children with varying learning styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their significant measurable results prove increased reading skill levels of up to 75% and positive increases in building self-esteem and better attitudes towards reading of up to 85%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Step // Donate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsor a struggling reader, donate toward expanding this unique program in all local elementary schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wilson-street-learning-center-costa-mesa&quot;&gt;Wilson Street Learning Center, Costa Mesa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilson St. Learning Center (WSLC) was formed in 2009 to provide a safe and comprehensive place for kids to go after school. The WSLC mission includes not just academic guidance but also meets the spiritual, physical, and emotional needs of the students that live nearby. Parents are an essential part of the WSLC and volunteer in the community through parenting classes, ESL, or joining nearby Wilson Elementary School’s PTA. Nearly 100 families participate and enroll their families in the opportunities at WSLC. After-school tutoring is every day from 3-5pm. Parenting classes are offered every Thursday evening 7-9pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Step&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get involved by becoming one of the following: after-school grade level academic volunteer, coach sports, give prayer support, donate classroom supplies and sports equipment, help paint classrooms, and assist with parent ESL classes at night. Financial contributions to continue all these programs, fund scholarships for graduating students, and add academic coordinators would be graciously received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact: Olga Parra&lt;br /&gt;
Email &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#111;&amp;#108;&amp;#103;&amp;#097;&amp;#119;&amp;#115;&amp;#108;&amp;#099;&amp;#064;&amp;#121;&amp;#097;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#111;&amp;#108;&amp;#103;&amp;#097;&amp;#119;&amp;#115;&amp;#108;&amp;#099;&amp;#064;&amp;#121;&amp;#097;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Phone: 949.630.6071&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;back-to-school-improv-night-fundraiserhttpswayfareticketleapcomwriters-room-improv-fundraiser-writers-room-productions&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/writers-room-improv-fundraiser/&quot;&gt;Back to School Improv Night Fundraiser&lt;/a&gt;, Writer’s Room Productions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, we’d love for you to join &lt;a href=&quot;www.writersroomproductions.org&quot;&gt;Writer’s Room Productions&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;wayfare.io/events&quot;&gt;Wayfare&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;Friday, September 16th&lt;/strong&gt; to help support this non-profit in their mission to ignite confidence and creatitvity in the next generation through creative writing and performances. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.ticketleap.com/writers-room-improv-fundraiser/&quot;&gt;Get your tickets&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;www.writersroomproductions&quot;&gt;visit their website&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about this amazing non-profit organization and the ways you can support their efforts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jill Arbini</name></author><category term="costa-mesa" /><category term="education" /><category term="common-good" /><summary>The 2016-2017 school year is upon us and while Back to School is top of mind, we’re featuring various action steps that can be taken to support the kids, teachers, parents, and schools in our community.

There are so many ways that any person can use what they have to contribute to the flourishing of our kids.  Today we are focusing on several ways to support kids in our area where we each can play a role in raising up the next generation of leaders, creators, innovators, and world-changers.</summary></entry><entry><title>Member Monday: Sarah Heath</title><link href="/stories/2016/08/22/member-monday-sarah-heath/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Member Monday: Sarah Heath" /><published>2016-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/stories/2016/08/22/member-monday-sarah-heath</id><content type="html" xml:base="/stories/2016/08/22/member-monday-sarah-heath/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who are you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah Heath&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best movie of all time is clearly….&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newsies and anything Guy Ritchie has made except for that one with Madonna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your favorite local restaurant?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been going to Durty Nelly’s for years. I love that little pub!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How would you spend your ideal day off?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Ideal day off would probably include one or all of the following: going on a run or to the gym, going on a road trip, taking my dog to the beach, dinner with friends with great food and conversation. Is it the weekend yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you could go anywhere in the world you haven’t been, where would you go and why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably cheating but Ireland. I am going there in October. My family is from England and as many times as I have been across the pond I have never gone to Ireland. There is something so captivating about photos of Ireland I can’t wait to see the beautiful landscape and visit all the local restaurants and pubs I am traveling with folks who have family there so it is going to be a fun adventure I think! Look out Australia you are next!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do you do for work? Tell us a little bit about how you got to where you are today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a United Methodist Pastor. In July I was asked to help revitalize and relaunch the community at First UMC in Costa Mesa. I am the lucky person who gets to work at the 100 year old gorgeous church building on 19th!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I got there is a long story but here is the short version: I came to California after graduating from Grad school in North Carolina where I got my Mdiv at Duke University. It was in grad school that my passion for creating and curating community began. After grad school I was brought out to Irvine to do youth and college ministry. While at that church I was part of a team that created a new worship service and became the lead speaker for that service. I was then asked to go to Rancho Santa Margarita to serve as the preaching pastor of a church who had just merged with another community and I spent 5 years there. It was a wonderful community filled with diversity and creativity and I think really prepared me for the work here in Costa Mesa. It has been amazing to see the community already grow at this little historic church. It is diverse and welcoming and we are just a month into it! I just get to help move it forward and work with developing the site itself to be a place of safety and sanctuary in Costa Mesa. As we say it is “A heart for the city in the heart of the city”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you stay inspired? Productive?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am inspired by all the amazing friends I have who are bringing goodness to the world. I am also inspired by the people I work with and for. Seeing people go through transformation keeps this job inspiring. Watching lives move closer to who they were intended to be is awe inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that I always have a looming deadline whether it be a writing deadline, a speaking engagement, or just the fact that Sunday is ALWAYS coming I stay aware that deadlines are a constant! I love the apps Evernote and Asana both of those keep me productive and on task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your favorite part of your work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love getting to be with people in their biggest moments and I love creating things like art, talks, sermons, and studies that connect people to the divine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/content/images/2016/08/756ff61dc2bb-Sarah1-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some of the biggest challenges of your work and what advice would you give to someone experiencing similar challenges?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time management is the hardest part of my job currently. From being a project manager for a big re-build project, to managing volunteers and creating weekly talks my time is filled with good things but I could work 24 hours everyday. I think the best thing I can do is create a team that help me take some of these things off of my desk. I think building a team is always one of the most important things about being a change maker!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you decide to work out of Wayfare?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the construction of our facility they took down the office space, not only that but someone kept stealing the cooper wire and so we didn’t even have electricity for a month. Just when I thought slow wifi was a stressor having no power caused us to have to get creative! I could have worked from home but being surrounded by change makers was always a goal for us. Working at Wayfare was an intentional choice for me to be in contact with those who were doing some really important and creative things in Costa Mesa that the church community can partner with and enact some crazy goodness in the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are some ways (if any) we can support you and get involved with your work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have such a small amazing community I think anytime we can partner with people who are doing things to help change the world we are amplifying the difference we can make in the world. So I think partnerships are one of the greatest ways we can mutually support each other. I also don’t have tons of creative resources so I am always loving to support anyone doing the arts by providing a space for them to do that. And of course you are always welcome to our new/ancient community on Sundays at 10am!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connect with Sarah on social media &lt;strong&gt;@revsarahheath&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://fumccostamesa.org/&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; (site is under  construction!)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Caitlin Kraina</name></author><category term="costa-mesa" /><category term="member-monday" /><summary>I could have worked from home but being surrounded by change makers was always a goal for us. I think anytime we can partner with people who are doing things to help change the world we are amplifying the difference we can make in the world.</summary></entry></feed>
