<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://wayfare.io/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://wayfare.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://wayfare.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-01-20T01:09:22+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io//</id><title type="html">Wayfare</title><entry><title type="html">Say Goodbye to “Wayfare”</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/18/say-goodbye-to-wayfare/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Say Goodbye to &quot;Wayfare&quot;" /><published>2017-01-18T21:12:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-18T21:12:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/18/say-goodbye-to-wayfare</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/18/say-goodbye-to-wayfare/">&lt;p&gt;Hey there,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a new year and we have big news. We started dreaming about what Wayfare would become over three years ago. It was our vision to create a workspace and support for organizations that would birth movements for the common good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were forming the organization, we decided on the name Wayfare because it captured the heart behind our vision. The word Wayfare has a double meaning. It means the act of journeying. It also means provisions for the journey. This word clearly encompassed the community we envisioned—a community of creators, doers, and adventurers aspiring to pursue the common good and support each other in the journey.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
Around the same time that we decided to name our company Wayfare, another company with a different mission (they sell furniture) called Wayfair was on the rise. They sell furniture at “way fair” prices and made news as they received hundreds of millions in capital investment that year. As we became aware of their company, we explored the potential of any conflict associated with our names sounding the same. We didn’t see any conflict, and our lawyers agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently however, their lawyers did not. We appreciate great furniture as much as anyone, and we even have a few items procured through our very own orders from wayfair.com itself. However, we are faced with a decision. We must decide how much time, energy, and money we want to spend in legal fees (the quick answer is zero…nobody wants to pay legal fees) to continue down the path of fighting to keep our name. We’ve chosen a different path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our startup programs, we advise organizations to quickly assess environmental changes and the big picture when experiencing challenges – to make sense of the situation and rapidly adjust. So we’ve taken our own advice and have decided to change our name while staying true to who we are…who you are. We’re going to redirect our energy and steward our resources in a positive direction to rename this community, and we want you, the community, included in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the name Wayfare is a great representation of our mission and this community, when we look at the big picture, we are struck with the amazing people that form this community, the wonderful hearts you have, and world-changing work you are doing. For that reason, we are thrilled to invite you into the process of renaming Wayfare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are humbled and full of gratitude that the community of three who decided on the name is now a community of over 200 members who work out of the workspaces or are currently participating in the startup programs. There are thousands of others who serve as advisors, have attended events, or have joined us on social media. You’ve been a part of this journey so far, and we want to continue this adventure along with you. YOU are Wayfare and we’re happy to release the name, because the community and the journey we are all on together matter more. And that is where we want to continue to invest the resources we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, let’s go on another adventure together.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re having a contest to come up with a new name (yes, there are prizes) and we want &lt;strong&gt;ALL&lt;/strong&gt; the ideas. We invite you to submit a name (or 20) for our rebranding, and the guidelines are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The name captures our goals of having spaces where people can daily be supported in meaningful work (workspaces) AND simultaneously captures the mission of guiding founders and startups of missional enterprises and social good organizations (startup programs).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The name communicates the concept of adventure, journeying, support, and encouragement in pursuit of the common good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bonus points if the .com of the name is available or there’s an instagram/twitter handle available (but we can work around this, so if you have the perfect name submit it anyway)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extra bonus points if you submit a catchy hashtag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;action&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wayfare.typeform.com/to/DFBRl1&quot;&gt;Submit your ideas and an explanation&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submit as many ideas as you want as many times as you want.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anyone can participate (you don’t need to be a member to share your ideas)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All submissions must be received by January 31st at 10 p.m.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prize&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One winner will receive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A $500 credit to be used toward Startup Programs, Workspaces, Meeting Rooms, or Event Fees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swag bag of goods with new branding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our eternal gratitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So get your thinking caps on and let’s embark on the next phase of this journey together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With extreme gratitude and excitement for the world’s best future,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brandon Arbini &amp;amp; Jeff Tanner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Co-founders of the organization soon to be formerly known as Wayfare&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeff and Brandon</name></author><category term="creativity" /><category term="rebrand" /><category term="community" /><category term="collaborate" /><category term="contest" /><summary type="html">Hey there,

It’s a new year and we have big news. We started dreaming about what Wayfare would become over three years ago. It was our vision to create a workspace and support for organizations that would birth movements for the common good.

As we were forming the organization, we decided on the name Wayfare because it captured the heart behind our vision. The word Wayfare has a double meaning. It means the act of journeying. It also means provisions for the journey. This word clearly encompassed the community we envisioned—a community of creators, doers, and adventurers aspiring to pursue the common good and support each other in the journey.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/rebrand-blog-post.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Make What You Wish Existed</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/09/make-what-you-wish-existed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Make What You Wish Existed" /><published>2017-01-09T18:26:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-09T18:26:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/09/make-what-you-wish-existed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/09/make-what-you-wish-existed/">&lt;p&gt;Lots of people are saying 2016 was one of the worst years, and so they are looking at 2017 with hope, excitement and lots of plans to make big changes. I don’t know if 2016 was my worst year, but it was for sure my busiest. During overwhelming times like these, my dad says, “Life can feel like trying to drink out of fire hose. It all just comes at once and you feel like you may drown.” I was drowning this year! This year I was tasked with restarting a church that had experienced a huge decline and I published my first book where I was the primary author. The project included art, video and writing. So it was a crazy year where every other day I thought I was going under. Let alone feeling like I had a personal life. &lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s this thing about drowning: it only takes one hand to reach for you and pull you to safety. Last year that life-giving hand came in the applause of a three year old named “Willow.” Before I share her story, let me first share how I got to this moment of drowning. It all started with a sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Make what you wish existed.”&lt;/strong&gt; That sign hangs in the coworking space, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wayfare.io/locations/costa-mesa/&quot;&gt;Wayfare&lt;/a&gt;,  that I currently share in Costa Mesa. I am working out of Wayfare for several reasons, but my favorite reason is that I get to be surrounded by people making big changes in the world and as I have been tasked with building a church community that I actually want to go to - these are the people I want to be around. I have been working in this artistic and innovative space with lots of other startup pastors. Sometimes I overhear planning sessions of really creative worship services. As I hear the ideas pour forth, I get overwhelmed with trying to envision what my new church will look like. This feeling gets worse each time I pass the sign “Make what you wish existed”. I find myself doubting my ability to create anything anyone wishes existed. I have always dreamed of creating the church and worship services I wish for, but the excitement of that idea sure seems to fade in the face of daily community, building, financial and other resource issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These challenges show up in many ways. Our building is 100 years old and has no room for classrooms or fellowship other than worship itself, the existing congregation is in varying stages of being on board with anything new, and the surrounding community has great need but is hard to serve. When you add these obstacles on top of trying to work out a stream of income to keep the doors open, it gets difficult to imagine being creative enough to make anything, let alone something you wish existed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week of my rescue was a particularly hard week. That Monday I discovered that some contracts created before my appointment to the church were not working out as hoped – which was making the church’s financial situation, among many other things, much more challenging. Then on the same day, someone tried to break into the building…and a June bug flew in my car window. I am afraid of all bugs, but let’s just say I am never emotionally prepared for the ones that are the size of hummingbirds and fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting in my car about to cry, I began to pray. Then I remembered a tiny incident – a moment of proof that something that I do wish existed is being created…already. Worship as it was at that time was awkward, especially in the music department because, among other things, we had no worship leader. Instead, our accompanist played the hymns while all of us tried to sing along. Our accompanist was very talented, but without a worship leader we often felt like we are just stumbling through the music. Sometimes, in the middle of a service, I just want to stand up and declare: “Just wait! I know this is awkward, but hold tight – something new and great is coming!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other awkward part of this whole “new church in an old church” setting is that is that although the church has a few rooms other than the sanctuary, they are currently full of pipe organ parts. One tiny office is too small to house a class. So when new families show up, we have no classroom space for their children and they sit and worship with their parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two awkward components crashed into each other this week in a life-giving moment that saved me from drowning in my own doubt. It was Willow’s first week at our church. This little darling showed up excited for church in a beautiful dress and shiny shoes. Her parents seemed worried about her chattering mid-worship, but I loved it. During the time of the offering the accompanist played a beautiful piece. When she was done instead of the usual silence that fills that huge sanctuary, Willow was overcome and clapped, exclaiming “Good job!” Overwhelmed by her enthusiasm and the beauty of the song, everyone else joined in the applause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I sat in my car staring at my beautiful hot mess of a church, Willow’s joyous applause came flashing back to me. In that moment, I could see the beauty and joy of who we were becoming. We are an absolute mess, but we are also beautiful and joyful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with that tiny clap, Willow saved me from drowning. So I am pressing on with God, Willow and the rest of my congregation to &lt;strong&gt;“make something both Willow and I wish existed.”&lt;/strong&gt; And I guess it is working because on Christmas Eve there were 80 people huddled together in this church to celebrate. It has been years since the church has seen these numbers. But the best part was, as I scanned the crowd, I saw the most diverse gathering of people I have seen and they are the type of people I want to spend time with. I have actually started to build the very thing I needed. So 2017, look out I am coming for you and together we are going to build something amazing!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sarah Heath</name></author><category term="creation" /><category term="building" /><category term="church" /><category term="innovation" /><category term="creativity" /><category term="beauty" /><category term="joy" /><category term="busy" /><category term="new year" /><summary type="html">Lots of people are saying 2016 was one of the worst years, and so they are looking at 2017 with hope, excitement and lots of plans to make big changes. I don’t know if 2016 was my worst year, but it was for sure my busiest. During overwhelming times like these, my dad says, “Life can feel like trying to drink out of fire hose. It all just comes at once and you feel like you may drown.” I was drowning this year! This year I was tasked with restarting a church that had experienced a huge decline and I published my first book where I was the primary author. The project included art, video and writing. So it was a crazy year where every other day I thought I was going under. Let alone feeling like I had a personal life.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/make.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Starting 2017 With Your Legacy in Mind</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/02/starting-with-the-end-in-mind/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting 2017 With Your Legacy in Mind" /><published>2017-01-02T17:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-02T17:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/02/starting-with-the-end-in-mind</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2017/01/02/starting-with-the-end-in-mind/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been pondering the concept of legacy a lot lately. Perhaps because I just had my second daughter-and I’m overly intentional about the words that come out of my mouth towards and about them. I want every day, every moment, to be wrapped around intention because, truth is, girls still need to hear that they can and should do the hard and holy things in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s another side to legacy that drives me. My mom. She is not my hero. No, the complete opposite. Her life was an example of everything I never want to be-selfish, addict, abusive, promiscuous…lost. My birth mom raised me to fear the world, fear her hand, fear her words. She made me believe my worth is in my sexuality and I’m only as good as the attention I received from guys. To go to college, to have a life long spouse, to do better for myself, well, this was selfish and wrong and I obviously thought I was better than everyone for doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved out when I was sixteen. With a black-eye and a battered heart, I moved in with my now family. Three years later I graduated college. Six years later I met a man that is good, and stable, and strong and thinks I’m lovely and smart and worth loving because, I just am. Nine months later we welcomed our first little girl, and now we are a tribe of seven (we picked up three more kids along the way). My husband has never laid a harmful hand on me or raised his voice-like my birth mom promised the man I was bound to marry would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, growing up with such volatile words and fists constantly being thrown my way, I know the affect of words. Because of that broken record of her voice, I let opportunities and chances pass by out of fear of failure, or, worse, becoming someone just like her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look at my two girls, one just over one and another just three months young, and I see their little personalities and strengths start to bloom-one is strong and fearless, trying to pick up bees (I’m serious) and the other is a softer kind of strong. T, our three month old, is tender and sensitive and doesn’t like to be messed with but my, oh my, does she love to stare at smiling faces. I see them. I see people within them, and I want to nurture that which I see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The legacy my mother left me was one of injure-I was promised failure and abuse and heartache. I get to rewrite the course for my kids. I called a halt to that legacy and yelled out, with my life, No (more accurately, hell no), and started a new route. The legacy I leave for my daughters is one of art and music and you cans because I did. I took leaps and pursued dreams, and did they always succeed? No. But I tried and they will too. They may be babies, but the words I speak to them, the words I speak over them today will follow them through high school, through their twenties and thirties, and through their own journey as a wife, mother, friend, sister. This is the legacy I get to be a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting a new year and all of its resolutions is a good thing. It’s good to have short term goals in mind-I want to go to yoga more regularly, start waking up at 4am (because…babies) to get some alone time, and to date my husband more regularly. I want to land three more clients by the end of each month and write a book proposal and blog for my heart more regularly. These are all really good things and goals to have. But, my biggest goal this year is to keep the end in mind-what is my end goal? To look back in fifty years and know that I left a legacy for those watching to enjoy and learn from.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sally Kim</name></author><category term="goals" /><category term="new year" /><category term="legacy" /><summary type="html">I’ve been pondering the concept of legacy a lot lately. Perhaps because I just had my second daughter-and I’m overly intentional about the words that come out of my mouth towards and about them. I want every day, every moment, to be wrapped around intention because, truth is, girls still need to hear that they can and should do the hard and holy things in the world.

There’s another side to legacy that drives me. My mom. She is not my hero. No, the complete opposite. Her life was an example of everything I never want to be-selfish, addict, abusive, promiscuous…lost. My birth mom raised me to fear the world, fear her hand, fear her words. She made me believe my worth is in my sexuality and I’m only as good as the attention I received from guys. To go to college, to have a life long spouse, to do better for myself, well, this was selfish and wrong and I obviously thought I was better than everyone for doing so.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/ojvirvbkwp8-lukas-becker.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What a Blank Canvas Taught Me About Letting Go</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/26/what-a-canvas-taught-me-about-surrender/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What a Blank Canvas Taught Me About Letting Go" /><published>2016-12-26T18:36:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-26T18:36:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/26/what-a-canvas-taught-me-about-surrender</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/26/what-a-canvas-taught-me-about-surrender/">&lt;p&gt;This year has been one of chaos, of change, of newness. I graduated college. Got engaged. New Job. Moved. Marriage. Bliss. Chaos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the beauty and the gift that change is, I’m never prepared for the grief that it’s paired with. Transition melts you and reforms you to where you feel like a piece of playdough that a 3-year old pancake-smashed, mixed with other colors, and stuck on the bottom of a desk. I almost don’t recognize myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, a friend said a picture of me came to her mind–She saw me running as a young girl through the streets of the town where I grew up. I wasn’t running from anything, just running simply because I could run. She said I was marked by a free spirit, uninhibited by the rules of perfection and performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She said I’ve lost that, and I miss myself…I’ve forgotten what it feels like to be full, to not limit myself to the mold that I’m expected to fit into, or limit myself to the words that I’ve begun to describe myself by: &lt;strong&gt;Wife. Employee. Machine. Tired. Incapable. Not. Good. Enough.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve laid out high expectations for myself, ones that I could never achieve without wearing myself down to dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If our house isn’t speck free. If our fridge isn’t full. If our lunches aren’t prepped. If the bed isn’t made, I’m defeated. I question my worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is it that I’ve even begun to define myself by the state of our dirty laundry?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I begin to re-discover the parts of myself that have been choked, I recently began creating space in my weekly rhythm to explore things that fill me. I started painting again, one of the things I spent most of my time doing in high school. It was one of those things that really mattered to me that was the first to go when ‘life’ got in the way. I hate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Warm, 11a.m. sun bleeding into our 600 square foot studio, bare feet, and hair in a top bun, my paint brush grazed the bare canvas and I immediately stepped back. What was I doing? I didn’t have a plan for this painting. I had no vision for the final piece, much less a plan to execute it effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept going, and I let myself have so much fun with it. There was no formula I was trying to follow. You know how often I was told as a kid to stay in the lines? Screw it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That canvas that day taught me the three most important things I needed to know about surrendering myself in a way that leaves ample space for freedom. After all, the literal definition of surrender is to cease resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.A painting is never perfect. Stop striving for perfection.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t ever be done. I won’t ever be able to apply twelve point font and one inch margins, double check for spelling and grammar, and submit myself to be graded. Trying “arrive” is mentally, physically, and emotionally draining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.A painting adds life and character to a space. Stop trying to be someone else.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my canvas looked like the one on the wall of my favorite coffee shop, there would be one too many. I need to add my own life and character to the places you find myself in. If I find myself in places where I can’t do that, then I probably shouldn’t stay there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.A painting is a process. Step back once in awhile, refocus, and remember why you started.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Halfway through my painting I had to go take a walk. My eyes were dry and sandy with frustration. When I came back I had new eyes and a new excitement for where the painting was headed. Step back once in awhile, refocus, and remember why you started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, my new words for myself as I began to run through the streets again and regain freedom? &lt;strong&gt;Messy. Passionate. Strong. Imperfect. Not. Yet. Finished.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="surrender" /><category term="new year" /><category term="change" /><category term="transition" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html">This year has been one of chaos, of change, of newness. I graduated college. Got engaged. New Job. Moved. Marriage. Bliss. Chaos.

With the beauty and the gift that change is, I’m never prepared for the grief that it’s paired with. Transition melts you and reforms you to where you feel like a piece of playdough that a 3-year old pancake-smashed, mixed with other colors, and stuck on the bottom of a desk. I almost don’t recognize myself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/IMG_9056.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">12 Questions to Ask Yourself Before the New Year</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/22/12-questions-to-ask-yourself-before-the-new-year/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="12 Questions to Ask Yourself Before the New Year" /><published>2016-12-22T08:01:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-22T08:01:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/22/12-questions-to-ask-yourself-before-the-new-year</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/22/12-questions-to-ask-yourself-before-the-new-year/">&lt;p&gt;This year, my husband and I created a New Year’s bucket list of all the things we wanted to do in 2016. The list included things like: ride a motorcycle through Vietnam, hike the narrows at Zion National Park, attend the RISE festival, and finally take up a ceramics class. And a graphic design class. And sewing (because why not?!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list was posted on our refrigerator throughout the entire year, and I looked straight into it every time I opened the door. The things on the list were inspiring and wonderful… and completely unachievable. Our plates were full.&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every morning (after gazing at our untouched bucket list), we left the house for full days. We spent each weekday working full time jobs (that we love), giving 110% of ourselves daily to our work. For my husband, that often meant working through the night as an EMT while being a full time student and a volunteer firefighter. We took on new projects and learned new skills, learned a lot about humility, service, and how to say “no”, and we invested, celebrated, and mourned with our friends.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to the day we can cross “ride a motorcycle through Vietnam” off the list, but I do not mourn the remains of this year’s resolutions. This year, I celebrate the unexpected joys and trials that have taught character and grit. I celebrate what I’ve learned about my priorities as well as my capacity. I celebrate that saying “no” to instagram-worthy New Year’s resolution items left essential white space for personal growth and reflection, the response to pain, the creation of meaningful work, and most importantly, deeper relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m encouraged by fellow Wayfarers that have taught me to re-frame the definition and pursuit of adventure. I love checking out after a long week &amp;amp; exploring a new National Park just as much as the next person — but I’ve learned that showing up to our daily lives and rejoicing in the gift of each day, trailblazing through hardship with tenacity, and sharing &amp;amp; embracing our messy stories with those we journey through life with is often the biggest adventure we can embark on — and can be life changing for ourselves and those around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the new year approaches, I encourage you to set New Year’s resolutions for yourself that embrace this kind of adventure. Start small. Spend more time in conversations that matter. Give yourself grace. Take more evening walks. Start each morning with a prayer of peace and gratitude. Seek more counsel from people you admire.  Turn off your phone.  Invite strangers in for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you move forward into the New Year and consider your own resolutions, I encourage you to pause and reflect on the previous year. Asking yourself important reflection questions can be a great way to ensure the goals you are setting are relevant, based on your priorities, and rooted in gratitude. Here are twelve questions to use as a starting point to reflect &amp;amp; take a moment to honor the triumphs, mourn the losses, celebrate your growth:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What was my greatest contribution this year?
(What did I do right? What do I feel that I have done especially well?)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What was an unexpected joy this year?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What was an unexpected obstacle? What were my biggest challenges/difficulties? How did I grow from them?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In what way(s) did I grow emotionally?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In what way(s) did I grow spiritually?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In what way(s) did I grow physically?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What are the three most important things I learned this year?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What did I complete or release? What still feels incomplete to me?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What was the most enjoyable part of my work?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What was the most challenging part of my work?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What do I want/need to incorporate more of into my daily life?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For what am I particularly grateful?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You got this! Here’s to a New Year of lives well lived for the things that matter most.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="new year" /><category term="new" /><category term="questions" /><category term="reflection" /><category term="bucket list" /><category term="resolution" /><category term="goals" /><category term="grace" /><category term="adventure" /><category term="gratitude" /><category term="priorities" /><category term="balance" /><summary type="html">This year, my husband and I created a New Year’s bucket list of all the things we wanted to do in 2016. The list included things like: ride a motorcycle through Vietnam, hike the narrows at Zion National Park, attend the RISE festival, and finally take up a ceramics class. And a graphic design class. And sewing (because why not?!).

The list was posted on our refrigerator throughout the entire year, and I looked straight into it every time I opened the door. The things on the list were inspiring and wonderful… and completely unachievable. Our plates were full.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/12-questions-blog.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Tips for Simplifying the Holidays With Your Family</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/20/5-tips-for-simplifying-the-holidays-with-your-family/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Tips for Simplifying the Holidays With Your Family" /><published>2016-12-20T09:12:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-20T09:12:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/20/5-tips-for-simplifying-the-holidays-with-your-family</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/20/5-tips-for-simplifying-the-holidays-with-your-family/">&lt;p&gt;As a child Christmas was my favorite holiday. However in recent years, the overall busyness, increased demands of the season, and the general state of the world, had taken away from much of the joy for me. It was for these and a variety of other reasons, (not the least of which was a gift request for squeaking dolphin slippers), that my husband and I made some changes that have shaped how we celebrate Christmas with our kids and it has made a positive difference in how we experience this time of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt; We live in a world where so many people are in need and experiencing horrible circumstances. It can be tempting to call it quits on the celebrating while others the world are suffering. Alternatively, it is tempting to carry on with our lives willfully ignoring the sadness because it can all seem like just too much. However, as with most things in this world, there is a simultaneous tension of celebrating the good while acknowledging the broken and taking steps to help change it. In an ever evolving effort of trial and error, my husband and I have tried to strike a balance between the two and develop a new way of operating in this tension, especially this time of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Why Do We Celebrate?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on your cultural, religious, and familial traditions, the reasons behind your celebrations will vary. However, regardless of what holiday or holidays you find yourself celebrating this time of year, the answer to why can help inform how you celebrate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our family celebrates Christmas. The celebration of the birth of Christ and/or Santa Claus or some version of him are the two main focuses of Christmas in the US and many parts of the world.  As my husband and I considered the why of Christmas and gift giving, we came up with an explanation that both allowed for the celebration of the holiday and all of its traditions and also made room for simpler more generous practices. We decided that our family’s “why” was to honor Christ’s birth by following his example. We decided that giving gifts to others and caring for people in need is an expression of love for others and our love for God, which Jesus famously said are the greatest commands. We also acknowledge that St. Nicholas was a generous man who gave to those in need and Jesus himself said that serving the most needy in his name, was like serving him. We have found that this is a good balance between our personal faith and the fun that Santa Claus brings while still giving meaning to the gifts and hopefully inspiring generosity in our kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will obviously look different for each family, but most holiday traditions this time of year include some form of gratitude, honor of others, and outward expression of love and care. Identifying why we celebrated was a key part in putting and keeping the focus on where we wanted it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. A Family Decision&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After explaining to our kids the reasons behind our traditions, we invited them into the decision making process. We told them that we had a budget for Christmas and asked them how they would feel about us spending less money on their gifts, and instead directing a portion of our budget to help others in need. Since this was a pretty significant change from how they were accustomed to celebrating, they had some questions as to what they would look like, but ultimately were in agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Four Gifts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a guideline for a simpler and less frantic gift extravaganza than in years past, we decided on quality over quantity. I found an idea on the internet to help guide us in our gift giving to our kids.  The idea is a fun rhyme that includes 4 categories: something you want, something you need, something to wear, and something to read.(Pro tip: If you can make things rhyme, kids get instantly excited.) So our kids each get 4 presents from us; 1 in each category. They also get stockings and Santa usually drops off a family gift in the form of an experience or activity that can be enjoyed together. In all honesty, I think our kids enjoy Christmas morning more now than they did before we started the 4 gifts. They savor each gift and seem to use and enjoy what they receive more than in years past. They have also become increasingly excited to make gifts and give to others with their own skills, time, and money. (Bonus: Knowing they get 4 gifts in specific categories helps decrease the asks for things like bacon scented body wash).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Caring for Those in Need&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Christmas morning, before we do anything else, we start off the day talking about the meaning of Christmas and we let the kids each choose what they want to give to someone in need by choosing from a give back gift catalog. The first Christmas we did this, I thought that they’d want to rush through this process to move on to their stockings and presents, but they surprised us and took great care in what they selected. Each year we love seeing a glimpse of their hearts and interests through what they pick and the reason behind it. A few catalogs we like are:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.compassion.com/charitable-gift-catalog.htm&quot;&gt;Compassion International&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://preemptivelove.nationbuilder.com/ann&quot;&gt;Preemptive Love Coalition&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://donate.worldvision.org/ways-to-give/gift-catalog&quot;&gt;World Vision&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been giving four gifts and selecting from the giving catalogs for a few years now and it makes the day so much more enjoyable. The kids know to savor each gift the receive, they know what to expect, and they really genuinely get excited about the opportunity to pick something to give to someone in need. Christmas miracles still happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Presence vs. Presents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve scaled back on the amount of gifts we purchase, it has freed up time and space to focus on experiences unique to this time of year. Looking back on my lasting childhood memories, I don’t remember many of the gifts I received, but I vividly remember the traditions we had. Playing in the snow with my siblings, baking cookies, decorating the tree, the candlelight Christmas Eve service at our church followed by a “sleepover” with my sister in my room are among my favorites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve reflected on these experiences from my childhood, I’m passing some on to my kids, and we’re starting traditions of our own as well. Some years we are able to and want to do more than others. This year, as the kids are getting older, our school and activity schedules have been more full than in years past, so in our tiny moments of downtime, we have all needed more space to rest and just be together. With a simpler approach to the holidays, it has been really wonderful to not feel the need to fill every free moment in an effort to get things done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world full of chaos, my continuous hope is that we all can experience peace in our homes, that it will bring hope to our hearts, and will compel our actions toward love.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="Christmas" /><category term="giving" /><category term="family" /><category term="presents" /><category term="give back" /><summary type="html">As a child Christmas was my favorite holiday. However in recent years, the overall busyness, increased demands of the season, and the general state of the world, had taken away from much of the joy for me. It was for these and a variety of other reasons, (not the least of which was a gift request for squeaking dolphin slippers), that my husband and I made some changes that have shaped how we celebrate Christmas with our kids and it has made a positive difference in how we experience this time of year.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/xjb7du_4kqq-andrew-neel.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Building Creation Economies: What Does it Mean to be a Creator?</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/15/building-creation-economies-what-does-it-mean-to-be-creative/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building Creation Economies: What Does it Mean to be a Creator?" /><published>2016-12-15T19:08:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-15T19:08:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/15/building-creation-economies-what-does-it-mean-to-be-creative</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/15/building-creation-economies-what-does-it-mean-to-be-creative/">&lt;p&gt;In this series, entitled &lt;strong&gt;Building Creation Economies&lt;/strong&gt;, I’ve talked about &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/2016/12/02/the-confounding-merger-of-work-and-leisure/&quot;&gt;The Confounding Merger of Work and Leisure&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/stories/2016/12/09/building-creation-economies-what-is-work/&quot;&gt;What is Work?&lt;/a&gt;. Now, let’s look at what it means to be a creator. I propose three components.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creators are rooted in their identity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creators display artistry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creators make meaning for others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creators are rooted in identity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creators have deep self awareness; they know their unique strengths, skills, and abilities. They are in tune with who they were created to be, and are ever-vigilant about working harmoniously with themselves. They don’t attempt to align with the outside voices of expectation or obligation, but they do include others in the wonder of discovering their best contribution to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identity is never found in individualism, isolation, and self-centeredness. It is always found in relationship. And it is a never ending journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end, the question I believe we need to constantly ask ourselves is this: What is my best contribution to the world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know the answer, don’t worry. You’re not alone. There’s no expectation, only invitation. And to redeem work, we must ask it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creators display artistry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artistry is celebrating and creating beauty, and not just visually, but in all realms. You can be an artist in designing handbags or in designing organizations or in the simple way you clean a room. Artistry is not limited to the “creative class.” In fact, if you’re glazing over as you read this section, please don’t. Don’t let “creatives” exclude your unique identity from this work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And creatives, you can help others recognize the ways in which they are artists in the seemingly mundane endeavors of everyday life. There’s plenty of room for the celebration of what is beautiful and the creation of new beauty in our world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the question I believe we need to constantly ask is this: What beauty am I being called to celebrate or create today?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creators make meaning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we all get this. We all want a sense of purpose in our lives, but for me, making meaning is for others. Our meaning is rooted in our identity, but this is different. This is about seeing the best in others and helping them find their meaning.
This is an other-orientation that fights against the self-centeredness we see at the root of all other human entropy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus told us to love our neighbors as ourselves. I believe love for ourselves is first and foremost embracing our identity, and loving others is to make meaning for them and help them live into their identity and artistry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the question I believe we need to constantly ask is this: How am I, right here, right now, making meaning for others?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friends, I believe we’re in one of the most profound cultural shifts in the history of the world. We’ve moved from being hunter/gatherers to an agrarian economy to the industrial revolution to the information age, and we’re on the cusp of what some are calling the innovation economy. But while I think that term is true for much of the world, it doesn’t capture the fullest extent of our creative calling because it is mostly transactional when it should be wholly transformational. I believe if you’re reading this, you are likely a participant in the creation economy. The creation economy is a subversive economy that’s fighting against toil and entropy that are too normal in our world. It is countercultural and calls for more. It demands whole life pursuit of our identity, artistry, and meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is my invitation to you today: Enter into a conversation with us at Wayfare about what it means to be people of the creation economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People of the creation economy refuse to engage around anything other than creation or re-creation. They refuse to contribute to the political diatribes or useless arguments about who won debates. They refuse to scroll mindlessly through Facebook or Instagram feeds. They refuse to toil through the next Netflix series that they just have to watch. Instead, they focus on restoring what is broken and celebrating and creating beauty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People of the creation economy realize that the problem of work is actually a problem of toil. The problem isn’t that we work too much. On the contrary, it’s that we toil too much on distractions and work too little on creation. The problem is that we are consumed by transacting work rather than transforming work as an act of creation or re-creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acts of creation or re-creation could be as complex as building a multinational NGO to fight extreme poverty around the world or as simple as picking up your kids’ toys at the end of the day–or sometimes over and over, all day –as an act of re-creation because it is part of the fight against the entropy introduced with self-centeredness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will you join me in constantly asking these questions of yourself and others? &lt;strong&gt;What is my best contribution to the world? What beauty am I being called to celebrate and create? And what meaning can I make as an act of love for others?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This creation work, which is rooted in identity, displaying artistry, and making meaning for others is the future past of work. It was always the intention. And it can be true of us again. Let’s redeem work. Let’s be people of the creation economy, and let’s create the world’s best future together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we continue this conversation as a community, I’d love to know what questions you have or what challenges you face in this realm. Tweet your thoughts + questions to &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/wayfarehq&quot;&gt;@wayfarehq&lt;/a&gt; or email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:jeff@wayfare.io&quot;&gt;jeff@wayfare.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="creation" /><category term="economy" /><category term="work" /><category term="common-good" /><category term="creative" /><category term="creativity" /><category term="artistry" /><category term="meaning" /><summary type="html">In this series, entitled Building Creation Economies, I’ve talked about The Confounding Merger of Work and Leisure and What is Work?. Now, let’s look at what it means to be a creator. I propose three components.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/0jw6_7hy-rm-samuel-zeller.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sitting with Someone in their Silent Night</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/13/sitting-with-someone-in-their-silent-night/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sitting with Someone in their Silent Night" /><published>2016-12-13T17:56:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-13T17:56:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/13/sitting-with-someone-in-their-silent-night</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/13/sitting-with-someone-in-their-silent-night/">&lt;p&gt;On our drive home from school, my thirteen year old son was telling me about his Christmas choir concert, and how he really did not like one of the songs. It just feels like they’re trying to make a calm holiday all jumpy and excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s our sensitive one. He often hears things differently than they are intended, is easily discouraged and offended, and takes about nine hours to tell us any kind of story. I laughed it off and turned up Baby It’s Cold Outside, which was sandwiched between Frosty the Snowman and Holly Jolly Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s something true about our boy’s observation. There is this tendency to skip the dark and jump straight to the lights, the coco, the loud and bright and happy…forgetting that the silent night was what started it all-the calm, bright, quiet evening that preludes all the celebrations begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because, the truth is, the tension that exists between the quiet and the dark and the loud and the light is thick and hard to sit in. But, this thick tension is exactly where we are needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s cliche to say that this is a hurting world in need of healing hands, I know. But it is a statement that renders truth…We live in a time of uncertainty and fear, where people are lacking security in their lives. I can’t go one day without hearing a story of a woman losing a baby after trying to get pregnant for years, or someone losing their job right before Christmas, or someone shaken by some inconceivable act of violence. This is the reality of our world right now. People we know, people we work with and family members and those we love, and those we don’t, are hurting, right now. So how can you respond?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t soften the blow. You can’t clean their pain away like food on a dirty dish. But you can be there for them. Even if you don’t know how, even if you don’t have the perfect words to say, here are a few ways to sit in the dark and calm of the night someone you encounter may be facing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t offer a solution.&lt;/strong&gt; 
Seriously, don’t. Just accept what’s happening with them. Look them in the eyes and listen…listen hard. Nod and grimace and swallow and smile and accept them in whatever stage of grief they are at. Don’t correct. Don’t judge. Set your biases aside and open your ears. Your job is not to solve, correct, or inform. Your job is to be a rock for them to hear their own voice bounce off of. Let their experience matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Pay for a housecleaner.&lt;/strong&gt; 
When we got our emergency foster placement, someone paid for us to have a housecleaner for nearly five months. I’m a firm believer that if the home is chaotic and messy and cluttered as heck, the mind and heart will reflect the same. Someone in grieving needs open space to breathe. They need permission to focus only on the ones in their care, and to be respectful of this very moment in their lives. The house won’t be perfect. Dishes will still fill the sink….but to know that the bathrooms are clean this week, that the stove is free of gunk and that the floors have been vacuumed could be the absolute greatest gift you give someone this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Drop off a meal, a book, and a candle (or coffee).&lt;/strong&gt;
When I was going through an intense season of grief after losing our foster sons, not having to think about cooking was such a gift. People would bring us cupcakes, dinner, a latte…anything they thought could bring me a smile, and would sit on my couch and listen or do my dishes and not require a thing from me. Think of what brings you comfort on a rainy day (Gilmore Girls marathon?)…it will probably bring your friend some cheer, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Do be the pursuer and let them be messy.&lt;/strong&gt; 
I lost a lot of relationships in my season of grief. I felt like I had enough energy to love my husband and my kids, and there were friends that didn’t understand that I couldn’t be the pursuer anymore. I had to let those friendships go so I could focus inward. When I did that, an amazing thing happened. I started noticing and valuing the people who pursued so much more. The ones that didn’t make me put in more work in our friendship (not forever, just in that season), and who let me be messy, angry, sad…whatever I needed to be. The ones who bought my coffee, who held my baby, who said “I’m on my way to say hi” when I was trying to hide myself. They were the ones that didn’t let me crumble in isolation. Be the pursuer. Go sit with them. And don’t expect anything in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Do say something.&lt;/strong&gt; 
I have a certificate in assault victim counseling-in one of my trainings, I was told an unforgettable truth about trauma: after something significantly traumatic happens (like an assault) to a person, there is a window of ten minutes that will determine how they will view this event for the rest of their lives. Literally, the things I would say to my clients in the hospital could make or break them for the next twenty years of their lives. Will I speak hope? Will I discount their feelings? What would I say that could possibly make this positive? Well, first, I would never try to make something horrific positive. Bad things happen. Accept and recognize that. Recognize the event for what it is: This is a terrible thing…This is an evil thing….This is cruel… Then empathize: I am so sad with you….I am so sad that you’re sad…I wish I could make this better for you. Admit your inability to cure all: I don’t have the solution….I don’t know what to say…I wish I could…And offer hope: I’m with you in this. You’re not alone. I love you. I care for you. I wish I understood, too; but I’m here with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no perfect anecdote to being with someone that is grieving or in pain. I wish there were. People have tried to create ten step programs; but the truth is that, as many people there are in the world (according to the population clock, 7 BILLION)…that’s how many different ways there are to grieve. There is never going to be a cut and dry way to be with someone that’s hurting because people are beautiful and messy and complex and human. But you can be there with them in their grief, and accept their heart where it lays. This holiday, your silence may be the lifeline someone needs to get through their calm and silent night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 22, Sally became a foster mom to her three younger brothers. Affectionately titled a Mister (mom-sister), she uses her story to inspire others towards the hard and holy that life brings. When she’s not editing or writing on her blog, Letters From a Mister, you can find her dancing in the kitchen with her husband and tribe of seven-hugging a baby in one arm and a latte with the other.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sally Kim</name></author><category term="Christmas" /><category term="life" /><category term="relationships" /><summary type="html">On our drive home from school, my thirteen year old son was telling me about his Christmas choir concert, and how he really did not like one of the songs. It just feels like they’re trying to make a calm holiday all jumpy and excited.

He’s our sensitive one. He often hears things differently than they are intended, is easily discouraged and offended, and takes about nine hours to tell us any kind of story. I laughed it off and turned up Baby It’s Cold Outside, which was sandwiched between Frosty the Snowman and Holly Jolly Christmas.

But there’s something true about our boy’s observation. There is this tendency to skip the dark and jump straight to the lights, the coco, the loud and bright and happy…forgetting that the silent night was what started it all-the calm, bright, quiet evening that preludes all the celebrations begin.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/Screen%20Shot%202016-12-13%20at%209.22.38%20AM.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Building Creation Economies: What is Work?</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/09/building-creation-economies-what-is-work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building Creation Economies: What is Work?" /><published>2016-12-09T18:23:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-09T18:23:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/09/building-creation-economies-what-is-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/09/building-creation-economies-what-is-work/">&lt;p&gt;In the book of Genesis, we’re told a story about work. We’re introduced to a creator God as he’s performing his initial acts of work in our world. First, he created the original structure and foundation of everything–heavens and earth, light and darkness, and water, sky, and land. Then came vegetation, sun, moon, and stars in rotation, creatures of the sea, birds of the air, and beasts of the fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He called them good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he did something different. 
&lt;!-- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So God created humankind in his image, in the image of God he created them; male and female he created them. God blessed them, and said to them, ‘Be fruitful and increase in number; fill the earth and subdue it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he called it very good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the dust of the ground and the breath of God, Adama, the earth creature, the first human, was created. Adama was considered different than the rest of creation and was given dominion over it. More than that, Adama was given creation responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being created in God’s image, in his likeness, meant that he was to also be a creator. And his first creation task was naming the animals, giving them identity. Adama began participating with God in his creation of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But something changed. If you know the rest of creation story, Adam and Eve disobeyed in the first act of self-interest. And this is important to note, because this original sin–self centeredness–was the act then and continues to be that act today that demotes work from creation to toil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you ascribe to this narrative about the formation of our world or not, I think we can all agree that we have “creator” in our identity, and yet self interest prohibits this. The reason I believe this is so important is that I need to ground myself in God’s original intent for humanity and his identity for me if I am to understand the original structure and intent of the world and everything in it, including work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve been meditating on this, here’s the question I’ve been wrestling with: What is work, and how do we redeem it to its original intention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In common usage, work is a job, a means of earning an income. The dictionary definition says: “Work is an activity involving effort to achieve a purpose.” But I believe it’s more than that. &lt;strong&gt;I believe work is any act of creation or re-creation that makes the world what it was intended to be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original work was creation, and I believe that perspective can and should be redeemed. Our work is creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-centeredness makes work become toil, but we have the opportunity to restore its original characteristics: curiosity, joy, hope, and beauty. We have the opportunity to be creators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my next post, I’ll dive into what it means to be creators, but I’d love to dwell in these question first: What percentage of my day is toil instead of creation? In what ways do I perpetuate work as toil through self-centeredness?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we continue this conversation as a community, I’d love to know what questions were prompted for you and what challenges you’re facing. Tweet your thoughts + questions to @wayfarehq or email me at jeff@wayfare.io.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="creation" /><category term="work" /><category term="life" /><category term="economy" /><category term="toil" /><summary type="html">In the book of Genesis, we’re told a story about work. We’re introduced to a creator God as he’s performing his initial acts of work in our world. First, he created the original structure and foundation of everything–heavens and earth, light and darkness, and water, sky, and land. Then came vegetation, sun, moon, and stars in rotation, creatures of the sea, birds of the air, and beasts of the fields.

He called them good.

Then he did something different.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/t026fufwmhc-breather.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">3 Steps to Uncover what your Family’s Give Back Passion Is</title><link href="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/06/3-steps-to-uncover-what-your-familys-give-back-passion-is/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3 Steps to Uncover what your Family's Give Back Passion Is" /><published>2016-12-06T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-06T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/06/3-steps-to-uncover-what-your-familys-give-back-passion-is</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://wayfare.io/stories/2016/12/06/3-steps-to-uncover-what-your-familys-give-back-passion-is/">&lt;p&gt;The holidays typically bring about the sudden urge to get the family together and go out and do some good. While I love the passion everyone has, it can also be quite stressful trying to find what it is you want to do, and how to go do it. I see families get all into a tizzy about it which lead to me getting frantic emails around December 20th saying, “omg, I want to help people. Help me.” I tell ya, it’s quite the job I get to do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This season certainly is a great time to highlight how meaningful it is to give when we are inundated with the trappings of getting – getting yummy food, getting presents, getting peppermint mochas, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year if you want to break the cycle (or at least the sugar high) and are considering volunteering with the family, but don’t know where to start, I have a great little guide for you that breaks down what fits your family best. The more personal to the values of your family the better. I recommend getting kids involved and asking them what they think really matters. You’ll have to do the Googling once you uncover your passion, but this will get you where you need to be in terms of how and where you want to give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve gone out and volunteered, be sure to recap with the family. Ask them what they liked and didn’t like, if they want to do it again, and how they feel helping others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these three steps, uncover your family’s give back passion. Circle which option makes sense to you and then create your list of what to look for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.The first thing to decide on is who to help.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a personal preference and often will be based on the current demographics of your family, who you’re close to, or something that has impacted you directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Homeless&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Military&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elderly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Families&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Animals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Ill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.The second element of your giving will be based on where you want to help.&lt;/strong&gt; Are you excited about your local community, or do you have a heart for Malaysia? Decide where you want to make an impact, and tack that onto your list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your neighborhood&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your city&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your county&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your state&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your country&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.The final step in uncovering where your family give back passion is, is in thinking about how you want to help.&lt;/strong&gt; Some families are comfortable going down to a local shelter to feed the homeless, and some would rather craft at home and write letters to soldiers – there are options for everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hands on service&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At-home projects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Going outside&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being inside&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serving the person you are helping face to face&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woo hoo! You now know just how your family can make the biggest impact, for you. No matter what you do this year, we commend you. This season is one of the best to start in on a tradition of giving, of service, and of community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some bonuses for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to make tiny random acts of holiday kindness really fun, I have a Holiday Giving Advent Calendar that you can download and work on with the kiddos! Check it out on my site &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abelimpact.com/family/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want a cheat sheet of fun volunteer opportunities in Orange County, I have one &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abelimpact.com/blog/2016/11/29/holiday-volunteering-in-orange-county-2016&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Bailey Van Tassel </name></author><category term="Christmas" /><category term="gift" /><category term="giving back" /><category term="family" /><summary type="html">The holidays typically bring about the sudden urge to get the family together and go out and do some good. While I love the passion everyone has, it can also be quite stressful trying to find what it is you want to do, and how to go do it. I see families get all into a tizzy about it which lead to me getting frantic emails around December 20th saying, “omg, I want to help people. Help me.” I tell ya, it’s quite the job I get to do!

This season certainly is a great time to highlight how meaningful it is to give when we are inundated with the trappings of getting – getting yummy food, getting presents, getting peppermint mochas, etc.

This year if you want to break the cycle (or at least the sugar high) and are considering volunteering with the family, but don’t know where to start, I have a great little guide for you that breaks down what fits your family best. The more personal to the values of your family the better. I recommend getting kids involved and asking them what they think really matters. You’ll have to do the Googling once you uncover your passion, but this will get you where you need to be in terms of how and where you want to give.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://wayfare.io/uploads/eugck1ifvp0-kari-shea.jpg" /></entry></feed>
